Yeah. So we have been developing a web
wallet for KERI essentially just as
you know more wallets more platforms
better.
All right. So initially Sam set out
these goals where we wanted to create a
fully web native wallet because
currently the Locksmith application is a
desktop application.
And so let's see. Core wallet, we wanted
and so let's see. Core wallet, we wanted
it to run entirely in the browser
with no like server or anything running
KERIpy on the back end. Which,
Proved to be a challenge in fact.
Yeah. So again, we wanted everything to
happen in the browser so you can have
all of your keys locally created and
stored on your device. Don't have to
worry about them being stored on some
server. Then we could just send you
this application and you would get your
Your in browser wallet
and we also wanted it to be
persistent because that would be a
little bit useless if it wasn't.
So some challenges running Python in a
web assembly was the first big hurdle.
Because currently
because currently
yeah Python is run on CPython which is a
you know C written interpreter.
The cryptography had to work in the
browser and this basically meant that
KERI couldn't drag LMDB into the
webpath because LMDB relies on MAPAP
which is not supported in web
assembly.
And yeah, again, we want this to be
not a one tab, one reload type of
wallet. We want it to actually be like a
production grade wallet that we can
deploy where you can just take the
files, serve them yourself, even if you
wanted to, and be able to have your own
identifiers that you can manage from a
browser and not have to download an
application on specific
architectures. So getting Python into
the browser was a interesting
challenge. We found Piodide which is
essentially the Python interpreter
compiled to web assembly which allows it
to run into in the browser which
means that you can then run any Python
native packages
and for all the non-Python native
packages that was a medium challenge
And then we have PycScript as like
the browser bridge so you can launch off
web workers in the browser and it
interfaces with like the browser
database so you can have again that
persistent storage
which is exactly what I put on my
slides.
So to do this we had to again go through
the dependencies of KERIpy get them
to work in the browser which started
with pi sodium which is
a python wrapper for lib sodium which is
a C library. So I had to take lib sodium
compile it to target web assembly and
then I re I changed some of the code in
pi sodium so that it loaded the packaged
lib sodium that I created called it py
chloride because it's like you know
sodium chloride yeah that was Sam's idea
I'll give credit where credit blake 3
is written in rust I had to compile this
web assembly and also in the in an
attempt to get ready for future proofing
we took this PIQS which is an open
quantum secure safety yeah library for
key creation and
made it web assembly compatible. So that
will be coming in the future hopefully
before quantum computers.
All right. Yes. Yeah. So we had to so in
KERIpy itself we had to make it web
assembly safe which meant creating a
second database backing which used
index DB which runs in the browser. We
created webdber instead of lmdvrer
which means we're no longer relying on
the memory mapb.
And we also had to make it so that the
imports don't randomly import lmdb so
that it works in the browser. And again,
this webder allowed us to create like a
persistent storage in the browser that
can survive when you press reload on
accident and then you lose all your keys
because that would suck. Can
I ask you can I ask you a question?
Mhm.
On that.
Sure.
So is that
from a technical perspective? Is
there an abstract class for that or is
that not implemented with an
abstract?
Yeah, we created a base baser
Or wait that's for basers. No,
for the database we u made a second
class just for this one.
Okay. So it's like what is it that
called duct typing or something? It's
like just the same.
Yeah, we duct typed it all the same
functions just with index DB.
I mean maybe we can come back to this
but you ask a question but
go ahead.
I'm not familiar with K pi so I
understand none of the words on
Oh, okay.
Except for like just from like a
more of a web centric mentality like I
know like how is it storing data?
We're we're using Pycript's API
actually which is one of the reasons why
we chose to use it. They have a storage
API that exposes basically a couple
useful functions that we can then use to
store our data persistently.
What is web DB?
WebDer is the class is the ducttyped
class
for LMDBRE and KERIpy. CarPie is the
core KERI repository.
Okay. That implements
okay
the protocol.
We can talk more after.
Okay.
Yeah. This is like basically the
nitty-gritty of
this is some of the pi the KERIpy
internals
of the library itself. Web db is a
KERIpy
so is ho.
Ho is a separate library. It's an
asynchronous library that gets
used.
Yeah. And Sam had to extend HIO actually
for this to be possible because the
browser and JavaScript uses
asynchronous calls and HIO did not
before and so Sam had to add an
asynchronous interface into HIO we can
then use to persist our database.
So are all these all these changes now
today committed into
car pie?
It's on a branch but yeah
let's see. Yeah. So this is how it
works. We have the UI. It's just like a
very basic JavaScript shell which
launches our PIScript web workers that
then call into KERI pine heo which
allow us to run Python in the browser
and those call out to index DB which
stores it persistently.
Yeah let's see
keys are created in browser arrives.
No server side key management. Don't
worry guys here comes the demo.
Before you get the demo guys
Yeah. Shoot.
So, what' you guys do about keeper? How
are you encrypting keys?
Made a web keeper that interfaces
with
to do the encryption before putting it
in index DB.
Yeah, I think so.
I could look at the code. I can tell you
what I did. I don't know. I did a lot
of this like a couple months ago.
So if I if I wanted to make my own
database implementation, I would make a
duct type class for another data store.
Correct. Yeah. And then you'd have to
create like a baser for that class and a
keeper for that class.
Really?
Probably. Yeah.
Anyway,
here's the here's it running in the
web. So, I just copied Locksmith's UI
because that felt intuitive.
Again, this is just being hosted
locally. Eventually, I think we're going
to want to deploy like a the KERI
Foundation will want to deploy like a,
you know, basic rate limited version for
the features that require witness and
watcher access. So, I have some vaults.
See, I was testing some vaults out.
all right, let's create a vault. Open
the vault.
We can create local identifiers. I'll
make one for Evan. Oh, those are emojis.
I'll do an emoji.
Nice.
Awesome.
Easter egg.
Yep.
Solid alias. Yep.
And
my ly
and I was trying to get this working
last night. Those might work. I created
the plug-in page.
So let's see if it actually works.
It's spelled incorrectly. That's okay.
The KERI Foundation plugin. So in
Locksmith which Phil demoed yesterday
which they then donated to open source
the idea is that because it's open
source anyone who wants to provide
witness and watcher infrastructure can
create like a plugin
right
and then you can connect to these
different providers plugins and get oh
it worked nice yeah so it works
you can get witnesses in the browser
so that plugin is pointed to some
external infrastructure or
it's pointed to the witness and watcher
service that healthcare also so
graciously donated that is running
locally on my machine right now. So
again
the same thing I de demoed yesterday.
Yeah, he demoed this yesterday just
spinning up your own local
infrastructure.
Help or the KERI Foundation is going
to provide I think like a basic API
which will allow you to interface with
our plug-in and then you can grab our
deployed witnesses and watchers on our
service. That sound right?
Close enough.
Yeah.
Have a plug car foundation will have a
have a plug car foundation will have a
plugin. Other providers will have
plugins as well that they can provide.
Yeah. So we're going to host all of
our services or we have hosted our
services on Digital Ocean.
Yeah. I'm doing this all running locally
because it was faster for testing
essentially. Yeah, and so
it's working in the browser. The next
thing I have I have a lot to show guys.
I've also been working on trying to
get Locksmith
able to
have multiple plugins so that we can
show that, you know, in this open source
ecosystem, anyone can come in and
provide their own provide their own
witnesses and watchers as a service. So,
let's see.
Let me make sure this is working.
Okay,
here's locks. Here's the KERI
foundation.
This one's desktop.
This is desktop. This is the desktop
app.
So again, you can
so again, you can
be Evan.
I'll add my Evan identifier. That's not
my name.
With an emoji. No. What? No emojis here,
guys. I'm sorry.
What are we looking at?
Try again.
So, this is Locksmith, the open sourced
version.
Okay. On the
desktop.
On desktop. This is the desktop app.
So, we just doing this for comparison
with the web one.
Yeah, the web one is not as far along. I
have plugins working on the desktop
one to demonstrate that you can have
multiple providers giving you witnesses
and watchers. So, we have our KERI
foundation plugin.
so we create like our account
identifier. I think Ryan showed this
yesterday, but
it's basically just talking to
Oh, it worked. I'm not going to scan. It
works a lot faster when it's local.
Does work a lot faster when it's local.
And then I have a second plugin here.
Well, actually, that wasn't anything
impressive. So, I can add one of my
local identifiers in the KERI
Foundation plugin.
And then I can grab witnesses from the
KERI Foundation infrastructure which is
running locally.
And I have to provision and register
and I have to provision and register
them.
It's like kind of similar to
healthcare because they left some shared
components. So I used a lot of them.
And then I can grab this.
All right. Selected to rotate in the
witnesses.
Okay. So now my local identifier has one
witness from KERI Foundation
infrastructure ideally once it's
deployed. And then say you as an
individual or corporation want to also
provide witness infrastructure. You
would create a plugin for Locksmith.
I copied and pasted the folders so they
look very suspiciously similar.
Can I ask a question here?
Yep.
So this
creating a plugin.
Mhm.
Do I have control over the UI?
Yeah.
Yes.
And totally. And so if I want to have
some enterprise
whatever specific thing or any
service I want I can I can integrate
that as a plugin.
Totally. Yeah. And you probably want to
again because this is fully open source
to get it like contributed to the you
could either contribute it like upstream
to like the one in the KERI
Foundation repo or you could just clone
it and deploy it as your own
application.
Yeah.
yeah.
Okay. Yeah. Yeah. And so just as an
example, when we first did the plug-in
concept, we were thinking just SaaS
providers would put a plug in here so
that you'd get watchers and witnesses
from anyone. But then we found use case
for the cred enterprise credential
issuance platform that we're building.
The user interface is a plug into
Locksmith and it just made sense because
if you're building any kind of user
interface that could use KERI, it's a
great place to put it.
As
long as you're like writing Python and
pass six. Yeah. Oh, yeah.
Or like a cloth.
Yeah. As long as you can. I don't like
it.
All right. So, I'm creating my test
infrastructure account. I'm not going to
scan this one. And then I can go to my
identifiers. I can grab the same local
Eban identifier. You can see and it has
the witnesses. It doesn't have all the
the fancy schmancy tooling that
Healthcare showed quite yet.
So now I have four witness servers
running for this one. So I can add four
witnesses here.
Okay. And then I can rotate in these
witnesses. I can also roach it out
the other witness, but I'm not going to
do that.
My authenticator is two seconds left.
my authenticator is two seconds left.
I'm using Google authenticator on my
phone, so no one password copying like
Phil was showing yesterday for me.
You're right. I missed a digit.
Yeah, but now they've expired. I'm just
kidding.
All right, there you go. They're in. So
now I have again it took it sequence
number is two because I rotated in two
sets of witnesses from two different
providers and there are five total
witnesses witnessing my local
identifier. So, it works.
Sweet. And then,
yeah, I've been trying to make it easy
for anybody who wants to create a plugin
to create their own plugin. I was
thinking u I've had many different
approaches as to how I best thought
this possible. So, my newest approach
was to create just like a templating
folder basically that would kind of
just give you like a one UI page that
you could use as a template so that it
would Claude could actually be smart
when he does it. Yeah.
So Sam introduced the concept of
what was it called? Observer registar. I
still need to figure out what all
that is. But so similarly here the
plugin you could I suppose manage
those kinds of things as well
eventually. Yeah I think the observer
and the registar stuff.
Are they just extensions of witnesses
are they just extensions of witnesses
and watchers? I guess I don't know
they monitor a different thing.
Yeah those monitor your
credentials. So, but if I wanted to make
a plugin for that, I could mention
probably.
Yeah, I don't we haven't gone down that
road yet. So,
wait, sorry, what was the question?
If the plugin could be used for
helping implement the registars and
observers.
Yeah, absolutely. I mean, it would it
would just be the user interface into
those. So if you stand up a SaaS platform
that has APIs to allow you to stand up
registars and observers that absolutely
you could add it to your interface here
in your plugin to reserve those for
you
which is similar to the witness and
watch you have to services out there.
It's just UI to connect manage
the relationship.
That's exactly right.
Yep. Sweet.
Okay that was most of the things I
okay that was most of the things I
wanted to show. I mean this is cool
because it shows the how we are car
Foundation. We're open source accepting
multiple providers and it's possible.
Yeah.
So then what's the status of the
mobile because we did web and desktop
the mobile is Jay do you want to take
this one?
I'm sorry.
You want to take what's the status of
the mobile? Jayzar been working on
mobile
be deployed sometime in the near future
as soon as it gets the account info
from Sam for the iOS and Android stores.
It's the same code though that runs the
web wallet. It's the same code.
It's it's the same code.
So it's just being deployed.
It the iOS and Android code are just in
wrappers that run almost like a pseudo
browser and we just deploy pretty much
the same code onto it.
So it's the web essentially version.
Yeah. And yeah, it's it's pretty much
just it's just the web app.
So it's doing all the same stuff you
said the Wom and all the WebDers
mobile.
Yes. Yeah.
Is there a mailbox as part of this?
No, not yet.
Probably.
So
So on e either the phone, you know, or
or a browser page, right? Let's let's
let's say I'm an issuer. Mhm.
issue. You have a credential offer or
grant
And your phone is off or your browser
is not on at the moment.
Will that will there be a mailbox in
between to pick it up?
That I mean I would assume it would go
to your witnesses or something.
Yeah. So that's a common misconception.
So when we originally deployed
witnesses, we did make mailboxes a part
of the witness deployment simply because
we were moving very fast and had nowhere
else to hang them. Okay,
we didn't want to create a whole new
service at the time. So, we have since
moved away from that. Healthcare does
provide mailboxes as a bespoke thing you
can reserve and I was going to demo that
yesterday but ran out of time and then
and then you just launch a Locksmith
turn it on say activate this mailbox and
now you can get messages on it and if
you miss any messages they're stored
forward so they sit here.
Are those on your platform like you're
storing?
Those are platform. So then
it's a very simple small service. It's
it's basically if you were to look at
the code inside of KY you just pull out
the mailbox stuff. Yeah, because there
is mailbox up in the right
that could be hosted anywhere.
Absolutely. It's just like any other
resource, right?
Yep. Yeah.
Yeah. Yeah. Again, we got this code
recently from healthcare. So,
awesome work. And
we're we're there's there's a long
list of features we're we're aiming to
add. So,
just hit the ones that were priorities
for the conference first. And awesome.
I mean, again, you can you can always go
into the open source repos, create
issues for features you want to see, and
We can address those as they come in
as well.
Sweet.
Or fork and build.
Yeah,
absolutely.
So did I understand you correctly
that you had you said five witnesses
were monitoring? Well, five witnesses
were associated with your identifier.
Okay. That's the same amount of
witnesses that GLE maintains in the
infrastructure and the same that we
require from QDIs to contribute to with
only a small overlap for shared
resources in effect. Should we be
also perhaps providing guidance to
wallet holders? Credential holders
Guidance
guidance
or guidance as to how many witnesses
they should be.
True. Yeah. Well, yeah. If there's
particular requirements for it, then
yeah, absolutely.
Yeah. Sam's recommendation was
was five.
It was either one or four
with a Yeah. cuz he says three when you
have three or four as your th signing
threshold for witnesses you can't be
eclipsed and then if you have one well
it's less secure because your one could
be
compromised
but yeah
okay
yeah I think a mission of the KERI
Foundation is going to also be to
provide
documentation with recommendations and I
would guess it will grow to span
ecosystems so like if you're if you
need if you're going to become a QBI
here's what you will need to consider
here are the recommend recommendations
you're going to have to follow if you're
going to be doing this in healthcare.
Here's other things. I suspect that
KERI Foundation will be a central
location for that stuff.
Well, I've already got those kinds of
requirements in the ecosystem governance
framework for QBIs. Yes.
Because obviously we issue credentials
to the QBIS.
But I could put in the credential
frameworks for the legal entity one, the
ECRS and the OS. A recommendation of
how many witnesses should be
associated with.
Yeah, absolutely.
That would be the right place to put.
Okay.
All right. Thank you.
Anybody have other questions, things you
want to say, comments, concerns? Yeah.
I just have a general question. I'm
not very familiar with KERIpy and I'm
I'm doing my own like very lightweight
kind of educational JavaScript
implementation and as soon as you as
soon as you try something like that you
notice how extensive the spec is. So
it's like on step five
but so you're doing this in the web
but you're not reimplementing with
JavaScript you're wrapping KERIpy. So
you basically get all the like how
much of the spec does KERIpy
implement
like pretty much all of it or
it so KERIpy as it stands right now in
there's three branches 1.2x and 1.3x
those implement full KERI of KERI and
ACDC of 1.0
and KERI has since evolved
significantly into 2.0. What these guys
are well so one of their missions
besides just put out these tools is to
take KERIpy and completely upgrade it
to 2.0. That is still work in progress
and it is the current main branch on
KERIpy represents that work.
Okay. So it will of course eventually
implement certainly the entire KERI
spec and I would guess the first
milestone is as much of the ACD specs
ACDC spec as is needed to satisfy SEDI.
So I'm suspecting that's probably Sam's
big goal for getting KERIpy to where
it needs to be.
But it seems like with this strategy
whatever the feature completeness is of
KERIpy you kind of get that for free.
You get that from this
except
is there is there a distinct UI in the
browser like do you have like could you
have a situation where the desktop is
ahead of the browser because the browser
hasn't written the HTML templates to
Yes. Okay.
Yep. Yep. Those are so those are Yeah.
Those are separate UI implementations.
Yeah. that could come slightly opposite
and I would suspect they'll eventually
grow to be somewhat separate simply
because of the paradigm of running
something in the web and mobile versus a
desktop app.
Yeah.
Just like if you look at one password
looks similar but there's quite a bit of
difference functionality between their
plugin and the desktop app.
Yeah.
So the Locksmith desktop app is that
also Python everything?
Yes. And what's the
pi side?
Pi side six.
Yeah, it's pretty good to work
with.
Yeah,
and that's that works cross platform.
So, Mac and everything.
Yeah.
Windows.