All right. Today, so the title
of the talk is fire and CMS. And
we'll talk a lot about that. I actually
want to spend a little bit of time today
going over what the vital framework is.
It's actually the vital initiative. I
need to change the slide on this.
This is an old one and as you can
see, it's glitching out. But I want
to talk through this, what it means, why
it's important what the acronym of
verifiable identity and trust automation
layer is. So here's just quick
intro. We're going to go through CMS
and their standards process
interoperability standards in
healthcare kind of at large, how we got
to what fire is now today. What is
fire? And we'll go very high level
on this. You we're not going to go into
kind of the different IGs within fire.
We're not going to talk about, you know,
Fast necessarily. Just this is
fire 101 for the KERI ecosystem as
they want to come up to speed on the
applicability of the KERI ecosystem for
different industries. Then we'll talk
about CMS 0057 and then we'll talk about
The vital initiative. So just as a as
a high level Jared Jeffrey CEO founder
at healthcare is a startup
that is in the industry of the
missing trust layer for healthcare. So
we have adopted some open source open
standard protocols. If you're at the
KERI conference, you can probably guess
as to what those are. But for us, it
is imperative that VC this
trust layer be implemented into the
healthcare ecosystem. As a little bit of
background on myself I am a me a
member of or a fellow of the American
College of Health Data Management. I'm
former class research. Class is
probably the biggest name in healthc
care's market IT research and convening.
So they've spent years and years
and years getting all of the right
groups into the room where typically
those groups are very contentious.
They'll put those people down in a room
say take your hats off. Let's
actually solve problems. And so they've
done a lot of work like getting pairs
and providers to come together and talk
about solutions which is the fact
that they did that and it never came to
blows was I think actually a miracle.
And then previously, you know, my
and then previously, you know, my
educational credentials come both
from UVU. So happy to be back at
the alma mater today. And then
WGU, which is Western Governor's. Okay.
Want to talk about just really
quickly why it is we're doing this in
healthcare. So my background is one
15 years in healthcare it. Yes. But
I'm also a brain cancer survivor and
patient myself. So at one point I was
being treated by the single machine in
the entire Rocky Mountain West that
could provide me the care I needed to
survive to thrive. Without that
machine I wouldn't be here today. The
reality is that for many millions
of patients that is a very similar thing
but often for them it is not some
bespoke proton therapy machine that
is hard to build. oftentimes it is
something as simple as access to an
ER doctor at the time they need an ER
doctor. And so one of the things that
has started to happen increasingly is
that as these ransomware attacks which
are targeting healthcare, we'll talk a
little bit about that in a minute.
The targeting of this industry has
the targeting of this industry has
real world implications. So the why for
us, why we're here, why we're doing this
is because as we increasingly move
care into a digital context, we
increasingly make the risk to patients
explode. And why is that? Well, if you
shut down a hospital using a ransomware
attack, the first response that
hospital has to do from a care
perspective is send every ambulance
that's supposed to come to them
someplace else. And this the especially
in the US that ecosystem is incredibly
fragile. And so if you're talking about
for example an urban center, they may
have to push hospitals out to hospitals
in rural centers and those hospitals may
not have the same equipment, they may
not have the same training, they may not
have a level one trauma center. So if
you shut down a large health system, you
are actively threatening the lives of
patients. In fact, NPR about two years
ago put out a report that stated that a
ransomware attack on healthcare should
be considered as disastrous as a
national or a natural disaster. So a
tornado or hurricane, they are the same
level of disruption. The difference
of course is while we can blame God for
tornadoes and hurricanes we blame
Russia and North KERI for the
ransomware attacks that are happening in
the industry. So a little bit of data
on this. Healthcare is the most
targeted industry by a large margin
when you look at some of these other
pieces. There's a few reasons for
this. They're also the most
expensive. So, this is part of what's
driving that. You'll get the biggest
payout if you're holding a knife to the
throat of an organization that has to
pay you or people will die. And so,
attackers know this. This is a
persistent data source. This isn't just
one year. This has been for the last
decade. Healthcare has been the most
targeted industry. So one of the
questions we get all the time is why
attack patient data? What's what's the
value proposition for an attacker to
come into this ecosystem and to
compromise all of this data? The reality
is there's a few different things. The
first is that on the on the black
market, a patient record is typically
10x or more the value of let's say a
credit card, which makes perfect sense,
right? You your credit card gets
compromised. What's the first thing you
do? You call up Capital One or Chase and
you say, "Hey, I lost my card." And
within a week, they've got a new card
for you, right? They've rotated you to a
new credit card number. And you're back
up and running. When you lose your
medical record, you're losing your
social security number, you're losing
your date of birth, you're losing your
name, you're losing typically one or
two payment methods, and you're also
losing all of your medical information
itself. None of that can be rotated. As
much as I'd love to call Capital One and
say, "Hey, you know, I've got brain
cancer. That's great. Can we rotate this
to like diabetes?" I'd prefer that
it just doesn't work that way. You have
immutable data in a health record, which
means that the value of that data lasts
for as long as the data is valid,
which is forever. So with that data,
there are a number of different things
that they can do. So one is just selling
the records online but beyond that it's
things like standing up fake clinics
to execute fraud to CMS and it is
I can prove to CMS that I'm treating you
and I can do that at a scale of you
know hundreds or thousands of clinics.
There was actually a clinic, this was
two years ago, I say clinic there
was a group in Florida that was found to
have absolutely no patients, but they
had a whole lot of data and they were
billing CMS pretty
aggressively to get money out of that
system. Other things to note here
is and this one I actually want to hit
Pretty heavily which is extortion
attacks. So, it used to be that the
primary attack surface that an attacker
was looking for, the monetization
that they wanted was if I hit a
hospital, they'll pay me $7 million to
unlock my data. And that's still true.
But these days, the attacker actually
also couples that with exfiltration of
that data. And because AI has made the
Cost per extortion so low, they'll
now go after individual patients as
well. So they'll go after a recent
article I read was that a bunch of
mimography images were captured and
they were actually going to individual
women and saying, "Hey, we have
compromising images of you from this
this data that we pulled out of your
health system. You're going to pay us
$2,000 or we're going to put these out
on the dark web." And so it used to be
that $2,000 wasn't enough to get anybody
interested. These days, because it is so
simple and easy to make that attack, and
by the way, I already have all your
contact information. We can just set
up a script and the AI can extort for us
Which is obviously not terrible but
when we ask about okay why is healthcare
so compromised it's because it's
insecure it's high value and the
data doesn't change across time which
makes it a really good find and
can be resold multiple times in the
future. So
the other problem here is not only is
healthc care's data incredibly valuable
it is also incredibly complex. So you
have health systems, you have health
payers. These are typically the two big
players in the space. Each of these
ecosystems will on average have about
1,500 connections. So the average health
system has got vendors that are
connecting into their system doing a
number of different tasks for them. Each
one of these connections represents
an attack surface for the attackers. I
showed on that previous slide about 3/4s
of actually originate in an external
party. So I think a good example of
helps people understand
is probably five six years ago now.
All of the credit card information in
all of the credit card information in
Target got stolen. The way that they got
in was through the HVAC vendor. So the
HVAC vendor had a connection into
Target. Obviously HVAC, he doesn't
feel like he's got to be all that
secure, but simply by virtue of
connectivity, they were able to do a
privilege escalation attack, which is
basically you compromise the first set
of credentials. You move from those
credentials laterally to somebody else
that has better access into the system
and then you can move up. Eventually,
you're looking for a CIS admin role.
Once you have a CIS admin role, you have
keys of the kingdom. You execute your
ransomware. You know, within a month,
the cyber insurance will have paid
out the $7 million because the
hospital's got to get back up and
running. So that's the attack in
a nutshell and this is the risk. So
again thousands of connections coming
into the system each one of them
representing a potential attack surface
for bad actors to enter in. So we used
to think and I think some people still
do that if we've encrypted the
channel then we have a secure connection
and the reality is that the attacker
will most often use that channel
against you hunting for what we call
shared secrets. This is a shared
credential. This is username and
password. This is a bearer token.
There's a number of different things
that qualify as a shared secret. Our
contention is that we probably should
stop letting them steal these shared
secrets. impersonating your third party,
moving through the channel that you
trusted to be secure, and then
exfiltrating your data. It's time for us
to actually reduce the attack surface by
taking this piece here and removing the
shared secrets that come into the system
so that those attacks are no longer
valid no longer reasonable for an
attacker to execute. Now, we've talked
about earlier today a lot of the value
in terms of the connectivity problem
with regards to onboarding with regards
to the manual lift on it. One of the
other things that KERI does for us is
this. It allows us to create a ecosystem
of true zero trust where there is no
Oh, that's cool. Where there is no
compromising credential for
participants to be attacked on.
In fact, we've actually shown this. We
in fact, we've actually shown this. We
had a pentest done on a system that
was basically running this. We stood
the system up. We were running hundreds
of thousands of fire transaction
transactions. We'll talk about that in a
second. Through the system, we
brought in some white hat hackers. We
pointed them to the system and we said,
"Go ahead and break it. Here's
everything that you would need if it was
a traditional system." They came
back and said, "We can't get into the
system. There's no serious flaws that we
see." It was humorous to me though
that they did say, "Hey, there's no
TLS on this connection. So you guys are
missing that. Maybe you should put it in
there." And the reality is we believe
that KERI-based connectivity is
actually a replacement for TLS. Okay. So
that's kind of the background on
healthcare and why I think the vital
initiative and what we're going to talk
about today is important. Now let's get
into what CMS is, what they actually do,
why they matter. So very high level CMS
is the Centers for Medicare and
Medicaid. Remember Medicare is for
the elderly, Medicaid is for low-income
individuals. So we care about our
elderly, we provide AID to the poor.
That's the way I always remember it. And
then you can keep those two straight.
It's important to note that while not
it's important to note that while not
all care happens through CMS, they're
managing what was it like a trillion
dollars? 1.2.
Okay. Yeah. one 1.8. So round up, you've
got a couple trillion dollars flowing
through the system every year, which
means across years it's trillions and
trillions of dollars. So even if you are
not a Medicare or Medicaid plan, even
if you're not accepting Medicare or
Medicaid dollars this is the 800 lb
gorilla in the room. So when they speak,
typically everybody listens. Yeah. Mark
amendment. Medicaid is not run by CMS,
right? It's it's stun.
The states they were the reason they
have the
some level of control is that they'll
pay 90 a 9010 split for investments into
Medicaid.
Yeah. Yeah. Okay. Yeah, that's good.
That's good clarity. But at the end
of the day, the reality is that if you
are looking to get money out of the
healthKERI system it would be wise
of you to listen to and abide by the
regulations that CMS puts out. Now
CMS themselves typically do not
originate standards. what they like to
do and what they've done numerous
times in the past is that they will work
with an industry group like HL7 who
who stands up the fire standard and they
will basically say these are the things
that we are looking for there's deep
collaboration there fire will say okay
let's get the industry together we'll
stand up a standard like fast which
is what Mark was talking about
earlier today once they have a an
acceptable standard CMS will come
back and basically bless that standard
put it into regulation and say this is
how we want to see things done. So, for
example, we talked about pretty
extensively earlier today CMS 0057.
It is a regulation. It's a requirement
it is a regulation. It's a requirement
for payers. They will not get or will be
penalized by CMS starting January 1,
2027. And that penalty is based on
whether or not they have a fire API
endpoint. So again, you start to see
this converging of the federal
regulators working with industry groups
to establish these standards, then
enacting them into mandate. And then
often, but not always though I
would argue the most effective ones
are when they tie those to payments. So
if they say, "Hey, you're going to get
penalties. You're going to get fines.
We're going to cut off your Medicare
Medicaid funding." That's when you
actually see the industry move. And
then yeah, they'll they'll they'll come
in and they'll basically say by X date
you want to see you know why happen
within the industry. So let's talk
about kind of the history of these
standards, how we got to where we are
today. I think there's some
instructive pieces here. It's important
to note that we started with what I
would call foundational interoperability
standards and as we've moved across time
we've moved up to I think much more
useful standards which would be
network interoperability standards. Now
I want to give a couple of
definitions here. So a foundational
standard is basically just what's the
pipe look like? If you stand up the pipe
good you've met the foundational
standard. And there we'll talk about
some examples here in a second.
structural is really just I have the
the PET pipe. I know that the data is
coming through and the reality is that
this is a you know for a diabetic let's
say it's a glucco glucose test. That's
more useful than just hey data is coming
in and out as you move up the ladder
to like semantic data. This is where you
start to get structure and coding into
it which basically lets you say things
like hey this is a glucose test it needs
to go into the doctor's decision support
tool. Right? So as you build the
standard on interoperability, you get
more and more value out of the data
that's flowing in and out of the system.
The network standard and this one is
So these are I would say adopted
nomenclature. I've been adding this. So
this is new to healthcare. My argument
is that we need to get to network
standards where it is not just
structured coded and scaled which is
important for these other things. It
needs to be governed and that governance
piece is the piece that healthcare is
still I think currently grappling with.
So let's talk about a few of the
ways that this lays out in terms of
manual effort. So if you have a
foundational interoperability model
literally it's just the pipe. Everything
else is on you. Congratulations. You
have data have fun you know
normalizing all of that. Maybe you'll
pass it into Mirthth or Iguana or
somebody else and they can do the job
for you. This goes all the way up to the
question we should be asking which is
when data is flowing through the system
is the standard built in such a way that
we can answer the question affirmatively
will this improve patient care and
that's what we're trying to get to
with interoperability standards. So
let's talk about what some of these
standards are. So back in the 80s
which I was not around for ADTS
came out ADTS is admissions discharges
and transfers basically this was the
building block of healthcare's
interoperability. Can I see from a
hospital perspective is the patient in
my hospital is he out of the hospital or
has she been transferred to another
hospital? And that was the foundational
effort that came again back in the 80s.
We moved on to between 87 to 95 there
was CCDAS that were added in and the
one that I actually want to talk about
is HL7B2. HL7B2 is the precursor to
fire. So this is probably and correct me
if I'm wrong here Mark the most
adopted standard in healthcare today.
Most data flows on HL7B2
most
yeah so it's HL7B2
question mark
it's standard. Yeah, standard adjacent.
And so that was back in 95 that this
came out. You can see that
healthcare is Yeah, go ahead.
What's the differentiation there? What's
what's the customization? Is it the data
model that's consistent? Is it just
what's what's the proprietary
niches?
It's it's extensions.
It's it's wide open extensions. They
call them Z segments. They just let you
let you put whatever you want in there
and define them for your local use. So
it's a local extension and they're
allowed and they're you know a lot of
them are used in fact even later
versions of HS72 that actually support
those capabilities later people
didn't change their Z segments because
they were working and they were mostly
were communicating inside the enterprise
so communicating from the system that
manages the
encounters with the systems that are
clear so from the system the lab system
back. So that's that's why they could be
that's why they could be not standard
because they were for use in a in a
price.
Yeah.
And the other thing is the V2 and C CCDA
standards
were effectively proprietary. So in
those days you have to pay to get access
to those just like you do today with
X12. So if you want to do a financial
transaction in healthcare it has to go
RX12 because over it cost you like 1,500
bucks a year just to be able to see that
and extra homes in that in that era.
Yeah. Right here.
Yeah.
Yeah. It's all it's all in here. And
obviously not comprehensive. We're just
trying to do a high level here. So
then back in 2011, you'll be happy
to note I was here for this one. I was
here for this one. The fire
standard was put out in 2011. Since
then there's been a lot of work in the
fire space I think at this point. So
when I got into healthcare we were
just talking about interoperability
standards and there was a lot of
discussion around is fire the go forward
are we going to do this? Are we not?
Because a lot of people were happy with
because a lot of people were happy with
HL7B2 in the sense that they're lazy and
Didn't see the need to change and
we're still faxing things anyway. So why
do we care about a data standard? I
would say that in the last 5 to 10
years that has really flipped and the
industry has started to say yes fire is
the go forward standard. So even if
people aren't using fire today for all
of their connections everybody has
kind of accepted the fact that at some
point fire is going to be coming into
their world and again we'll talk more
about what fire is in a second. So I
want to go up one level and talk about
kind of the network level of
interoperability standards. So for
things like TEFA, which is the trusted
exchange framework and common agreement,
This is a federally backed program to
do nationwide interoperability.
They are actually using fire in TEFLA.
they are actually using fire in TEFLA.
So this isn't a morphing of this
standard here. Well, sorry, they talk a
big game about using fire. They
anticipate that in the future they will
use it
is still Yeah. CCDA or HL7B2. But
but they have acknowledged that this is
the direction they're going to go.
So this isn't a new standard as much
so this isn't a new standard as much
as it is a new set of guidelines.
So that common agreement is the
governance framework that they're trying
to instantiate on top of existing
frameworks. So the other one that I
would mention here just kind of in
passing is CMS aligned networks.
That's one that will become I think more
that's one that will become I think more
relevant as we
and fire in the ecosystemality
here and the reasons
here the first being we don't actually
have full adoption of fire up here yet
and beyond that these ecosystems up
here do not have I would argue an
effective mechanism for governance and
trust on the frameworks. So and I'
I think I've got a couple things. We
we'll come to it later on why I say
that. But let's switch just very
quickly to talk about fire. So fire
is fast interoperability fast
healthcare interoperability resources.
It's a lot of things. So, it's an
acronym, but it's also the data
structure. It's restful APIs, which is
just modern API connectivity. It's a
set of tool sets. So, so it's a de
developers kits. it's, you know,
validation implementation guides.
HL7 actually does maintain public fire
test servers. So, if people are looking
to get into Fire, they've made it really
easy because you can go in and play
within their ecosystem. And then
there also is a community that's that's
I would say relatively strong and
vibrant, growing every day in terms of
People in the ecosystem doing Fire.
like I don't think I've talked to
another healthcare startup that isn't
starting with fire in terms of the
connectivity that they're trying to
drive into the ecosystem. The other
thing that I think I should point out
here is that the data structure piece is
actually incredibly valuable. So, a CCDA
HL7V2, they didn't really allow for
discrete elements of the data to be
called out, which meant that oftent
times when you're transacting a data
record, what you're getting is a
stack of information and then you'd have
to go through and kind of parse through
that to get to value. Yeah.
Yeah. How does that relate with various
EHR type?
So, what do you mean? What do you mean?
I think electronic health or portable
health records. I'm not sure if
Yeah. So, so with EHRs it's
going to depend on EHR. Obviously,
most of them are transacting data on
HL7B2,
but does this does this say you have to
use a particular type or aren't there
multiple EHRs?
There's lots of out there. Yeah, the ONC
basically has really got the role of
regulating the
healthcare tech industry. ONC being the
office of the national coordinator for
healthc
and so they a number of years ago
defined
fire
set of resources known as US core
And basically had certifications
so that if you were a certified health
information technology platform you
would have to certify against that and
that required you basically to have a
population health API based on fire
patient access API based on fire and
using those calls that was on an
older version of fire and what's
happened over the last year is
they updated to the same version the
players are actually
yeah so it is a standard that
lives underneath the EHR itself right
because they're they're trying to get
data in and out so back to this
the data structure the model here, these
data descriptions, and it's completely
gone now, which is great. Is
actually really important in terms of an
upgrade here. So, one of the things that
Fire allows you to do that
previous interoperability standards
didn't, is to be able to call out
discrete data elements from the fire
record. So, when you're talking about a
multiundpage patient record, which I'm
sure mine is with all the things I've
gone through the ability to go in
and say, I just want these blood tests,
I just want this, you know, from this
date to that date. to be able to parse a
record at scale like that. That's
incredibly valuable. And I think, you
know, all the rest of these things are
essential. They're helpful, but really
it's that data structure and the ability
to make the data actually useful in
clinical practice is what's driven fire
API as well because traditionally what
would happen is if you wanted data, you
would make a request say basically send
me a document.
Yeah.
Right. So, they're going to put that
data into the document. I've been in
meetings where been discussions of how
much data should we put in a document if
we're going to have a standard which is
a little bizarre
right
whereas with the restful API and those
data structures you can if you've got
the permissions you can go in and say
give me just the A1C readings out of the
observation resource
yeah just give me the discrete
elements from the data that I actually
want so this is the objectives of
fire that's that's stated by HL7 who's
standards body that forwards fire.
They wanted to be built for
implementers. So this isn't something
that was thought up by you know
people like me who would definitely get
it wrong but actually by impleers that
know what needs to go into a standard.
They regularly do connectathons
because it doesn't do any good to
have an implement standard if you
can't teach people how to get this done.
I think that this is another piece
that's very valuable is that they
operate on an 8020 rule. So they're
going to anticipate that they can get
about 80% of all the use cases enacted
into the standard. But that XKCD
Comic I had up earlier is very
true which is if your standard isn't
rigid you end up proliferating standard
or it is rigid not flexible you end up
proliferating standards. The other
things that are I think important is
it's open source. And the
adoption as far as everything that fire
tries to do is to make it incredibly
easy. So that's kind of the fire
in a nutshell. Let's talk about CMS
0057. So this is the latest version of
that synergistic loop that I talked
about earlier, which is CMS doesn't want
to set standards. They want the industry
to set those standards through somebody
like HL7 and then they come together and
start to put them into mandates. CMS
0057 basically says that by January 1,
2027, every payer that receives Medicare
and Medicaid dollars has to stand up an
API for these four use cases, which is
Pay-to-payer exchange patient
access pair to provider exchange,
and then a streamlined pri prior
authorization process. Is anybody not
familiar with what prior authorization
is? We've we've thrown that around
pretty loosely, but if you don't know,
okay, great. I will say that when I
went to go get the proton therapy, it
took 3 months to get the prior
authorization approved on that. So
if we can streamline that, I would be
very, very pleased. So,
let's talk about how the connections
work right now. Mark mentioned a couple
of these things earlier, but it's
typically in terms of trust on the
connection, it's certificates, it's
tokens, it's very manual. And often
the org identity is assumed not
proven. So they have some evidence of
who you are, but it's not cryptographic
evidence. It's not something that would
necessarily hold up in court. And so
with this idea that healthcare is the
most targeted and that most of those
attacks are coming through third
parties this is a disaster waiting
to happen. So CMS has come in and said
you need to stand up these four types of
APIs. In reality, what that means is
you're going to have thousands, if not
hundreds of thousands of new connections
coming into the ecosystem. And given
that we are already the most targeted,
we're just going to make it worse for
ourselves because again three-4s of
all the attacks are already coming
through an outside connection that
you have. So let's talk about
what fire has done and then we can talk
about what we think still needs to be
done. So semantic data again super
important that you're all speaking the
same language on your data transactions.
Real time versus asynchronous.
You want something that's lighter. I
you want something that's lighter. I
think they've done a great job with
that. The developer access and the
discrete element parsing. This is again,
I think the biggest one that Fire has
solved. You may disagree with me,
Mark. There might be things more
important, but I think that's pretty
foundational to the value that Fire
drives. So really fire fixes today
the how. They do a really good job of
how are we going to get data moving back
and forth. Sorry, that's a meta
alarm. But what it doesn't solve is the
who. So right now in the industry,
Mitch, what was the last count on Epic
lawsuits? Are we up to 15 yet?
It's climbing.
Yeah. Okay. So, we're we're somewhere
between 13 and 15 lawsuits. And that is
both Epic suing people and Epic being
sued by people.
Epic's the largest EHR.
Yeah. They're the behemoth in the
industry. So essentially what
happened, and I'll walk you through
this because I actually think it's
really interesting, is a small startup
called Particle Health sued Epic and
basically said, "You're blocking
information. We have a right to clinical
information through Epic's EMR. We want
to be able to treat patients and you're
not giving us that info." And so they
kicked off this lawsuit that kind of
rocked the industry. The response to
this was, yes, obviously Epic's taking
this with their lawyers in court and
they're having discreet arguments there.
But in the court of public opinion, Epic
decided to go out and sue one of the
on-ramps to the networks. So, Particle
said, "Hey, you have to give us the
data." And in the court of public
opinion, Epic said, "We can't give you
the data. The networks aren't
trustworthy." And so they went and sued
Health Gorilla, which is one of these
on-ramps into TEFLA, that national
exchange framework, and basically
alleged that they were letting bad
actors onto the network without proper
vetting. And so Epic now can kind of
hold their virtue in the court of
public opinion by saying, "No, no, no.
We're not info blocking. We're doing
what's right by patients because if we
were to put patients data out on these
networks, it would be compromised
because the networks can't be trusted."
And then of course because lawyers
get excited, there has been a number of
other lawsuits that have all started to
spawn out of this same thing. So you've
got class action lawsuits that are go
now going after Epic because this is a
big a big issue. States are suing
Epic around this same thing. And at
the core of all of these latigious
contentions is well can we trust the
other side of the ecosystem? And so
coming all the way back to the lawsuit
that kicked this off, if we could
trust the network, then we could
actually hold Epic to account and say,
"Yeah, you're info blocking. You're just
not sharing the data because you don't
want to because data is the new oil and
because you see a lot of value in owning
all of the patient records." But
without that trust, we have to get into
this incredible and increasing web of
litigation trying to solve that problem
at scale. So, I said this earlier today,
I'll say it again. The question used to
be, can we connect? The answer is yes.
Now, the question is, can we trust those
connections? So this is a slide I
also stole from Mark. I did I did
beautify it a bit. So but if we are
going to get to a place where we can say
yes to the question of trust and
connections we really need a couple of
things. We need first to have a
organizational binding to the
individuals in that organization be they
people or entities. You have to be
able to delegate and prove delegated
access and authority to those
individuals. And then you have to be
able to particularly in healthcare scope
down their access to just the minimum
needed the purpose of use for that
particular connection. If you can do all
of those things, you can bind them
together cryptographically then you can
get to yes we can trust the connections.
Now how do we get to that trusted
onboarding the connections
themselves? It's these pillars down
here. You need something that's
verifiable, auditable, automated, secure
and open. And if you think of a you know
there may be an open source open
standard protocol that was invented
by someone in this room may actually fit
the bill for this. In fact this
may be me right now. If you understand
KERI I think you know where this
starts to go. We want to build and we
talked about this earlier today. A
trust equity framework or connectedness
at trust. This is a diagram I
entirely came up with myself. Phil gave
no commentary on this at all. He didn't
No, I'm just kidding. This is Phil's
diagram for really how VC KERI and
in particular the vLEI participating in
an ecosystem where we can start to
answer that question of can we trust the
connection. So it starts with the
trust anchors. Yeah, go ahead. Okay,
I'll go super quick. It starts with
the trust anchors which for the BLI is
GLEIF. VC direct trust playing a
huge role in this in terms of
translation of global standards into
value for individual ecosystems like
healthcare. And then obviously SEDI
because this is all built on the same
stack plays very nicely with the rest of
this. So the way that the BAI stack
works is they are the root of trust.
They create what are called QVIS that
issue a credential to organizations.
That credential is called the vLEI. Once
you have your VI, you can start to issue
credentials off of that vLEI to
individuals or entities within the
organization. And again, all of this
is cryptographically attestable all the
way back to the root of trust. So, I now
know who you are, who you work for.
In particular, I know what you're
in particular, I know what you're
doing, which is where direct trust comes
in. And it's the right things to be
doing. And that you are chained back to
GLE as a root of trust. So, super
important. the end result is we can
move from an ecosystem where connections
take you know weeks to a day or two and
like you said earlier today Mark the
actual technical lift on this takes
minutes it's going to be a day or two to
get the emails you know coordinated
right that's all the lift that has
to happen on these and we drop those
costs down by 75% or greater per
connection the result is of course that
If we take away the attacker's favorite
toy in this industry, they will move on
to other industries. They will find
another place to go and do compromises
because the third party attack that is
so common and prevalent today no longer
An issue. So what do VC? We
see a future where the question of can
we trust this connection is answered by
KERI through the VLE. So as you
incorporate the vLEI into the fire
standard, as you start to build network
interoperability standards that require
organizational ID, then you get to a
place where you can start to say yes,
the connection is trusted. And more than
that, you can start to automate
connectivity across multiple
organizations. The initiative that
we've kicked off for this is called the
vital initiative. It's backed by
Caroline's direct trust and GLEIF.
This is this is a group that's come
this is this is a group that's come
together and said yes, VC this as a
problem. We want to get this solved.
So I'll stop there. What questions do
so I'll stop there. What questions do
you have for me?
Yeah.
So when
I'm writing up and I'm making fire end
points to Epic. So do you foresee this
protocol or this trust layer being the
the inter intermediary in that fire
call or is it a
I'm trying to understand at what level
do you actually implement this?
Yeah. So we would we would see it as
embedded within the fire API the call
itself. So every time you reach out and
call basically you're doing a credential
presentation. You're saying this is my
VI and any of the relevant engagement
context RO credentials underneath that
that say I am Etna. I'm the CIS admin
there and I have a purpose of use for
payer-to-payer connectivity. And all of
that is cryptographically handed to you
as you establish the connection and then
the data flows through a typical fire
API.
What about from the clinical parts
for
so the next step for us really so this
this is the simplest version right we're
trying to get to just can we prove to
the payers that they can connect here
the next step I think you're absolutely
correct is to say can we get this to the
providers right and that becomes a much
more complicated individual
identity but you end up having to you
know a provider can work at three
different places so what's the context
in which they're operating so that's
where the VI with a purpose of use tied
to a digital identity would be able to
say because you're working for Beth
Israel as a as a provider that yes you
can request data about this patient
you're treating
yeah and there's there's going to be I
anticipate there will be a large
Fruitful discussion in the future
around how we do credentiing for
providers using things like this.
Right now there's a there's a very
right now there's a there's a very
very expensive rent seeking happening
which is the American Medical
Association gets $300 million a year
just issuing credentials to providers
to provide care. And like we heard
earlier today oftentimes that can take a
couple of weeks to get things done. So,
okay. And we are at time. So, thank you