Okay, well, let's get started everybody.
Thank you for coming to this session.
Hopefully, you'll find it interesting.
Let's see if I can get my cur- whoa,
my cursor. There we go.
Oh.
So, my presentation is on did:webs.
My name's Jonathan Rayback.
I am
a co-chair on the did:webs task force
underneath the KERI stack working group
at Trust over IP.
My other co-chair is Kent Bull here's
here with me.
And I'm going to be talking about DID
Web S.
I also am a chair of the DID methods
working group at Decentralized Identity
Foundation. So, I am squarely in the DID
ecosystem and community.
And
the
idea behind this talk is really to talk
about did:webs, which is the KERI entry
into the DID Web X
Genre of decentralized identifier.
So, the talk today is going to be
I would say pretty technical, and I'm
going to really assume that the audience
is fairly familiar with KERI. I'm not
going to assume that the audience is
familiar with DIDs. I'm going to sort of
that's kind of the point of the talk is
a little bit to describe DIDs and
why we have did:webs and how it relates
to KERI.
So, that's kind of I guess my prelude.
Let's see if I can actually get this to
There.
So, we're going to go through a little
bit about DIDs. We're going to do a
brief discussion on DID KERI itself cuz
there is DID KERI came before did:webs
and it is another DID method. We'll talk
about DID web,
the original DID web at W3C. We'll talk
about did:webs and why it exists
when DID web exists.
Then, we'll do a little bit of a
conversation about the relationship
between did:webs and DID web. We'll
talk about some other DID web X methods,
the status of did:webs from a standards
point of view, and then I'll do a little
demo.
So, decentralized identifiers or DIDs.
It is a W3C
official recommendation
As of several years ago. There
There's a 1.0 core spec and I think
they're working on a 2.0 spec now.
You can click through to the actual
specification there at on that
hyperlink.
It's a type of identifier. It's It's
formally a URI identifier that allows an
entity to communicate things like
cryptographic material keys,
Verification methods, and or service
endpoints like say an authorized agent.
And this communication happens by
resolving is the term the DID. So, you
resolve the DID like you would resolve a
URL. And when you resolve a URL, you get
back a usually a
chunk of HTML like a webpage or
something like that, some resource. When
you resolve a DID, what you get back is
a DID document and the DID document will
contain information like what are your
current public keys, do you have any
authorized agents, etc. etc.
So, the scheme
for a DID is you have
the mandatory URI scheme
prefix, which is DID,
the colon, similar to a URL.
So, like in a URL if it's the HTTP, you
know, and then whatever. This is in this
case it's DID, whatever.
The DID method name, so in the case of
did:webs this would be webas. And then
each did method has its own method
specific identifier that's determined by
the designers of the specification for
that did method. This is an example of
an imaginary one.
You have, in addition to the did
document, the did method itself
describes how do you create, update,
delete, you know, etc.
the did documents, and every did method
has its own mechanism for that, along
with its own method specific identifier.
There are currently hundreds of did
methods out there in various states of
standardization.
Many are associated with specific
blockchain technologies.
There are lots of other creative ones.
There are a few that deal specifically
with web and web protocols and web
infrastructure, of which didwebas is
one.
If anybody has questions, by the way,
at any point, feel free. Oh, there'll be
time for questions at the end,
hopefully, but if you just want to ask a
question, ask a question.
Okay, cool. So, decentralized
identifiers, as I mentioned, there are
four method operations that every did
method must explain. So, if you're going
to create a new did and then have a new
did method, you have to explain at least
how to do these four things. How do you
create them? How do you resolve them?
How do you update them? How do you
deactivate them?
Then the did document itself is
always called did.json, so it's a JSON
format following the specific did core
JSON scheme.
And
Every did that's compliant with the did
every did that's compliant with the did
spec is going to have a did document
did.json, and it's going to follow that
particular scheme, right?
Including didwebas.
Did document has specified
properties, including
and I'm I listed these out cuz these are
the ones that are particularly relevant
for didweb.es.
The subject of the did is in the ID
field.
The did can have other identifiers that
it calls out as equivalent IDs
basically, also known as
You'll see that in a minute. It has
Verification methods
Which is basically, you know, the
list of the keys that the
did controller is publishing the did
document. It can have verification
relationships, for example,
authentication saying this key is
authorized to authenticate for me or
this key is authorized to sign on my
behalf in these two cases.
You can also list out various services
that are relevant to you as a
controller.
Dids
did identifiers do support parameters
like URLs do, so you can have a did and
then like a question mark and a
parameter on the end that
allows you to, you know, adjust the kind
of information you're going to get back
from the resolver.
And there's also metadata that comes
back when you resolve a did. You'll see
that later when we do the
demo.
So this is an example did document. This
is pulled from the core did spec.
You can see in this case
the subject is this did.
And this particular the controller of
this did has authorized this key
which is an ED25519
key.
This one in particular.
[laughter]
They've authorized it to serve as
they've authorized it to serve as
authentication method.
It's basically what this did document
says.
Okay?
Questions so far?
Yes. Yeah.
There's no also known as In this one,
yeah. Also known as is a optional field
in the core spec. Yeah.
So and technically authentication is
so and technically authentication is
also an optional field. But yeah.
In didweb.es is not an optional field,
and that's why I called it out earlier
cuz DID web asset does makes, you know,
has certain
additional requirements above and beyond
the core spec, okay?
So, I just wanted to cover this really
quickly. I added this morning cuz
like if I was in a DID KERI conference,
I thought someone would ask what do I
DID KERI. There absolutely is a DID
KERI, okay? There's a specification for
it. It is
hasn't been touched in 4 years.
It's mostly
stub, I would say.
it's it's like got all the sections,
It's it's like got all the sections,
but each section kind of says, "Need to
fill this in," right? Like it hasn't
really been filled in yet. It's it's
very
early draft, very draft, right?
A DID KERI is very simple. It's just,
a DID KERI is very simple. It's just,
you know, the
Prefix,
prefix,
the name of the DID method, which is
KERI, and then the AID. That's a DID
KERI.
The thing about DID KERI is it is
entirely silent on the topic of discover
discovery. How do you discover
the ver the KEL essentially? How do
you cuz like if you know the KEL, this
is totally sufficient for you to go do
whatever you need to do, right? You just
you have the AID, you go to the, you
know, Key Event Log, you can do whatever
you need for validation. But the but the
DID method itself doesn't give you any
hint on like how am I supposed to get
this KEL? And I and I think this
spec was actually written pre-OOBI world.
So, like they didn't have the idea of
OOBIs even yet. So, now you would say
you're probably just going to get an OOBI
or something, right? But
it in the day, you know, we just
don't have this. So, it has limited
practical use is what I'm saying, right?
In the real world today.
Because
you are going to have to negotiate how
to
Discover the
verifiable history
outside of the method itself.
Okay, so did web going to the other side
of the world. So in the W3C, right, it's
the
web specification, web standards
organization, they thought, "Well, if
we're going to have these DIDs, we
should have a did web. That would be
amazing, right?" So yes, there is a did
web and it's an unofficial draft right
now at the W3C, but
it's it's used and it's used in
production. People use did web. When
when I was at Gen
Digital, the solution we were
developing was built around did web.
So, the thing about did web is it's
all web technology, it's all web
infrastructure. So,
the way that you get to the way that you
resolve a did web is you turn it into a
URL and resolve the URL in your browser,
with KERL, you know, programmatically,
with a headless
browser, whatever,
And you get back did.json. And that's
amazing. It is extremely It's a very
very extremely limited practical use
because
there's no history of that did document.
That did document could change at any
time. It's subject to any of the
exploits that are common on the web,
man-in-the-middle attacks, hijacking,
you know, DNS, like any of these things.
It's completely subject to
all those problems. When you get a
did document, you have no way of knowing
that the key that's published here now,
frankly, is the key. But you also have
no idea of knowing this controller at
some point in the past may have had
other keys, may have signed things with
other keys.
Don't know. None of that. You know You
know none of that with a did web. Yes.
I
wanted to plus one and add a bit of
bit of history. So, I was one of the
co-creators of the did web
Spec and it was always meant to be
spec and it was always meant to be
training wheels.
Right? This was like, "Hey, you're just
dipping your toe into did web. You're
going to try to do key
and then, you know, try did web like to
resolve it over the network."
But, it has all of the all of the
downsides that you just mentioned.
Right? There's no key history.
There's no cryptographic binding of that
identifier to the key, all that stuff.
The funny part is, so
I've at least always meant to add that
to it.
But, what happened was so I was I was
one of the authors of this back.
And I opened an issue like, "Okay, now
that we've gotten it out there, let's
add cryptographic binding. Let's add key
history."
And the other developers were like,
"Nope." And I was like, so basically
there was a lot of pushback against
that. They're like, "We're going to keep
it super basic. We're going to we're
going to leave the binding and the
history to other methods."
This is
this is
Yeah.
So.
that's that's basically what ended up
happening. Hence, did web
and all that stuff.
Yeah. Yeah, thanks. Appreciate the
history. So,
history. So
So this is a the main thing I wanted
so this is a the main thing I wanted
to show here was kind of just give a bit
of background, but then
if you look at the syntax of a did web,
this is like relevant as we move
into did:webs and other did web X
methods. So, you're going to have
basically the method specific
identifier for a did web is looks very
much like a URL. So, you're going to
have your you know, host information.
You can have an optional port
information. It has to be percent
encoded like this with URL safe.
And then some path to whatever the
document is. This would then translate
into a URL that looks like this, right?
So,
your host is example.com on port 3000,
path to document did.json. You resolve
this, you're going to get back that JSON
did document.
So,
there because of did web having the
shortcomings that it has, a number of
designers have proposed solutions. Did
web S is one of them.
I think it was really the first,
honestly, and then some others spun off,
but
did:webs has a specification. Kent and
I are responsible for it. We're working
on it.
[laughter and gasps]
But what did:webs does
is it separates discoverability from
verifiability. So we use the web to
discover the information about the
identifier, and you can use the did
document to get the keys and all of
that. But, if you want to verify the
information in the did document, you do
that via KERI events
through something we call the KERI
event stream, the KERI event stream,
which is kind of an
aggregation of various KERI events from
various sources that the control that
may be relevant to the controller, and
that's aggregated into this KERI event
stream. So, to resolve a did:webs, you
actually are resolving two resources,
two endpoints. You resolve the did.json
and get the did document, but then you
also resolve the KERI CESR, and you
have to validate that just like you
would any other KERI event stream. We
have a question back here. Yeah, I just
wanted to ask you is it possible to get
the copy of the slides? Yeah. There's a
Yes. There's a little QR code at the
end if you want to just scan it. Yeah.
Yeah. Yeah.
Yep.
Oh, all slides all presentation
Well, I must have missed that in the
beginning.
So, it just makes it's more widely
adoptable than did KERI because, you
know, it's got existing web
infrastructure. It solves the problem of
how you discoverability.
And it keeps the security cloud
properties of KERL.
It provides way better verifiability
than did web did web certainly, but
also than other did web X methods. And
we'll talk about did web versus other
did web X methods a little bit at the
end. But there are properties you get
from did:webs that you don't get from
any other did web X method.
This is a did:webs identifier. You can
see it looks super similar to a did web
identifier. The only difference is
the last segment of the method
specific identifier is always the
autonomic identifier. It's always the
AID of the controller.
So
da
path. You know, you've got the host,
you've got the port, optional port,
you've got the path, and then at the end
you've got the identifier.
In order to resolve this, you're going
to turn this into essentially a URL up
to the path, and you're going to go get
the \slash} did.json and the \slash}
KERL.cesr,
and the very first thing you better see
in that KERL cesr is the inception event
for that AID.
If you don't see that, you're already
no go. No bueno. Right?
So that path is not is just to a web
server that's serving the redirect. It's
not necessarily the KERL watcher.
It's not the KERL watcher. 100% not the
KERL watcher. It is where you go to get
the
Ultimately, it's where you go to get the
KERL.cesr stream.
But it's also where you can for
convenience get the did.json file,
because it's a did. By specification,
you have to have a did.json file there
at that endpoint as well. And then with
that did.KERL stream, that's where
you're going to confirm against the
watcher to make sure that it verifies
correctly. Sure. KERL.cesr, you're going
to take the information from
the
KERL event stream With the file is
called KERI.cesr.
It's a cesr encoded stream of KERI
events and you're going to use that,
yeah, sure, against the watcher or
whatever validation you're
going to do. What's going to happen
first is your did resolver is going
to validate that. That's what a did webs
resolver is supposed to do is check
that.
So, I mean I'm I'm not hearing so I'm
trying to understand.
The cesr file is the source of truth for
that Key Event Log? Yes. Okay, it's a
Yes. The cesr is the credential is the
credential encoding format used by
KERI.
Okay. Correct? Cesr is a it's an it's a
streaming yeah, it's a streaming
protocol.
It include which includes encoding, yes.
So, so given that we are reversing we're
giving responsibility to the controller
for his her keys? Yeah.
Is there a protocol that given
this
exception log gets pushed to the domain
of some
DNS host
or I mean a website?
Or
Yeah. I'm
I'm I'm looking at it from the custodian
perspective. So, I have my customers, I
assign them a did webs did. Mhm. But
then
it breaks the whole purpose of KERI,
right? Where my controller is
No, we'll talk about that in a minute,
actually. Okay. But
theoretically you could provide a
hosting
platform for individuals to have a did
webs. You could certainly do that. And
the individuals have to push their own
Well, they wouldn't have to push their
own. You could do that for them, but
but there's a mechanism that did webs
has that is intrinsic to KERI that
allows the controller to authorize that
endpoint as the definitive endpoint for
their did.
And we'll talk about that in just a
minute. And that's actually one of the
unique features of did:webs that other
did:webs methods do not have. And this
is maybe a good point, too, to bring out
the fact that
In did:webs, and this is a it may seem
in did:webs, and this is a it may seem
like a minor kind of detail, but it's
actually functionally has some pretty
important ramifications.
did:webs, the DID document is always a
derivative of some KERI event stream.
Always.
So, there's no idea of like
I'm going to go write this
like type out my DID document or
something like that, right?
Like
the DID document should always be
generated from some KERI event stream,
and the current key state and all of the
other events that have happened in that
have a consequence on what shows up in
the DID document. This is reversed from
other did:webs methods like DID Web VH,
where it's kind of the other way around.
The DID document and the state of the
DID document creates the verifiable
history as hashes.
It's the other way around. And
there are some ramifications for this
that
come up.
It's it's less it's a less nuanced
differentiation than you might think.
Are you going to cover those
ramifications? At the end, yeah. We'll
talk about it for a little bit, yeah.
You just piqued my interest.
[laughter]
So did:webs has some features that
just come because it's KERI based. You
get multi-party signatures.
You get delegation. I want to be
clear this is really clear for
people who are in KERI land, there's
kind of there's two kinds of delegation
we can talk about, right? There's
ACDC-based delegation that you get
through like VE LI, where you get, you
know,
this hierarchy of credentials that
go back to a root credential. That's not
what we're talking about here. This is
AID delegation. This is where my
identifier is specifically saying, "And
this identifier is allowed to act on my
behalf. Okay? That's a different kind of
delegation. We can we can encode that
into a did:webs did document. It
supports services that are relevant to
KERI like OOBI endpoints, witnesses,
agents, mailboxes, and it supports
designated aliases
through ACDCs. So this is an ACDC
delegation concept, but this is where
for example
it's required in the did:webs spec that
if I'm going to have my did web
I
I says example.com in it
implicitly I'm telling you I've
authorized this. In a did:webs when I
give you
you know, Moisey's service.com
or whatever it is you're hosting for
people
like
the person who's verifying my did gets
to go through my KEL and gets to see
that I actually did at one point give
you the authorization to host that at
this location. This is the only did web
S method that provides that capability.
Sorry. Did I control their scale? Where
where do those live?
They live in the authorization.
Are you asking where does what live? The
the controller's KEL live.
The controller's KEL lives wherever
the controller's KEL lives cuz it's
KERI, but the information from that KEL
that's relevant to the did:webs is
aggregated into this KERI event stream
and encoded in a KERI.CESR file which
lives on your server cuz hosting it.
Yeah, Ken. So I want to I want to
May I add something to
Sure. what you said earlier?
So, earlier you said, and this is
important
for those that are new to DID Web As,
you said
the DID Web As DID document is always
derived from the KERI event stream.
Mhm. And I think it's worth
highlighting the fact
that based on what you just barely said
about the path information being in an
ACDC,
that the DID document will always be
derived
from an ACDC as well. You've got the
KERI event stream with the KERI
event logs, and actually the tail and
ACDC. So,
cuz when I was first learning the DID
Web As spec, I was like, oh, is there a
is it Does it make sense to just have a
KERI event as it cuz I you know, that
was simpler, I thought. I thought it
was a good idea at the beginning.
Then as I got more familiar, I thought,
you know what? Actually,
cuz my goal was maybe we can have a DID
Web As version that only depends on
KERI, not KERI and ACDC. I tried
to simplify it.
But actually, when you look at the
security characteristics that you're
going to get into in just a minute,
Jonathan,
you want there to be an explicit
authorization
of the path segments of the whole DID.
So, it's important to realize that
the KERI event stream I think it
bears repeating that the KERI event
stream will always include at least one
ACDC. It has to have one ACDC. You
cannot have a DID Web As unless there's
at least one ACDC because at the very
least, you have to authorize the host
and path information for the DID Web As.
Period. That's all. Why is DID Web VH
inherently unsafe? Well, it's not
inherently unsafe. It does a lot of
things fine. One thing it does not do is
it doesn't let you as a controller
explicitly
authorize host and path information for
your identifier. It's always implicit
because like I'm going to give you my
DID web VH and it's going to say
rayback.com and because I gave that to
you by whatever mechanism, you're going
to assume implicitly that I've
authorized that.
KERI says no, I'm going to actually
validate that because I'm going to check
to see if you issued an ACDC authorizing
this cryptographically. That's an
explicit authorization versus implicit.
So that makes sense. I just want to add
web VH implicitly authorizes it not just
by handing over but by
signing. Right? There's an The
identifier.
The identifier. There's there's an
implicit authorization
signed with the user keys
that serves as a
Yeah.
Yeah. True.
And I might as well just get to the
point cuz I may not get to the slide
cuz I realize I'm running out of time.
But like the other thing that did web VH
does not do as well as did:webs is the
long-term long-term long-lived
multi-decade
identifier problem.
The spec really tries to make sure that
it's possible to do that but it gets
quite awkward. If you're going to change
like hosting, you're going to you're
going to change path websites over time.
And this is where I think that stems
from the fundamental difference. Like
you're essentially going to publish a
new
did document with new
location information in it and then you
have to kind of go and make sure that
your verify history A got transferred
from one domain to another, B that it
like has all of the steps in it, that
nothing got missed. Like that's all
really important. Managing that over
time is much less practical than a did
web S because it's the other way around.
In did:webs all of this is happening by
stuff in the in the KEL or the tel or
one of the KERI artifacts which ends up
in the KERI.CESR and therefore your did
document is always going to be like
reflective of the actual current state
of things cuz it's derived from the
KERI event information. So they did
tried to do KERI light and now they
have to bolt on.
I mean, they have a whole section on
witnesses and watchers now, so yeah, you
know, but
So, this is the also known as I want
to get into this really quick.
The spec requires there to be an also
known as section in every did web to
document. You must list the equivalent
did KERI as part of the also known as.
So, at least there's going to be a did
KERI in every did web to document cuz
that's considered an also known it's
always by definition
any did web is also known as did KERI
whatever the ID is.
You may, if you choose
authorize a did web endpoint.
So, that would happen by ACDC, the same
ACDC that the did:webs identifier shows
up in. You can authorize a did web
endpoint, which means you're authorizing
a did web resolver to go resolve the did
web version of the
Identifier
for interoperability or for whatever
reasons you want to you want, but like
you have to explicitly authorize that
and you if you don't authorize it
nobody should assume that like it's did
web resolvable. You have to look for the
actual identifier in the did document to
know that.
Verification method. Okay, so
this is
what a verification method looks like in
a did:webs did document. This is all
standard, you know, one of the various
options that's in the did standard.
We support JSON web keys. We support
ED25519. There are two or three other
you know, what whatever key
public key
are supported in KERI, we support in
did:webs.
Verification relationship. This is
verification relationship. This is
optional. It's optional to have this in
your did:webs, but did web the did web
S spec does say specifically if you are
going to include verification
relationship
the keys any key that you publish as a
public key must be authorized both for
authentication and assertion. That's the
one thing. If you're going to have it,
you have to have both.
So,
again, because KERI itself
any keys that you publish are for either
either authentication or assertion.
We support these services, these
KERI services, which would look
familiar, I think, probably. Looks
something like this in the
in the did document. So, this service
is a witness service. You can get to it
at this URL or this TCP endpoint.
Parameters, as I said, you can have
parameters on the end of a did
identifier, just like any other URI. So,
for example, this one has a version ID
parameter on the end.
This lets you tell the resolver
that you want version one of the So, you
can go back in time and derive the did
document that existed after
event with sequence number one occurred
in the in the KEL, right?
We also support this transform keys
extension, which just
I don't actually think we have this
implemented in the resolver right now,
but like theoretically, the spec says we
should support this. This basically just
means if you pass this in as part of the
parameter, we're going to transform all
the keys in the document to that format
for convenience. This is for convenience
for people who when they resolve the
did.
What other formats would you use besides
CESR?
I mean, they're like the native
format that we support is this JWK.
Okay.
JSON web key, right?
think I opened an issue on this. There's
public key JWK and public key
multi-base. Yeah, those are the two. I'm
already using public key multi-base in
the W3C cross walk, and so it's going to
be added to the resolver. And
the spec says we should be supporting
public key CESR as well. But,
then there's document metadata.
This is where you get into some like
I'm not going to get into much detail
here, but the main one has to do with
this equivalent ID. There's a bit of a
distinction, but the idea is anything
that should show up in the equivalent ID
in the metadata. This is not in the DID
document itself, it's in the document
metadata.
Should be other did:webs's that
you've authorized. And again, this is
going to happen via some ACDC. But, it's
possible you have a did:webs
example.com, but there's an equivalent
did:webs foo.com. That's fine. You can
have that. You just need to
definitely call it You have to have to
be authorized by ACDC. Yeah. Mhm.
Why equivalent ID and not put it in also
known as?
This goes to This goes back to the DID
core spec. So, the idea is
equivalent ID are equivalent ID of the
same DID method.
So, if I have a did:webs identifier,
any other did:webs identifier that I
want to call equivalent ID goes in
equivalent ID.
If I have a did:webs identifier, it
might also be known as a DID KERI DID
method, it might also be known as a DID
web DID method. You have It's more
inclusive. The also known as section is
meant to be more inclusive. The
equivalent ID is meant to be within the
scope of that DID method because it's
meant to be processed by a specific
resolver. That's going to be a did:webs
resolver, right?
I mean, it could be that
It could be for any other any number of
reasons, but
I can give an example there.
So, we like to do some work that's
called up with
DID IOTA and the twin. So, they did
IOTA Foundation. And the integration
point The initial integration point
between DID IOTA and did:webs was just
through mutual also known as. So, from
their DID document, they put the DID web
S. And from our DID document, we put the
DID IOTA in the also known as sections.
So, I'm going to go through this really
quickly cuz I want to do the little demo
and I'm like about 5 minutes. So,
This is important though because this
is something we had to like deal with
because of KERI cuz there was no way to
deal with this in the did document. So,
when you have
multi-signature. So, this particular
Verification method type, conditional
proof 2022, there's a spec for it at
W3C.
That's what it looks like. This is the
This is actually the KERI event
stream. So, you can see here that
there's a threshold. It's a two out of
three threshold involving these three
keys.
When you get to the did document itself,
it looks like
Oh, this is delegation. When you get to
the did document itself, it looks like
this.
So, you get a verification method,
conditional proof 2022. Says there's a
threshold of two, here are the keys, and
then here are the keys listed. We'll
look at that more detailed later.
And then this is a delegation of the AID
itself. It just basically you have to
provide the delegator OOBI so that the
person can go look up the delegator's
KEL and validate that the delegation
event is in that
doc. Okay.
I'm going to really quickly.
Specification status, there's a bunch of
stuff we've done. We've registered it
all the right places. There's a bunch of
like There's a draft final draft version
that's being reviewed at under the KERI
stack working group. There's an I a
new IANA media type registered. We also
are in the final review stage at DIF to
become a DIF recommended did method.
Okay. We're going to do the demo here
now really quick. So,
Yeah, that's why I want to do this. This
is pretty This is This is more like an
illustrative demo.
Why? Why? Why?
Oh.
Okay. So, the what we're doing here is
we're just going to kind of start doing
some KERI stuff. So, the first thing
I'm going to do is I'm just going to
accept an AID, right? So, I've I've
created this AID.
It has that public key.
This is what the
KEL looks like. This is what the KERI
event stream looks like.
Okay? So, you've got the
the AID, you've got the key.
At this point,
I cannot have a did:webs.
Why?
There's no ACDC authorizing the host and
path information. So, that's the next
thing I have to do. I have to issue the
the ACDC.
Here's the ACDC that I just issued
that's authorizing for this identifier
these two
identifiers. For this AID
identifier, these two did:webs or DID
identifiers. One is a DID Web In this
case, I'm authorizing a DID Web endpoint
as well in the correct format.
So, now I have this key event
log, this KERI event stream
that includes
the ACDC right here.
Right? That has my
host and path information
committed to, right? Now, I can create a
DID document.
So, this is what a DID a what did:webs
DID document would look like. This is
almost the most simple possible DID Web
S DID document.
I don't have to have a witness service
if I'm working in direct mode. So,
that's optional. I don't have to have a
DID Web identifier.
Beyond those two things, this is about
the most simple possible did:webs DID
document you could have.
Okay?
Now, let me show you a multisig
example.
So, I'm going to set up a multisig
group.
And they've got to do all the chatter
back and forth to get each other's
kills.
Okay, so now I've created a multisig
group. It involves three identifiers
with each key each one having one key.
You can see here that the keys are given
each one half weight. So, this is
fractional weight using very fractional
weights. That means that there are three
keys and each key gets half a vote.
So, in order to have a full vote, two of
the three have to vote, right? Two of
the three have to have to approve. That
gives you quorum.
That produces a DID document that looks
like this.
So, I've got my you know, my identifier.
I have my also known as. Now, here's my
verification method conditional proof
2022. It correctly determines that two
out of three, so two of these three
keys, which are listed in detail here,
have to sign in order for something to
be valid, right?
And then we get our cute pony.
CUTE PONY.
[applause]
SO, THERE'S THAT.
And then let me really quick just
show you in the last minute or so. I
have We have
Yeah, we have the
This is the universal resolver and I
forget Bend the Universal Resolver. This
is mostly Marcus and his work that he's
done on this. It's pretty amazing. Kent
wrote the driver for this. So, we have a
did:webs driver that goes here.
So
Let me grab my
did:webs identifier here.
So, I'm going to resolve this did:webs
did
at the universal resolver.
There it is.
Tells me where the witness is.
You can look at the did document, see
the did document.
You can see the document metadata where
you should get the equivalent IDs.
Okay.
And
this is where you cannot because
DIDweb as has the unique property of
the KERI CSER that's not available
on the universal resolver page.
If you want to see that.
I can resolve that.
Just by KERL here.
And you'll notice too that this CESR
that's getting
printed to the terminal.
Looks really great.
This is a tool that can't wrote recently
here that's a really nice that annotates
and prettifies the CESR stream.
So this is the CESR this is the this
is the
aggregated chunk of KERI events that we
call the KERI.caesars the KERI event
stream that created that did document.
So you're going to go all the way back
you're going to see an inception event
here.
Somewhere in here you're going to notice
that there's going to be an ACDC.
It's very bottom.
Right here.
That authorizes the endpoints.
So.
So there you go. That's what I got. Time
[applause] up.