Hi everyone. For those of you who don't
know me, I'm Phil Feairheller, CTO and
co-founder of healthKERI. And
those of you who are presenters will
know that we had to submit our talks
ahead of time to get the slides
approved. And so I submitted a talk on
ACDC's for authentication. But I'm I'm
going to pull a little bit of a fast one
and switch it up because there I think
is a much more important topic that we
need to discuss and that is HIO. Why
Sam? I'm just kidding. I'm not going to
do
totally kidding. I'm actually doing
ACDCs for authentication.
Okay, so this talk is based on the
demo that we did for the SEDI conference
and I have it here. I'm just going to
run the video of it real quick and
talk through what we did.
Let me get it started. So, in this demo,
we start with our Locksmith wallet. We
show that the wallet is holding a couple
of credentials, a VI credential and a
fake Utah SEDI health identification
card credential and the various fields
that are in it.
And then we switch over to the site
which is a fake healthcare portal and
demonstrate how we could use those
credentials to first create an account
and second to authenticate and log into
the account from there on go through the
fact that you could allow the user to
type in the information and suffer
through typos and everything else or you
could use the SEDI credential and get
accurate data and much more secure
connections. In addition to that, we
went over the fact that we could
introduce at the beginning of the OOTH
flow an offer stage that allows me to
offer the credential without sharing the
data and require a signed receipt back
from the site that they agree to my
terms and conditions before I give them
my credential and all the data in it. So
that's what we're doing here. We're
doing the offer.
We also demonstrated that the site is
built so that anyone using any other
KERI tool can create an offer and
upload it. You don't need the plugin.
Let me just use the plugin make it
work a little more smoothly. And then
here they have reti returned the signed
receipt.
You can view the receipt in the accepted
offer section
and then submit the full credential and
now you're logged into the site. You've
created your account.
All the data is extracted from the
credential
and you are now signed in. And then you
can go through the process and sign in
again. And the point here was that we
made it such that the process of
using a any kind of ACDC credential for
this form of authorization can be just
as easy as using a pass key, for
example, but of course much more secure
because it's based on a KERI identifier
through the stuff I'm going to show
next. Key rotations work seamlessly. You
can do them anytime you want. And if you
use this AID in this account,
how do I go next? There we go. If you
use this AID for multiple sites that
you've logged into, you do one key
rotation and they'll all get your new
keys. So you don't have to worry about
changing a password, remembering
passwords for many different sites, etc.
So that demo was something that we kind
of backed into because of the work that
we've been doing in healthcare. And so
what I want to cover today is how we got
to that by starting to work with
integrating the vLEI into the OAuth
protocol for a specific purpose related
sorry specific per purpose related to
these protocols. But then we realized
that if we just keep going and extend it
a little bit further into OOTH, we could
do end user authentication. So these
protocols I realized this morning
looking at my slide you've all heard
about them now I think at least three
different times in three different
sessions. So I'm going to go over them
very quickly but to make a very
specific point about them. So HL7 fire
think of it as REST APIs for healthcare
very simple but extensible data model
specific to healthcare. It supports
real-time APIs documents and messages.
It is actually written into HSS
regulations and it was informed by all
of these other standards that have been
used in healthcare for 30 years, Mark.
20 years. Yeah. And so the old way Mark
explained this in another session
yesterday. The old way was is that as
they were starting to exchange more and
more data, they were just exchanging
documents over these protocols and
the documents were just getting bigger
and bigger because they had to send the
whole thing. So fire what it did was
allow people to send distinct sections
of records that were much easier to
transmit and of course modernized
because they're REST APIs. So the fire
modules are broken down into these
different categories. You have your
foundation and base resources and then
of course you have the specific
resources that are defined for things
like clinical, financial, specialized
resources. And you can see all the
categories here. they're not
particularly interesting to us or
KERI, but I wanted to point out that
what we're trying to accomplish is
the ability to do authorization at a
level that's as low as this. So, very
particularly, we are working on
something called pair-to-payer access,
which allows payers to, for example, if
you switch from one pair to another, get
your information over to the other payer
much more seamlessly than happens today.
But we only want the two companies to be
able to exchange data for
payer-to-payer, not for anything else.
So, we're able to dig in at this level
and create authorizations very specific
to the purpose of use.
Okay. And what got us here? What got us
here was CMS 0057F final rule. easy to
say and it mandates that Medicare
Advantage, Medicaid and CHIP plans. So
anyone that interacts with these people
have to implement firebased APIs to
streamline prior off and accelerate
decision times.
So you have the impacted players here as
I said anyone who works with these
people. The one that's probably most
interesting to folks in the industry is
the prior off because that's always been
a sticking point. Takes forever. It's
manual in some cases. They want this
to be automated much more quickly.
Patient access, so getting into patients
patient access, so getting into patients
being able to get a hold of their own
data at the fire level. But then the one
that we focused on because it's the
easiest to get pilots going, it's the
most constrained use case was the
pair-to-pair data exchange. So this
mandate is forcing by January of 2027
health plans to implement this. So that
was our opportunity and what gave us the
idea actually Mark the idea that we
could integrate the vLEI into this to
accelerate the connections that are now
going to be needed between these payers
and then down the road between payers
and providers and then down the road
even further between patients and payers
and providers. So you're starting to see
the number of connections that are going
to be needed. Making those connections
quickly and securely would be a limiting
factor without what we're trying to
implement.
So OOTH 2 I don't really need to go
into this most of you probably are aware
of what it is legacy kind of like
using the word legacy authorization
authentication protocols
essential for essential for
interoperability and that's the key so I
think the biggest lesson learned for
healthcare here is meeting the customer
where they are a little history when we
first started out we created a product
called rack routing authenticity and
confidential confidentiality with
KERI. I like making acronyms, too.
And what that was is a API gateway
and what that was is a API gateway
that wrapped every transaction in an ESR
ESSR packet. So, signed and encrypted to
a specific destination and provided full
security between those two endpoints. No
need for TLS, no need for VPNs, anything
else. And it also created a
cryptographically verifiable audit log
of every single transaction.
Nobody wanted to use it because it was
not interoperable. So what we have done
over the course of the last six months
is slowly back our way out and meet the
customer where they are by integrating
with OOTH because fire requires o or
requires or mandates or includes the
ability to use OOTH for authentication
a protocol I'm about to talk about next.
UDAP had taken OOTH and added five or
six, I only mentioned four here, new
profiles that allowed the use of X509s
embedded into these different flows to
do authentication.
Mark Scrumshshire came to us and said
that seems to work, but what happens
when everyone hits their 47-day limit
and they have to rotate all their
searchs? What happens? And so as the
companies we were talking to, they're
like, "Well, I have to manage my Certs,
but now I got to worry about everyone
else's CS. How what do I do when they
all have to rotate? How do we
reestablish these connections?" And so
he identified that the vLEI would be the
perfect opportunity to introduce true
organizational identity and KERI to
solve this problem in a very similar way
that UDEP did, but replace X509's with
the VLE.
And there's there's quite a bit more
detail underneath. I'm not going to get
into it, but we have other credentials
that chain off of VLIS to define the
purpose of use to allow them to be that
more specific authorization I was
talking about, but we don't need to
go to that level of detail. So these are
the four protocols or profiles that
were defined in UDAP that we are
going to be augmenting or replacing. So
the first one and this is where we were
going to stop before we decided to do
something for the SEDI presentation
and that is dynamic client registration.
So in oathor is what is it RFC7591
dynamic client registration that allows
people without having a developer go to
a developer portal and register your
client ID get a secret or enter a secret
get it back so that your client app can
now make token requests. There is a
RFC that allows for that to be dynamic.
And so what UDEAP had done was say okay
if we insert a signed statement from the
client and a reference to their X509erts
if we have an ecosystem of CAS that we
trust for this purpose we can allow a
client to be registered dynamically and
and automatically. So we saw that and
said okay cool works great just replace
X509s with VIS and now we're on to
something. So that's the first thing we
did. So we automated the ability payerto
payer remember that's what we're
focusing on. We automated the ability
for one payer to submit a credential to
another payer and without any human
involved be registered to start
interacting payer-to-payer APIs and from
there that point down the rest of their
stack stays the same. They're using
they're using fire APIs. They're using
token. They're doing the token requests
because this is client au
authentication. So there's no
authorization code step first. And so
that worked great. Then when we decided
that okay, that authorization server
works great. There's a real good
opportunity here to insert ahead of or
after client authentication after client
registration and then client
authentication to do user
authentication. So they had JWTbased
user authentication which allowed for a
cert to be used to sign a JWT that would
then assert who the user is. So you
could do the user authorization flow
which involves getting a code first then
it redirects back to you and then you
use that code to get the token. We
replaced that with VI as well and that's
what I demoed here. The last step was
after having conversations with the with
the fine folks in the state of Utah,
George and Chris, we realized that there
was still one problem left to solve and
that was okay, if we're using these
credentials, how do we still know that
our data is being protected? And that's
when we added a new step that's not part
of OOTH, the credential offer. And so
doing the credential offer allows us to
offer a credential based on a schema. So
the structure of the fields, a
cryptographic commitment to what the
data will be and require the site to
sign your terms and conditions with that
cryptographic commitment before you
reveal the data to them. Then once you
reveal the data, they can verify that
yep, it matches the schema. Yep, that's
the data they promised to give me
without revealing the data. Now I can
register them and allow them through.
So I pretty much just talked about
this but the crank credential the client
credentials flow with UDAP and VI
involved you know like I said dynamic
client registration with VLI we do a
sign inserted inside of the
Client registration request it's
slregister is an IPEX presentation in
the OOTH registration request itself the
flip side of this one of the things that
UDAP had that we borrowed from is a
well-known for the server so that we
could identify by the server. So we can
avoid having a server that we get a man
in the middle or whatever. So in our
case, we just have in the well-known an
OOBI that identifies the AID of the
server that we're going to be
interacting with.
Pardon me. Oh, so then finally, and
most importantly in this case, the
client ID is mapped to the set of the
presented credential. The set of the
presented credential. And there's no
client secret. Every token request from
here on out is a signed request. So you
eliminate a shared seeker from the
equation and you have fully signed token
requests. Now of course our hope is that
once they see the power of this they'll
say okay now that I can sign these token
requests can I sign all my other
requests and then we'll start selling
them rack.
So then that and so then I just
touched on the client credentials
flow. Every other request after that
is present is a IPEX presentation
signed and the client and server key
rotations are supported by the watcher
network and I'll talk about how we
implemented that to enable connectedness
as trust at scale specifically for
purpose of use and these extensions to
the ooth protocol.
So then the logical next step
authorization code flow. Let's let the
user now leverage what we've done to log
in with their VI credentials. Okay,
good. So we extended the model to
support user authentication with data
privacy of doing the offer ahead of the
actual credential presentation. So this
is a typical OOTH flow. The user
the resource owner goes to the client
application. The user gets redirected to
the authorization server. They say
approve. It comes back here. The client
then says, "Okay, here's the code. Can I
have a token?" You get the token and
then you send that over to the fire
resource server and you get your data
because the resource server is able to
talk to the authorization server behind
the scenes and say, "Is this a valid
token?" So that's how it works. This is
a I stole this diagram from actually I
made it but I looked at someone else's.
This is what it looks like with KERI
and the vidc.
So in this case the resource owner has a
KERI database. The client application
has a KERI database and the
authorization server has a KERI
database. So in this case when he is
redirected over there he submits a
credential instead of username and
password. You've all done this with log
on with Google, right? This is the exact
same thing but it's now log on with your
ACDC credential.
So then you get redirected and
everything works the same. But the
really important part here is these
arrows. Everybody is watching the
watcher network and each other's
witnesses so that when he decides to
rotate his keys, he can do it every hour
if he wants to. We actually did that in
a in a pilot we were running. It was
really fun. He can rotate every hour if
he wants to. It'll get propagated to his
witnesses. Everyone else's watchers will
pick it up and now it's still fully
secure and you have new keys as
frequently as you want.
What's that?
Yes, you can hyper churn your
credentials.
And Sam, your voice is sounding better.
Okay, so IPEX issuance and
presentation exchange protocol. It's a
protocol built on top of KERI EXN
messages and it allows this flow
defined. I stole this table from the
KERI spec, the ACDC spec, sorry.
It allows this flow of messages to
negotiate credential exchange between
two parties. So we are only starting at
the offer phase and you can see where
you can start. That's the wise in here.
And you can see after an apply you can
spurn it. I love that you use the word
spurn. I don't know why I just do.
You can offer it. You can either spurn
you can offer it. You can either spurn
or agree to the offer and then you can
grant the credential. And then once you
grant the credential, this is an
important step, you admit it, which
sends the admission back to the person.
So you have a receipt that they accepted
your credential.
And so what we've leveraged with IPEX,
one of the I think the driving factors
for IPEX was graduated disclosure, chain
link confidentiality, and contingent
disclosure on them accepting your offer,
assigned acceptance of your offer. And
then once you embed the rules inside of
your credential, the metadata credential
that you exchange back and forth during
these exchanges, you get
contractually protected disclosure as
well. And that's what we're leveraging
here
and I just said that. So this just
details the contractually protected
disclosure. The user offers the terms
and conditions, no data exposed. you get
a cryptographic commitment in the offer
to the structure of the data hash of
what the data will be and then terms and
conditions which are being enforced. I
I think in the future we can see sites
offering a couple of just like when you
create a GitHub account you can pick
your license for the for the new
GitHub repo. I can see a world where
sites are offering different terms and
conditions and the user can select which
one best suits their needs for giving
the data to the site and if none then
they don't give the data.
the site agrees, returns the signed
agreement, and then the user saves the
receipt and grants the full credential.
And that's what the flow that we showed
in the demo.
So, this is just further detailing the
The credential offer comes back or
I'm sorry, the site comes back
and says, "We'll accept an offer, you
make the offer, you get to see what
terms and conditions are there before
you agree to it."
And then the signed agreement comes back
from the server. We use our plugin to
validate it. But again, at any point if
you don't have our plugin, you want to
do it yourself, you just download the
signed agreement, you send it through
KERIpy, if you want to or any tool
that supports this flow with KERI
and you can then upload your offer or
your full grant, sorry, you upload your
full grant, which we do with the submit
full credential and now the site gets
your information. And when we did this,
it really did hit home that the
user benefits greatly for all the
reasons I just talked about, but the
site benefits from it is something I
think George said in one of his talks.
they get cryptographically verifiable
data. They're not going to get typos.
That's going to halt that's going to
slow down the process of users signing
onto your site and getting access to the
data that they need.
Okay, so this is how we did it. We built
an ACDC authorization server. It acts
as both an O2 authorization service as
well as an OIDC identity provider. So
we're doing it with ACDC schema
configuration.
You can configure both the client
registration schema that you'll accept
and it can be a list and you also
specify the user authentication schema
that you'll accept and it can be a list.
Each of those supports a base schema
specification which allows you to
enforce what issuers you will accept at
any chain in your hier credential
hierarchy. So, for example, an oversight
we did with GLEIF, the I can I can
issue VI credentials. They're not valid
because they don't come from GLEIF root,
but you can enforce that it has to come
from GLEIF Route in here by putting the
issuer of the GLEIF root AID.
This was a fun part. ACDC payload to
OIDC claims mapping. We used a pretty
simple template syntax ginger 2 for
those of you who are familiar with
Python to create complex field mappings
between the credential payload and the
OIDC claims that come out the other end.
So when you put all this together, what
you're really doing is you're creating a
truly distributed identity provider
appliance. I can put one of these up,
specify a list of credentials, I'll
accept, specify how I want the data to
look in OIDC.
Someone will submit their credential to
me and I'll let him in. Sam can do the
same thing. We never have to talk. Our
systems aren't federated. We don't share
data. If he specifies the same schema as
me, he'll let the person in the same. It
looks exactly the same to the user. The
data comes back to the to the relying
party, no, to the client application,
sorry, of who that user is. But
there's no federation. You're not
relying on Google to hold your Gmail
account. you're doing it with a
decentralized credential issuance from
anyone.
So then these are the flows I've already
talked about that we worked with dynamic
client registration secret lists the
client authentication flow this is for
our pair to pair model so that the pairs
can then just start as soon as they do
the DCR the pairs can start exchanging
data by getting the token and then user
authentication.
Okay, so the last part I talked about
integration into the watcher network and
the witness network. For those of
you who know me, I do actually own a
great Dane and a bull mastiff, but these
aren't my dogs.
So we called it HK Tracker and it's
what Sam has been calling forever a
local watcher. And so anywhere where we
deploy a server that or a or a system
that needs access to the KERI watcher
network, it's going to be resolving AIDs
and it's going to need to keep track of
key state. Any enterprise system we can
put as a sidecar. So think of a sidecar
pod inside of Kubernetes or just running
along in a VM. We put a local watcher
service which is configured to our SaaS
platform to be able to ask our platform
to start watching new AIDs. So the
situation where someone authenticates
for the first time and then continue to
keep track of their key state changes. So
it adjudicates the key state changes
locally and integrates with the KERI
watcher network. It uses our secure ESSR
secure connections to our APIs to get
the updates for the AIDs that it cares
about. And the cool thing is it doesn't
have to do it for any ids that have
registered with SAM server because I
don't care about those only the ones
that I have authenticated against. And
so we use borrowed very heavily
from Tailscale if any of you are
familiar with that VPN company. They
have a model for when you want to get a
ser a headless server on the system you
go into the site and you get a
authentication code onetime
authentication code that you use. And
so that's how we do it down there.
And so these are my actual dogs. I just
wanted to show this. That's Zoe, my
great Dean. That's Jackson, our bull
mastiff. And that's Remy
rescue pit bull.
Okay. And then this is the diagram that
we've created. I think Jared already
showed this in one of his talks, but
this is the diagram we created when we
were first trying to conceptualize this.
And the idea here is that when you look
at the convergence of what's happening
here, Direct Trust is working very
closely with GLEIF
to help facilitate bringing the VI
ecosystem into healthcare.
And so you can have these credentials
issued into a payer and a provider
wallet, dynamic client registration,
client authentication.
They can issue VIS down to their
members. state of Utah can issue set
credentials and then all of them can now
authenticate against the site and get
the data they need using this exact same
method. So that's what we're trying to
get at here.
And that's it. Any questions? Yes. Do we
have a microphone?
Just a quick question. Can you say
more about the difference between the
payer and the provider wallets?
So,
like what they're meant for.
Oh like the purpose of use, like
why a payer would be accessing another
payer versus why they'd be accessing a
provider. Is that what you mean?
Yeah. Yeah. And what the wallets do,
like what's their provider mean?
Oh, well, so yeah, I'll go back. So,
in this case this was just meant to
represent the fact that you have
this the same type of wallet.
Got it. The payer would be holding his
VI credential and use it to access
anyone else in the ecosystem. Literally
anyone else in the ecosystem access
their data.
Got it. Those are just roles, not
different wallets. Okay. Got it. I
misunderstood.
Okay. So, my question is about the
authorization server flow. Wow. I'll
hold the mic a little further away from
my mouth.
So, so the authorization server waits
for an ACDC presentation. So that does
that make your the ACDC essentially
the identity provider?
Yeah. Yeah. That's why I call it a
dynamic identity provider appliance
because it's it's just you install
anyone anywhere and you say trust these
credentials.
Okay.
And it just works.
Cool.
Yeah.
Is this Hello.
There you go. Is it limited to person
to business or can also be used in API
situations businessto business?
Yeah, the client authentication
flow, dynamic client registration and
then client authentication flow supports
businessto business.
So anywhere where you do you so in
OOTH you can do just client
client authentication where you skip the
authentication flow you get you don't
get the authentication code that's just
pair to pair that's businessto business
so it does support that as well
that's why I guess you have a client ID
because the client can get the data
themselves not on behalf of a user