All right. So, I want to introduce Henk
van Cann. Right, the KERI Fashion
Foundation would not exist without him.
He came out of retirement. He likes to
play guitar and sing on the streets in
the Algarve in Portugal, and he could be
doing that instead of being here with
you guys. So,
so give him a big round of applause.
And he's also a financial sponsor of
the KERI Foundation. So, there's no
amount of
thanks that I that
is too much for him.
So,
So
I want to thank everyone for coming.
this is KERI Conference 2026.
This is KERI Conference 2026.
Get a t-shirt cuz you'll never there'll
never be another first ever KERI
Conference. So, you know.
And I think they're downstairs, right?
Yeah. All right.
And then
one more one more one for the for the
for the sponsors.
So, I'm going to talk about the state of
the KERI Suite,
the journey to adoption.
And
and
I look at 2026. We've been doing KERI
for a lot of years now,
and it feels like this is going to be
the year of KERI. So, you know, mark
your calendars. This is where the world
starts to understand and
and know that KERI exists.
Some early feats
some early feats
That have already happened in 2026.
The KERI Suite of protocols released
as Linux Foundation open standards. That
was a five four-year process starting in
2020.
And we've got Trust over IP. Drummond
is the chairman is here today.
And then we have a couple of members
of the steering you know, several member
at least three members of the steering
committee here today. So, so they've
been helpful. Karla and Nico and
Drummond.
The
the
we started a funded project to build
open infrastructure for KERI.
We received a grant from the Utah
Governor's Office of Economic
Opportunity to build a did digital
identity utility for SEDI
based on KERI.
The Telecom Industry's OBCE Alliance
the Telecom Industry's OBCE Alliance
is
Doing proof of concepts to vet you use
doing proof of concepts to vet you use
of the KERI suite of protocols and the
verifiable voice protocol. And later
today you'll have a Daniel Hardman
is here. He'll talk about talk about
that.
We have Utah state passed the SEDI
implementation law
funded law to build to build SEDI.
There is
there is
Production implementation of
using those for stopping call spam.
Healthcare is vital
Initiative. We'll have a talk later
today about that with the vLEIKERI
and
and using the KERI for healthcare
data provenance.
We just completed the SEDI
Policy summit the last 2 days. How
many people are here that were here the
last 2 days?
All right, almost everybody. Fantastic.
So, you so I don't need to tell you any
more about what happened there.
And first ever annual KERI conference
and first ever annual KERI conference
today. So, that's just that's just this
first 4 months of 2026. We're just
getting started.
So, one of the things I want to
look at is
you know, what is
what is what are the chances of broader
adoption? What are the sort of
rules? And so, I went back to
Malcolm Gladwell wrote a book
called The Tipping Point.
And he had rules for
when adoption reaches a tipping point.
And the and this is a you know, a curve.
And the tipping point is this inflection
point down he- down here where
You sort of go from
you sort of go from
flat adoption to where you start to
get a significant grow- you know,
growth a steeper curve. And the
the reality is down here, it's not a
smooth curve. It's really noisy down
here. And so, really the tipping point
is when the noise starts to dissipate
and you start to see, you know,
year you know, month over month, week
over week, year over year growth. And
so,
so
So where
so where
we are we where does that tipping point
happen? How do we get to that
tipping point? So his three rules
are the law of the few, the stickiness
factor, and the power of context.
So, the law of the few. What does that
mean?
Well, if you have a sufficiently
influential set of early adopters, those
are the few.
That means you have to have people
that recognize the technical
suitability. And then they have to try
to get other people to adopt it.
And so, you guys
are the few. You're the ones.
So, let's see what's happened.
You have to first overcome the seven
stages of adoption resistance.
You know I know there's some people
in this room that, you know, shock,
denial, anger, bargaining, testing, and
acceptance, right? Most of you are
well along. There's still a couple that
maybe they're in the bargaining
stage yet. They're still trying to well,
do we really need KERI or you know,
does it really solve what we want? We'll
see.
So,
what are what are some adoption vectors
that the few start sort of like an
epidemic, right? What are some
of those? Well, I sort of hinted at
those. We have the telecom sector.
That could be a massive adoption
vector.
We have the healthKERI sector. That
could be a massive adoption vector.
And we have state entitlements,
which
Could be a massive adoption vector.
Any one of those
could
create, you know, cross the tipping
point. And since I'm I'm a fault
tolerant person, I believe in fault
tolerant systems. I got to have three,
right?
You got to have three massive adoption
vectors to make sure one works, right?
So, that's what that's where we're at.
Widespread bootstrap vectors. So, the
difference here is
in order to have adoption that is
we had a
saying in Florida, you know, what
what comes in over the transom goes out
over the transom.
You know, as a wave washes fish in, it's
junk fish, you don't want it, right? But
what we want are to have adoptions
that we didn't plan on. We didn't know
that they were going to happen. And they
they just they just they just spin up
spontaneously. And so, we need something
that will bootstrap those without us
forcing them. These are These up here
are the result of years of work.
I mean, you know, I we started working
with SEDI, you know, three years
ago. I know how long Provenant and
healthKERI have been working in their
sectors. It didn't happen overnight.
It took lots of time, right? But we want
to also have vectors that happen
quickly. So,
we have two bootstrap vectors,
organizational root of trust, that's
GLEIF.
And that's been the thing that has
been enabling these other ones, right?
It started They went to production with
the vLEI in 2022. That's That's now
been 4 years. Seems like it was
yesterday, but it's been 4 years.
So, we want to we
you know, and we're starting to see the
fruits of that.
But one of the things that is new this
year and in the next year is a personal
root of trust. That's never happened
before, not an organizational root of
trust, a personal root of trust. That
means lots of businesses
that wouldn't normally consider using
digital identity, centralized digital
identity,
are going to get for free bootstrapped
identity assurance that is highly
trustworthy.
That means every industry
has the potential to leverage
that root of trust, which is Utah state.
And then all scale enablement vector,
that's open standards,
open source, and open infrastructure.
I'm going to talk about what I mean by
open infrastructure a little bit later
in this talk.
So, there's the law of the few. So, I
feel like
we've got that.
The next one is the stickiness factor.
What makes it stick?
Well, it needs to be compelling and
contagious.
So, we have to think about things that
make it, right? So, we need to have some
sort of pathology that's endemic
that isn't going to go away and it's
going to stick
and it's going to keep driving adoption,
and that is fraud.
The world is filled with fraud. Every
business is suffering the cost of fraud.
And fraud includes identity theft. It
includes,
you know, all of the security,
you know, exploits,
you know, exploits
You know, ransomware.
you know, ransomware.
But, it includes just normal day-to-day
business, you know, factoring fraud, PO
fraud (Purchase Order), those sorts of things.
And they're getting worse. And one of
the things that are making them worse is
the fact that the tooling that enable
fraud has now reached the point where it
is better
than the mechanisms that protect against
fraud.
And so,
that's going to continually push people
over the edge, right? They're going to
say, "Do I really need KERI?" And you
go, "Well, can you fix fraud without
KERI?"
And they go, "Well, no, not really."
Okay, then you really need KERI.
Regular regulator imperatives to
repress fraud and abuse, right? Those
are happening in several industries. For
example, in the telecom industry, FCC.
In the healthcare industry, you know,
you see Scott schooling on his
head, right? In
in state
endorsed digital identity, right?
You're you now have regulators that are
you're you now have regulators that are
saying, "Hey, we need to we need to
we need to we have an imperative that
says we've got to get rid of fraud and
abuse." And by abuse, I mean
exploitation of citizens in the case of
personal identity.
The malaise of digital exploitation.
Do any of you feel like you're sick
of being exploited online?
Only a few of you. Okay.
Do any of you know of anybody that
feels like they're sick of being
exploited online? Okay. [laughter]
All right. Okay? Do you have a desire to
control your digital presence? Yes.
Absolutely, right? The
So, so that's a stickiness factor. Is
that desire going to go away?
Do you know anybody
wants to have less control?
I know I know some, but
Yeah,
there are few. But, most of the
everybody in this room I'm pretty sure
wants more control over the digital
presidents.
The other thing that's happening
is that the technology
that enables KERI
is key management.
And that means the devices, the
software, the systems operating systems
have to start moving in the direction of
educating people
to manage their own keys. And that is
happening.
You know, when we started KERI and
I mean, when I started doing digital
identity in 2015, 2016,
the people were
really like saying, "There's no way
you're going to get
people to manage the private keys."
Right? The blockchain community had
already gone there, right? They had to
manage private keys to be on the
blockchain, right? So, the technology
got a got a big boost. But, now you're
seeing it in every system. Everybody's
this endemic pathology is pushing
people to better key management.
And so, as people become familiar, the
friction to adoption reduces.
So, I think we have stickiness.
The power of context.
What that means is timing and
externalities. Is the timing right?
Well,
I think the specter of AI is making
an unprecedented,
you know, context that says the timing
is right.
We have we are faced with
the potential for the annihilation of
trust. There's an impending doom. I
don't If you guys don't see it, if you
aren't, go read OWASP 100-page
report they just
published
on how to deal with AI threats to
security.
And it is chilling cuz they say
it has never existed before, it is a
different type of threat, and we don't
have a cure. All we can do is mitigate
some of the symptoms.
And they're only going to get worse. And
it's 100 pages long.
Right. And it's And it's just starting.
And it's They're going to add 100 pages
on a regular basis because the threats
are increasing at an exponential rate.
So, impersonation,
been around for a while. AI
impersonation, deep fakes,
those They're just They just barely
happened.
When was the ChatGPT moment?
Yeah, 2023. It's only 3 years around,
and we're already
We're already see- seeing those effects.
Exploitation, you thought somebody
could exploit you? Wait till an AI
exploits you.
Surveillance, you thought you were being
surveilled online?
Wait till Just ask an AI to surveil you.
You know, I've done this test for
people where I went out and said, "Hey,
I'm working with X,
and he needs somebody to manage his
online presence and reputation, and I'm
and I'm and I'm doing that for him."
And it says, "Okay."
And after about three prompts, it says,
"So, would you like me to create an
interactive dashboard that tracks all of
the things they say and do online?"
And I always say, "No."
[laughter]
But that's that's how it takes
literally 10 minutes to for anybody in
the world to say, "I want to know
everything about everything that anybody
that they know of that they have a name
for has done.
And that's just and that's just
starting.
We're not even close to the
capability yet.
Sufficient political will to legislate
new civil rights. I think you saw that
the last 2 days.
Individual control over digital ID data
and context. That is
what we need is legislation that gives
us back control over our internet
presence.
Duty of data loyalty is probably the
most significant legislative initiative
that we can put in place to enable
control over
over our digital ID presence online.
We can't do it with anything less. It
inverts the liability equation. And for
those of you who don't understand the
difference between
Consumer harm legislation and fiduciary
consumer harm legislation and fiduciary
law,
the standard of proof is different. If
if I have consumer protection,
I can't
punish the person abusing me unless I
can show harm. The standard of harm is
pretty hard high. And it's pretty hard
to show harm in a diffuse
internet online where your data gets
spread out all over the place and you
can't point to somebody and say, "You
harmed me." They go, "No, no, no, I gave
the data to this person. They gave it to
that person." And then you can't show
harm.
But fiduciary duty of loyalty says,
"If the fiduciary
is self-dealing,
then you can punish them because your
interests have to come before the
fiduciary's interests." That means
everybody that collects any data about
you online in Utah now has to
understand that if they self-deal,
if they benefit from your data and you
don't,
you can go after them.
That has never happened before. That is
the way place where it has to be.
So, that's the stickiness factor cuz
that's now in law.
And that stickiness, that's the context.
And then the last one, the inevitability
of KERI. You have to have true
believers who are going to fight through
the fights, who are going to go to the
go to the meetings and put up the put up
with the arguments and make the
case. And I think we have cadre of
people that are willing to do that. So,
people that are willing to do that. So
And the thing is, we have a severely
constrained solution trade space.
And what I mean by that is, I spent
years
doing the trades. What can we do to
solve these problems? What tools do we
have available? And everything every
time I go, "Well, I could do this, but
wait, if I do that, then
here's the tradeoffs, and I don't
like those tradeoffs. And I do that,
here's the tradeoffs. I don't like that
those tradeoffs." And once you do the
tradeoffs, you realize that there's only
a very small
space for a solution, which means, as
far in my opinion, if it's not KERI,
it's going to be something that looks,
smells, walks, and quacks like KERI.
They just changed the name.
Because the under the hood, there just
isn't any other solutions. We have to
you know, we cryptography only gives us
a handful of things that we can use.
And so and so that means that
the timing is right. So, anyway
Persistent problem cascade that
continually exhaust anything less
capable.
It's just every time you look at some
other system, you look at DNSSEC, you
look at OAuth, OIDC, you look at these
systems,
and they keep failing for the same
reasons.
And so,
people are starting to recognize that.
So, what does that mean?
That it's a matter of when, not if. If
it's not this year, it's next year. If
it's not next year, it's the following
year.
Because none of this is going away.
I'm going to predict that before the end
of 2027,
KERI adoption will reach its tipping
point.
[applause]
All right.
So,
the journey begins. So, what I wanted to
do on this first ever conference
is give a brief history of how we got
here.
You know, sort of like the foundations.
I think most of you have been there
through most of the journey.
But, I know there's some people that
haven't been, and this talk, you
know, will be made available online for
other people. So, I thought this would
be a good opportunity to sort of
talk about, you know, where it came
from.
So, I started down this path
back in 2013, 2014. I wrote a protocol
called RAET.
It's reliable asynchronous event
transport. It is a
end-to-end, peer-to-peer,
encrypted, signed, and it was used in
production at scale, and it was open
source.
So, this was years before most of you
have even heard of Signal. Back when
Signal wasn't called Signal, it was
called Whisper.
But, it was the start of that. So, what
was the lesson learned?
Well, I could solve all the problems but
key management with RAET.
[laughter]
So, so I said, "Okay, that's not a
solvable that's not a solved problem."
So, so, I already knew that
there was a big problem that had to be
solved sometime.
OpenReputation,
I wrote a white paper.
It started using self-certifying
identifiers.
It had the concept of identity ledger
it had the concept of identity ledger
and identity graph.
It defined reputation as a modulator for
it defined reputation as a modulator for
trust for online interactions.
And it
brought up the idea that we wanted to
have individual control over the context
in which we interact online.
Our internet presence.
And lesson learned from that is that I
needed persistent identity. I can't have
a good reputation without a persistent
identity, and that's the hard problem of
identity because nobody had a solution
for it back then.
Identity System Essentials, this
white paper. This is the first draft.
Introduced cryptonyms, built on the
skid model. It provided a formal
identity model, primary secondary IDs.
Talked about identifier management
with HD key chains, three degrees of
privacy, and it introduced the concept
of self-sovereignty for identity. And
lots of people This The draft paper was
shared in the community, and lots of
people amplified and built on the
concept of SSI, but as far as I know,
that was the first And I And I stole it
from Phil cuz Phil Windley had
written some blog posts on
self-sovereign data, and I said, "Well,
we don't just want data to be
self-sovereign. We want our identity to
be self-sovereign." So, So, that was
back in 2016.
The lesson I learned there, there's a
hard trade space. If you want to trade
off security and privacy and
self-sovereignty and control,
you're making some pretty hard trades.
Sovrin Foundation
that really changed the environment
for decentralized identity.
The idea was there's going to be one
ledger for digital identity.
One ledger to rule them all.
And it had persistent identifiers.
It had prophylactic key rotation, not
recoverable key rotation. That
would wait that was going to
come a while later, but it built on
but it established the foundation of
managing your key state
so that you'd have persistent ident-
identity.
Hard problem, shared governance.
That was a hard problem.
Spent a lot of time trying to solve that
problem.
2017, the ledger wars.
Okay, a lot of you fought in those wars,
right? What happened is
SSI was such a great concept
that everybody wanted it. Every ledger
wanted to have their own SSI
Identity.
So there was every time somebody would
have an application
that they wanted
decentralized identifier,
the very next thing was, "Okay, which
ledger are we going to put it on?"
And so all the all the people for all
the ledgers would come to the table and
say, "No, my ledger. No, my ledger."
Right? And that's what it looked like
for several years.
And then
GDPR came out in 2018 and that made it
difficult to have identity on a ledger.
So the whole idea of persistent identity
using a ledger is a problem for GDPR.
And so
the ledger wars, so
the insight was that blockchain is too
centralized
for truly portable identity.
That was a really hard lesson to learn.
It took several years of fighting the
ledger wars to realize that.
So,
you know, the way of KERI
Really the first paper that sort of
really the first paper that sort of
opened the path was this one in 2018.
The three R's of key management and one
of those R's
is rotation and this is where I
defined the concept of pre-rotation. So,
it's in that paper.
It says, "How are we going to do key
rotation?
If we do it the normal way,
If we do it the normal way
Where we use our signing key to rotate
where we use our signing key to rotate
to a new signing key, if our signing key
is compromised,
then we lose control of our identity and
that's all of blockchain, by the way.
Right? And that's all of blockchain
identity. If you lose control of your
signing key, you lose control of your
identity. So, that's
that's kind of a problem.
The other approach is
have a rotation key that you use to
rotate your signing key.
But then what happens if your rotation
key gets compromised?
Well, then you have another rotation key
to rotate the rotation key that rotates
the signing key. And I had several
cryptographers says that's best
practices. Well, what happens when that
one says two is usually enough. You only
need two rotation keys. They'll never
they'll never get there.
Good idea, but
that may maybe we could do better. So,
pre-rotation is one-time use only
rotation keys.
You rotate your rotation key every time
you rotate your signing keys.
So, pre-rotation
and then that also introduced the idea
of having a key a log of your key
state.
Didn't call it a KERI event because
they hadn't coined the term KERI, so it
couldn't be a KERI event log, but it
would or you know,
KERI Key Event Log, but it was a log.
Had multisig individual source and
provenance data.
So, the idea is make key management
so, the idea is make key management
fault tolerant. So, I started down that
path.
In 2018, a little bit later,
paper called A DID for everything.
It introduced the idea of verifiable
provenanced graphs of cryptographically
chained data.
So, that's the core idea that is now in
the ACDC standard.
Yeah.
yeah.
In 2019, KERI version one white paper.
in 2019, KERI version one white paper.
So, based on those, I said, "Okay, let's
see if we can figure out a way to do it
without a blockchain."
And the idea is that you have a
cryptographically verifiable append-only
event log for each identifier. So,
there's no shared governance.
You get rid of shared governance, you
get rid of the ledger wars.
Introduced CESR,
key rotation, witnesses, deconstructed
blockchain.
It solves the hard problem of cross
trust domain transfer.
Lesson learned,
we don't need a blockchain.
And I spent a couple of years arguing
with people that said, "No, no, you have
to have a blockchain. You can't do it
with a Key Event Log (KEL)."
But now I hardly ever have anybody
tell me that you need a blockchain for
identity. Does anybody Is anybody
arguing that still in the room?
You don't have to raise your hand.
[laughter]
So, after So, I took that paper on
the road. I went to IIIW several
conferences, shared with everybody that
I knew. Tell me what I'm doing wrong.
Got lots of really good valuable
feedback. There's a list of
of acknowledgements in the back of
the KERI V2 white paper because there
were some really significant
meaningful enhancements that came from
that. One of those is the watcher
network,
CESR streaming, hierarchical
CESR streaming hierarchical
delegation, layer threshold
structures
in more detail.
But, basically it solved all the hard
problems of key management and so it
was ready to go and that was 2020.
And then the same year like
While we were still refining
the version two white paper came
across the idea of quantum secure DIDs.
I co-wrote a white paper white paper on
this.
Using hashes to protect the
pre-rotated keys means that we've
pre-migrated along with the cryptography
agility. So, so we're already
have a story for post quantum secure
and Daniel and I and Daniel did most
of the work co-wrote a recent paper
about the post quantum
position for KERI. So, if you're not
familiar with that, go read that
white paper. And
Dan, you can maybe do a reference for
it.
2020,
GLEIF
got religion. They said, this
works. We don't like the ledger wars. I
think that was your main motivation,
right, Karla? Yes. The ledger wars. They
didn't want to fight those anymore.
So lasting peace from the ledger wars.
so lasting peace from the ledger wars.
Important insight. It solves
important insight. It solves
organizational ID. Organizational
identity is a new concept. Came from
that because now you have a
organizational root of trust. It's a
bootstrap for any organizational ID
problem.
And now people in this room are starting
to get that. I wrote a white paper
universal identifier theory just to
extend the identity model, unified model
for identifiers, bootstrap trust, be a
reputation by reference, multi-valued
key management, starting to talk about
how we build infrastructure at scale.
So that went into more detail.
so that went into more detail.
And then in 2020 we formed a
task force at Trust over IP to start
standardizing this stuff and the and
ACDC
became a thing,
At that point.
So, authentic chain data containers, and
so, authentic chain data containers, and
I think,
We'll talk a lot about those in the
next 2 days.
And then 2022, GLEIF vLEI in production.
and then 2022, GLEIF vLEI in production.
I won't go into
most of you are familiar with that.
So, now where we're at? Well,
So, now where we're at? Well
we needed there was a story
We needed there was a story
missing in KERI. KERI is about
authentication, proving that you control
an identifier.
But, there's more to the story
and had lots of conversations about how
do you deal with privacy and
confidentiality,
and
wrote the white paper, the spec white
paper, which is now a task force
within Trust over IP working group
at ToIP, and it's like draft version
three or something,
To solve,
you know protected communications
online.
So, it uses a,
so, it uses a,
It uses a three-layer tunnel,
It uses a three-layer tunnel
And the idea is that if I have
and the idea is that if I have
layered confidential contexts,
then I can solve
surveillance and privacy using layered
confidential contexts. And so, that's
the that's the basic idea. And what
I mean by it's exploitation, stupid,
what I'm saying is that the real
question is, how do we protect people
from being exploited, not how do we help
people hide better. Hiding is not a very
fun place to be. If you've ever tried to
really hide,
you don't have a life.
I know people that live off grid. They
don't have a life.
You want to be able to live with a life
and not be exploited, and that means
having control over the context of your
data, not_not having a context, right?
That's the main difference.
Do you have a context that you control,
that you share data with then, or do you
not have any context?
Right? And most of the community
says, "Don't have any context." And
that doesn't work very long
because
you live longer than a week, and you can
maybe have no context for a week or a
month or 3 months, but you're going
to run out of out of places to hide
after a while.
And so, you need
need a fortress that you can hide in.
You need multiple fortresses you can
hide in and have context.
So, 2023, Utah State Senate work begins.
Wrote a white paper called Sustainable
Privacy, talks more at length about the
regulatory things.
Due to
Due to data Due to loyalty
is in there.
The idea is you need a comprehensive
approach. Technology by itself won't
solve the problem. You've got to do it
the And so, that meant as a
technologist, spending a lot of time in
the room with
regulators and politicians,
which, you know, were not my favorite
people, but now they become my favorite
people. I'm looking for Chris Bramwell,
but I don't see him.
He's late today.
ToIP, we got our own working group,
which helped speed along the things. We
had some
Cardano Foundation made a big investment
in open-source software.
Utah State started passing legislation.
KERI Foundation we established last
year.
And the
Well, I Yeah.
No, that was that's wrong. That's
2024 12 02. So, it's in just the end of
2024, but it's really last year. To
try to foster
KERI throughout the world get adoption.
And then we're back We're now at
2026.
And we already did what happened in
2026. So, that's the history in terms of
And you know what? I left a whole
lot of stuff off. There's been a huge
amount of work by people in this
community pushing KERI along. But the
core ideas, where they came from, and
then
you know, the milestones that got us to
where we are, I put on there.
So, what's the mission of the KERI
Foundation? Our mission is to foster
open infrastructure.
What does that mean?
It's the I in KERI. I had somebody ask
me, "Why Is that a typo? You made
the I in KERI red." I said, "No, I'm
trying to emphasize that I stands for
infrastructure."
KERI doesn't exist without
infrastructure. It's not a system that
works without infrastructure. And if you
don't have infrastructure, people can't
adopt it. They can't practically use it
because nobody wants to build their own
infrastructure.
So,
KERI is a decentralized key management
infrastructure.
Right? It's It was designed to be web
scalable
so that we get an ultra low cost floor.
Right? That's why blockchain ledgers
weren't weren't
you know, were a problem.
The idea is
and I spent time working for I spent
time working in the
blockchain world. I think there was
somebody here from the Wyoming
delegation yesterday that used to work
for Consensus Networks when I worked for him.
But he had a beard and you know, had a
different lifestyle. He was all
clean-shaven and had a suit on and I
didn't recognize him and he said, "No,
it's me, really. We work together." And
I go, "Oh."
You know, it took me a minute. But,
and
But, the idea is tokenomics. You build
incentives into the governance structure
so that people work together to build to
to make your infrastructure alive.
Another word term for that is a
cooperative model. You can be in
competition. You can make money.
Everybody's making money.
But, they're helping everybody else out
to build the infrastructure that makes
it all possible for everybody. And
that's the idea.
So, we want to incentivize multiple
vendors.
No single vendor lock-in. We don't want
that. That's bad for KERI.
If you think about it,
if you have pre-rotated private keys,
you can and we have this in the code
in the in the Keeper, you can
reconstruct
all of your keys if you're using HD
keychain from any copy of your KEL
because the HD path is in the KEL. It's
the sequence number and the offset into
the into the key list. You don't need
any other information. You actually
don't have to worry about losing
all of your information
as long as one copy of one legitimate
valid copy of a KEL exists somewhere in
the world, you could reconstitute
it.
We don't want wallet vendor lock-in.
We want multiple wallets. So, we now
have several wallets that are now open
source and we're going to demo
open source stuff. So, the KERI
Foundation team, like they've they've
only been doing this since January, but
so you know, you can ask them whether
whether it was hurting their brain to
try to learn KERI in 3 months, but you
know
Some of them had a had a head start.
But
but
so we've added another wallet. We've
got a mobile wallet.
You'll see some talks today about
you'll see some talks today about
People that are building wallets and
and infrastructure for KERI so that
we have multiple vendors because
adoption requires multiple vendors. No
no big adoption wants to have a
single source of the technology. They
want to see they want to see multiple
vendors.
We have in KERI the concept of non-
we have in KERI the concept of non-
non-cooperative key custodianship.
You can have key custodians that
are custodians of your signing keys.
They can have the keys.
And they can go away. They can hate you.
They can lose them. And you can still
reconstitute control over your
identifier
because you just have to retain your
pre-rotated private keys.
And so the major friction
of people managing their keys and
managing their signing infrastructure,
you can
rent out.
But you're not locked in because at any
moment in time you can pull your
pre-rotated keys out of
air gap cold storage, publish your
rotation,
sign IR to your custodian.
And I think there have been
lots of money lost in the blockchain
world from
key custodians who have What do they
say? Not your keys,
not your coin. Not true in KERI. Not
your keys, still your identity.
Not steal, still.
[laughter]
Users benefit from witness pools that
have no common mode failure sources. So
if your witnesses all come from the same
vendor, the vendor is a common mode
failure source. So, you really want to
tell your customers,
you know, have it have witnesses
supported by multiple vendors.
The watcher network, every watcher
that wants that is an honest watcher
benefits from other watchers sharing
what they see in duplicity. So, so
there's a huge incentive for watchers to
cooperate.
So, so what we're doing for what we're
calling open infrastructure
is the five Ws
or one click KERI. The idea is people
would come and say, "Okay, I want to use
KERI. How do I do that?" Well,
KERI. How do I do that?" Well
Come to some meetings,
come to some meetings,
go read these repos, go do this, build a
bunch of infrastructure, then you can
use KERI. Right? I'm sure I see
some people in here that have
walked that path, right? That's not a
really good story for adoption. So, the
idea is
we want to be able to tell somebody one
click,
it'll install KERI infrastructure for
you. You got a wallet, you got
witnesses, watchers, and now you can
start to build stuff with it. So, that's
the goal. So, the five Ws,
wallet,
witness,
watcher,
web,
so it's all on the web,
and wizard. And what wizard is the
catch-all term. We want user interfaces
that hide the complexity of key
management from the users.
And KERI gives you the ability to do
that. I mentioned some things that KERI
has built in that allow you to do that.
People building user interfaces need to
understand those so they can build user
interfaces to take advantage that. The
other wizard is agents.
You want You want interfaces to a agentic
AI, and you want to control those
interfaces, you want to use KERI to do
it.
So, this is what KERI infrastructure
looks like.
We've got a wallet on one side. Whoops,
go back.
And now I got to go Yeah, got to go
through those. Sorry.
So, we have entity A has a wallet.
Entity B has a wallet.
Entity A has their witnesses they
control. They have watchers they
control. Entity B has witnesses they
control, watchers they control. There's
a shared watcher network. And now entity
A and entity B
can communicate
authentically.
But, they can't do it without
the watcher network and the witnesses.
Now I can move on.
This is
early screenshots from
Mobile wallet that
that we've that we've that you'll see
demos today. So, you'll If you look at
the sessions, KERI Foundation team is
doing demos of the KERI stuff.
healthKERI had developed
HealthKERI had developed
Locksmith wallet
Watcher watchers and witnesses
watcher watchers and witnesses
for their proprietary products. And
earlier this year, they donated those to
the KERI Foundation and allowed us to
debrand them and rebrand them so that
everybody that wants to build can build
on proven production quality
infrastructure. And we're hosting those
repos and we have spun up we're we'll
we'll be providing some
some
witness and watcher networks on our own
servers so that people that want to test
it out can test it out running in the
cloud. So, that's that's one of the big
things that we're doing for the
community and
and I hope that makes a difference.
[applause]
There's two other pieces of
infrastructure
that are new
That we're building this year.
Registrar and Observer. And the reason
these are important is that
they are how we do this concept what I
call
control over context.
So, I have issuances like SEDI
issuances.
They're ACDCs
and you have a registrar
and registries for like revocation.
And you have observers they get bulk
updates. The key here is the bulk
update. Bulk update means that the
observer
and the issuer
can't correlate back to the point of
validation
because that's the point of use the
observer sees it
but a change in state by the issuer
can't be correlated forward because of
the bulk update and the observer's
not allowed and doesn't need
to communicate to the issuer because
they get a an update of all the
information that they need to do
verification. So, so the verification
happens at the observer and the
and the observer
And observers can't collude
between each others if you're using
bulk issued credentials. So, we'll talk
more detail about that.
So, this enables bulk issuance. It takes
advantage of sparse Merkle trees.
And so, that's some new
infrastructure. Another new
Use case, and these are in the spec.
These are in the ACDC spec, are things
called a user presentation registry.
So, one of the challenges
in verifiable credential world is that
if I have a proof
that a holder has that they that they're
the subject or the holder of a
credential,
and that proof gets stolen, and they
steal the user's keys, then that user
can be impersonated, and they can
present that credential, and the user
can't know that's happening or
doesn't have any way to know it. But, we
can use the same Whoops.
Go back.
We can use the same
registrar mechanism
so that a user in the ACDC, when they
get it issued, can
designate
that they their own registry
Is going to is going to keep track of
blinded presentations.
And that means that a verifier won't be
able to verify the presentation unless
the presentation itself is anchored
in the in the registry. And this is all
blinded so that it's not correlatable
presentation to presentation. But, that
means that
that issuees or users
that want to be ultra secure
can have fault-tolerant detection of
compromise of their keys with regard to
their own credentials. And they'll
know, just like
you know that your keys for your KEL
been compromised because you can watch
your own witnesses. You can watch your
own registry to see that somebody else
is presenting your credentials
and you didn't do it. And so now
now you can take
recovery action.
So, what is KERI really? Right?
Well, you've heard the phrase Keys at
the Edge.
Security First, Always.
Anybody who's come to the user the
Minimally Sufficient Means. These are
mottos, phrases, Signed Everything. Sort
of ways to look at the elephant from the
multiple blind men.
Right? So, all of these are features of
KERI, but if you only
thought of it as any one of these,
it wouldn't be KERI.
And lots of people have copied parts of
KERI,
but they've but not all of KERI. And if
you don't have all of KERI,
I guarantee you there are
vulnerabilities that you'll be
exposed to.
So,
heard a lot about that yesterday.
So, no more half measures, guys. It's
It's all KERI or no KERI.
[laughter]
All right? So, what So, KERI is
truly an identity revolution. There are
concepts in KERI that don't exist
anywhere else in the world in identity.
And I'm going to give you a short I
love creating acronyms because
I'm old and if I don't have a mnemonic,
I won't remember what I thought of
yesterday. So, this is how I remember
what I think from day to day.
Reputable Autonomic Pseudonymity. That
That encapsulates KERI in the smallest
set of words. Right? An identifier's
a pseudonym.
Is an autonomic pseudonym. What does
autonomic mean? Well, all of the
features of true individual control
over you know autonomic means self
governing individual control over your
identifier that's secure that's
persistent that's perpetual all of those
things right and reputable
means it doesn't go away.
There's something to stick to a
reputation isn't good unless it sticks
to something it has to stick to an
identity right? And then the other
mnemonic Control over Confidential
Context in which you use your identity.
You want to control the context that you
use the identity and that means that you
want the context to be confidential. Now
in the dictionary there are 20
definitions of the word privacy
or private.
About a third of them are synonymous
with confidential.
So when I say I'm sharing a secret with
you and I say it's just private between
us right?
That's not private that's confidential
right?
Because there's other meanings of the
word private that don't mean that.
The core private word means
intimate means only you know it.
Right? So a private key is never shared.
A shared secret isn't private.
Shared data over the internet is never
private in that meaning of the word
private but it could be confidential.
You could make the information
confidential.
So if you're going to interact with
people you want to interact in
confidential context and so you want to
make those contacts you want to have
control over that confidentiality. That
means control over what you disclose
control over what they do with it once
you disclose it to them.
So
So here's the thing RAP-C3
and if you say it really fast
it's a rhapsody and that's KERI.
That's it.
And we have a minute for questions.
Yes. I think it'd be useful to explain
the difference between watchers and
observers.
So, watchers watch
the KEL. That's all they watch. They're
looking for duplicity in your KEL.
Observers are watching the state of
issuances that are anchored to the KEL.
So, KEL?
Via the TEL. Yeah.
So, it's a TEL observer. Yeah.
Yeah.
Why do they need to be separated?
Well
they're they have different purposes.
So, separation of concerns means you
design protocols so that everything has
Yes, it's layered. So, it's a layer,
right?
They depend on watchers,
but they aren't watchers.
Any more que-
I guess I guess we're out of time.
No, one more?
Four more minutes. Okay, I guess we
we started a little bit late. More
questions?
Please be gentle. I'm Moises.
Be gentle. I'm a newbie at KERI. So,
be gentle. I'm a newbie at KERI. So,
watchers witnesses. You are You
mentioned the term
KEL or TEL. Key event log.
No, TEL. But TEL is transaction event
log. So, but
since there's an exchange of two parties
of information and keys,
how do the watchers attach to
confidential a confidential transaction?
Well, watchers aren't part of a
confidential transaction. Your key event
log is public.
You're publishing your key state so
everybody can verify
Any attestation or assertion you make
Relative to an identifier. And to do
that, you sign the
You sign things, and you have to verify
the signatures, so you need to know the
public key to verify the signature. So,
the Key Event Log publishes your
public key and then the witnesses and
the watchers, the witnesses make the
public key state highly available and
also give you a detection mechanism.
And if you were you at the SEDI
summit?
No. Oh, okay. So, one of the things that
happens is that you want to be able
to detect that your keys have been
compromised. So, the witnesses are a
detection mechanism. Because if somebody
wants to publish something on your KEL,
they have to get your witnesses to
witness it, which means you get to see
it because what the witnesses witness is
public. And so, you can see that
somebody's compromised your keys in
order to publish to the witnesses. And
then the watchers are watching the
witnesses to make sure that the
witnesses don't cheat.
So, where is it published if not
in ledger?
W- Well, a KEL is a ledger. It is a
micro ledger controlled by one
identifier. So, it's not a shared ledger.
It's not a shared ledger. It's a
non-shared ledger. But, technically
under the hood, it is a it is a
blockchain. Yeah.
But, how is it made public? I guess
that's my point.
I probably can't answer that in this
room. Okay.
But, if you're here for the conference,
you got 2 days of people who'll answer
that for you.
With that open-source infrastructure
Okay.
Yes, that's right.
Okay, thank you. One more Yes. Yes.
Maybe you'll answer this later, but
witnesses are selected by the
controller.
controller, and then the watchers are
selected by the verifiers. So, what's
your vision of how a controller actually
selects a witness?
Usually they will hire They'll either
If they're technically savvy, they'll
spin up their own witness, but most
people won't do that. They will just
rent witnesses from witness services,
just like you would rent
a cloud host for your website.
Okay, well, do you ever see individuals
being
Or employees being controllers, and
would they have to go hire someone?
the vLEI, if your work for company
has a vLEI and you get issued, you know,
an ECR and OR credential, you'll have a
wallet and you'll you'll select
you'll select witnesses that you
probably your company spins up for their
employees to use.
Okay, and then at the individual level,
do you ever see grandma having to go
select a witness?
And so, one of the things would one of
the things the discussion that we've had
with the state of Utah is how do you pay
for disadvantaged populations to have
infrastructure?
And so, so there would be that would be
an entitlement that somebody would
pay for your infrastructure. But, it's
going to be the cheapest form of
infrastructure, which is web
infrastructure, not really expensive
blockchain infrastructure.
Okay, yeah, I'm curious to know more
about the transactional friction
there or the just the friction
there.
a really good conversation to have
because
another conversation.
Yeah.
So, a real quick one on the registrar
observer network, do you see benefit for
the registrar putting or putting random
noise into the stream so that they can't
tell it's a correlatable event on a
revocation? Absolutely. The blinded
state TEL, which is the thing
that we use, not the current
version one is does not have that,
allows you to do updates because they're
blinded that don't change the state,
they're just there to introduce
to whiten the signal. So, you can as a
registrar, you can whiten your signal.
You can you can issue random updates to
to registries that don't change the
state. And so, that means that a state
update doesn't necessarily mean the
state changed. It just means you did a
state update and most of them are and so
you could create
you could roll out 4 million
registries for birth certificates
and update them. And then when
somebody's born, the fact that there's
an update to a registry doesn't
correlate to the fact that they were
born and you then started using that
registry for their for their birth
certificate.
Thank you very much, Sam.
Time's out. Running out.
Do you want to introduce the next
speaker?
Yes,
that's Daniel.
Do I need to I need to get to move my
Please a big hand for Sam.
[applause]