Hi everybody. This is KRAM It! with Ari.
Important exclamation mark
placement there.
So
so
KRAM is KERI request
authentication mechanism
and this is for all non KEL
events or non-key event messages
that occur in the KERI protocol and
some examples include encrypt sender
sign receiver which if you were at
Phil's [talk] you'd know is a good way of doing
Phil's you'd know is a good way of doing
Secure APIs to a given identifier
essentially a replacement for
shared secretbased account management.
You can do exchange
transactions for negotiating
contracts or other negotiations. You can
do credential presentations. And
so the fundamental problem that KRAM
solves is ensuring that a message is
timely and authentic.
So without KRAM, an attacker can
intercept a valid signed message and
then replay that message at a later time
and you could have a or the
receiver of that message would have no
way of distinguishing it from a fresh
one which could cause all kinds of
problems with you know like if you
were signing on to an account or
something you could have someone who is
able to sign on for you. So the so
KRAM works by enforcing a timeliness
cache window.
Each message includes a datetime stamp
and the receiver is going to check
whether that time stamp falls within an
acceptable window relative to its own
clock. If the message has been seen
before, if it falls outside the window,
it's just going to get dropped.
So KRAM exists at the top of the message
processing pipeline. All of the
non-key event message flow through a
non-key event messages flow through a
single method and KRAM is applied
immediately after some basic allow deny
logic if in case you want to filter for
given identifiers right in case you want
to not let specific people in. And I
should note here that KRAM is designed
for KERI v2 which is not out yet.
But it represents a change from a prior
but it represents a change from a prior
approach wherein before we would escrow
messages u when authentication
information wasn't immediately available
like if we didn't have the Key Event Log
whereas now we just drop them and notify
such that the Key Event Log can be
retrieved via something that is out
of scope for this talk.
So before diving into KRAM's
mechanics I just want to make sure that
everybody is familiar or largely
familiar with these few with these
few key terminology points. Does anyone
have any questions about KERI? Well,
okay. Questions about KERI might be a
little broad, but we all know what AIDs
are,
kels,
key state, we've talked a lot about it
today. Said is maybe worth touching on,
which is the self-addressing
identifiers, which are digests computed
over the contents of a data structure.
And basically, this is an ID for a given
message or in this instance, it is or
referencing it as an ID for a given
message. So that it's a context
identifier based on your payload.
Yeah. Yeah, that's that seems
correct.
It's actually the whole message,
right? It's a digest of the message.
It's a digest of the message,
but it's embedded in the message
protocol. So that there's one universal
identifier for that message.
So it's unique per message even in the
thread.
Yeah.
Yes. Could you repeat the
conclusion of this because you are the
only one with a microphone then we going
Oh yes. So basically
we have saids as unique identifiers
which are digests of a given message
such that no two messages that are the
same would have different sets. I.e. If
a me if two messages have the same set
then they must have identical contents
and time stamps. So then seals
briefly is a cryptographic commitment
which can anchor arbitrary data to a
tree of hashes or to a particular
event in the key event sequence. And
we're assuming with KRAM that the
receiver will already hold the copy of
the sender's KEL. Which is again
kind of gesturing towards that fact that
that retrieval mechanism is out of scope
but it does exist or will exist.
So in KRAM we have three authentication
types. We have an anchoring seal
reference which is a message that's
au authenticated via a seal in the
sender's KEL. And this works because
you can preemptively authenticate your
messages as a sender by digesting
them into a seal with the
authentications already
created and then adding that to your
keel you know and then continuing
your Key Event Log. I think this would
be done via an interaction event and
then other people can just look up that
seal and confirm that is a
pre-authenticated message. We have
single key signature which is just one
key in the key list. I should mention
that let's see
when we are determining this type of
authentication we're looking at key list
cardality.
So sometimes an identifier will have
multiple signing keys but it won't be a
multi key signature and for the purposes
in eventually that matters. It is
covered in KRAM because KRAM does
authenticate but what we're doing here
really what but why we're breaking these
things out is because oh did I no
it's still good because we're trying to
do amplification and DOS mitigation.
So, it's important to do the cheapest
method of dropping messages before we
get into the more expensive
authenticationbased
methods of dropping messages.
So, first we would
first we're going to look at the key
list cardality. We're going to say is it
a single signature? Is it a multi key
signature? Does it have a seal
reference? And then if it's multi key
and it has a seal reference, we're going
to try and look at that seal reference
first before we go on to see if that
multikey has some has some validity
to it, if it has signatures that are
valid and validating those.
All right. So we'll talk briefly about
multisig. You guys have probably heard
it all already today. But this is
when multiple signing keys are required
to authorize an action. These would be
distributed signing keys. In
practice, that's when a multi-IG group
sends a message and not all the
signatures may be attached at once. The
different members of the group may sign
at different times and from different
devices. The receiver needs to
collect those signatures
needs to collect those signatures
sorry
incrementally until we meet a threshold
which will validate that message if
it if the message is able to collect all
those signatures.
So this is where we have different
KRAM windows. KRAM uses a long lag
window for multi key signatures wherein
As opposed to a short lag window for
single keys and seal reference
messages. The long lag might be minutes,
might be hours or days whatever is
appropriate for the operational tempo of
the multisig group and the short lag
only accounts for network latency and
initial processing times. This is that
window that I was mentioning earlier.
It's going to be different depending on
the authentication mechanism that we
kind of sus out in the beginning of the
KRAM It method which is why this is
called KRAM It with re
so
let's see
further
let's talk about what a replay attack is
I mentioned this already but I wanted
to go through it again just so that we
can
Create some context for the next
things that we're going to be talking
about. So, replay attacks are
fundamental threats in any authenticated
messaging system. The concept is that
an attacker will intercept a message
that was legitimately created and signed
and then is able to resend that
replaying it to the receiver at a
later time. If the receiver has no
mechanism to detect that the message is
a duplicate, it may process it again as
if it were fresh. And depending on
the message type, this could grant
unauthorized access, trigle trigger
duplicate operations, or otherwise
cause harm. So, it's important to note
that the attacker doesn't need to forge
or modify anything in the case of a
replay attack. The message is
genuinely signed by the real sender and
the attacker can exploit this the
fact that message has a valid
signature on it. But that doesn't
mean that the message is provably
delivered right now.
So that's this is why timeliness is a
core mechanic for KRAM. A message could
be properly signed but it must also
fall within the timeliness window that
Is able to correctly filter out
any messages that may also that may
be sent by malicious bad actors
in current use protocols. How is that
mitigated?
Or other examples.
or other examples.
I don't know. I've only studied
KERI so I couldn't tell you how OOTH 2
does it
approach in most secure channel
is it a non
by TLS is you do a challenge response.
So it's you three messages. So you send
a request, the host sends you back a
nonce, you sign the nonce or encrypt the
nonce, send it back and then they decrypt
it or verify the signature and that
knots is basically
not replayable as long as they don't
ever generate the same knots and accept
it. That means they either they either
assume an ephemeral secure session so
they don't have to save the nonce but if
you want something like multi-IG that
has that can span multiple sessions then
your host because now you have to store
all those nonses forever get replayed.
So, so, so when you look at replay
attack protection, when you go away from
ephemeral interactions to things that
have to last for long periods of time,
most of the existing mechanisms just
don't work. They just they don't they
don't scale. You have to remember things
forever or you have to start to build
prable caches.
Statistically random with large
Yeah,
that makes sense actually.
Okay.
to summarize
to summarize other authentication
mechanisms like OOTH to do multi-
message authentication via nonses which
are not scalable as such. Okay.
all right.
Now,
talk about some fundamental protections
of KRAM.
So, the first thing that we're going to
do when well, we're we're we're ordering
these by the cheapest means of
making sure that your message is
authenticated per the given point in the
in the protection that you're at. So the
first thing that we want to do is we
want to look up the look up this
message. Like we said, it's got a set on
it which is unique. So we're looking it
up against a cache. And if that message
is there in that cache already, then we
know it's a duplicate because no message
can have the same set as a message
that's already existed. So you know
you've got something funny going on if
you're or well it could it could be
it could not be something funny. It
could also just be someone who's
legitimately trying to send a message
again. But the point being that the
first thing we do cache lookup cache
lookup and drop if it's if we already
have something there. We are also
checking to see if these are multikey
messages because we can have a message
that has the same said but has
additional signatures that must be
collected towards a threshold. So there
is a little bit of nuance with respects
to multi key or multi yeah mult multi
key messages.
Next you're going to do a timeliness
check which only occurs for uncashed
messages. And you're going to do this
nice little formula here. This is this
is the real magic behind KRAM or at
least some of it which is a receiver
date time minus drift minus ML which is
going to be sort of a this is like a
v this is a variable like this could be
different depending on whether you have
a multi key it might be a longer lag or
whether you have a zip wherein you're
going to be waiting for an even longer
time to do different negotiations. of
contracts or multiple messages within
within a given very long time window.
So right do you see here ML equals SL IE
so right do you see here ML equals SL IE
we're doing for seal reference and
single key we swap this out for a short
lag long lag for multi key etc.
Next you're going to try to
authenticate. you're going to resolve
the O seal type by checking the seal
reference first because it's cheap and
then you're going to go on to signatures
and with single key you just have to
validate cache and accept. Multi key.
Again, you're going to verify the
available signatures and then you're
going to take a look at that threshold
And see if it's met at that point.
And if not, then you're going to
you're going to well, you're basically
just collecting those and waiting for
more messages to come in until that
threshold is met. It's important to
note that the prune windows always
must be greater than the accept windows
which is going to prevent gap attacks
during configuration changes. And again
we're doing yes
the window is a measure of timing.
Yeah it's it's like it's a sliding
window. So a given window will be an
offset in one direction and another.
Right. So like if it's what time is it?
Three. or something else.
Say that last part again.
Is the expectation that it's wall
clock time or something else like tick
counts?
It's going to be wall clock time,
right? Network time.
Network time.
Yes. So
so is there a dependency to have secure
time?
Yes. Well, no. Okay.
No.
No. No.
What's secure? What do you mean secure
time?
Is always relative to the host. So it
doesn't matter what an attacker
does. If they don't if they're not
synchronized with the host time, they
can't lie about the time, right? And
and if the host records the timing, they
can't do a clock reprate attack on
it. So that when they spin back up, you
know, they can't like push the time
back, you know. So time, but the
security is the
the host the host itself. And the
assumption is the attack
Yeah.
So to be clear,
I know what you mean by security
but those
answer server that tells.
Yeah. But in this case server you just
you are the server.
Yeah. You are the server.
Okay. So you are the server which is the
security essentially to answer your
question. Okay. That for the microphone.
Let's see. Did I miss anything on
here?
Oh, right. Key state protection.
It's good to be aware that this is for
it's good to be aware that this is for
A single given key state. And if
sender key state changes in the duration
of a given, you know, messaging
exchange, like if you're collecting
signatures on a multisig and the sender
key state changes at some point during
that, then that messaging operation
is going to have to happen again.
You
said gonna have to what?
It's gonna have to happen again.
Oh, yes.
Yes. Okay, good. Looking at me. I was
like,
I didn't hear what you said. I didn't
hear the
Thank you. Okay. Now we get to talk
about the cool stuff. So, it's all cool
stuff. I'm just kidding. These are
kind of they're not introduced by KRAM,
but having KRAM as a replay attack.
Defense introduces other modes of
defense introduces other modes of
exploitation. So we have gap replay
attack and gap first play attack.
Essentially
essentially
I'm actually going to move on to the
next slide because I have some nice
visuals here for you for a gap replay
attack. Here we have our timeliness
window. We have our message being sent.
It's accepted and cached and then the
message gets pruned. You have an old
timeliness window right here. And after
the message is sent, before it's
accepted, a bad actor is going to go and
grab that message. Right?
Next, the timeliness window expires. The
message is pruned, but then you as the
server or the receiver is going to
change your timeliness window and
increase it. So here after the message
is pruned a bad actor can replay that
message in this little vulnerable gap
right here. We're going to talk about
how we solve these with KRAM but these
are complications that are introduced
that need to be addressed.
You dynamically change
if you dynamically change windows
yes exactly. So this is when you have a
running system and you want to change
your timeliness window for a given
message type or other configuration.
So for a gap
hold on sorry this one should say gap
first play visual. This is a gap first
play attack. Basically what happens
here is you have a message sent. A bad
actor is going to intercept that
message, but it's going to come through
With the receiver of the message
never having touched it or looked at it
because it comes through after your
timeliness window.
Post that. This is a little bit
of a confusing time scale, but post that
you're going to increase your timeliness
window. And then that bad actor who's
saved that message can first play it
into your new increased timeliness
window. What's the intuition for why
they increase third time in this window?
Could be any number of reasons like
let's say you're doing a multi-IG
exchange or a mult a multisig and the
group participants are not they're
they're not getting their signatures in
on time for given messages and you say I
want to give these people a little bit
more time. You increase the window but
you also open yourself up to this
just on a network with lots of packet
loss.
Exactly. the network starts to have
congestion and now your latency.
So taper could simulate that using the
denial somewhere in the network
and then and then and then it into the
window. Okay.
Yes, that's so another to reiterate
another reason that you could
encounter this or that you could
encounter needing to change your
timeliness window is if you have a lot
of network latency. Perhaps an
attacker is dosing you or maybe you're
just scaling up and you realize that you
need more time to process. So
anyways, now we're going to talk about
how we address these. So
oh now this is the right slide. We
have three cases.
If you're decreasing a window size,
that's safe and you can apply that
immediately. If you're increasing a
window size, you need a two-step
process. And if you're changing
cache type granularity, I'll talk a
little bit about configuring cache types
in the later slides. That's more complex
and would require a worst case analysis,
but that's a little bit out of scope for
this. Anyways, the two-step
processes for increasing it is you're
essentially going to want to have a
prune lag wherein
when you do an increase, you have an
extra lag where you're not pruning
windows until you've exceeded the time
delta between your old timeliness window
and the new increased timeliness window.
And that actually covers both gap replay
attacks and gap first play attacks.
Let's see here.
Then we have a little bit about the
configuration
wherein this is designed for
incremental adoption. So not every
deployment is going to be able to run
KRAM for all messages types overnight
and the configuration system sort of
reflects this. So we have up here the
enabled true which just means your KRAM
is on. Then you have denials and
these are each keyed to KERI
version. So we have version one and
version two right here. And these are
going to be message types. And these are
going to be
these are going to be thinking on the
word for it
route. Yeah, sorry.
And the denial systems supports wild
and the denial systems supports wild
carding through empty fields. So these
one comma zero KERI version one wild
card wild card just means we're going to
deny all KERI v1 messages for KRAM
or well we're not going to use KRAM on
KERI v1 messages right and for these
it's we're not going to use KRAM on
KERI v2 messages with a pro message
type and then any route and for the
third one we're not going to be using or
we're not going to use we're not going
to feed messages through KRAM for KERI
version two reply messages with a
slashend route.
And the denial logic is applied at the
top before we even get into any of the
Message processing stuff that we
discussed earlier.
That is pretty much all I have. Well, I
was also gonna say
that
a lot of people worked on this. Sam
wrote the white paper. Several other
people from the KERI Foundation have
put a lot of effort into getting the
implementation to where it's at now. And
I know that many other people are going
to work on it before it's complete. So,
I give them a round of applause.
Does anyone have any other questions?
I run a little short.
Yes.
Where do you see this being put into
application within I mean let's just say
the healthcare
platform.
So this is going to be like for say
for example for our account
communications with ESSR they could use
this for any credential
presentations they could use this right.
So, we were talking a little or we
haven't talked about this yet, but
actually I'm going to abstain because
I'm not sure if I'm supposed to say that
yet, but those two use cases are
pretty relevant to us as a healthcare.
Absolutely.
Yeah. Anywhere we're accepting messages.
Yes.
In particular, all the messages are
messages.
Yes. So, IPEX EXN messages all covered
by KRAM.
Yes.
I just want to understand the problem a
little bit better of why we need to keep
this just I think that's what he had
asked.
Oh, sure.
I understand it replaces the knots, but
why is that beneficial? Like what?
What?
Yeah. Just so if you have a non I
assume it's kind of like a temporary
token.
Yes,
that's what I've used in the past. that
then it would increase the database size
or maybe you have to have
connectivity back to I'm trying to
figure out why.
It's like an elegant way of solving
it's like an elegant way of solving
replay attacks without attaching nonses
to every message because the time itself
functions as the nonce
like the time attached to the message.
It's not you know it's not that we don't
have a non the time is the non right
and with the knots you're talking about
interactive authentification right
this is fully not interactive
so if you think about think about
network latency we're doing at scale
requests
every request
has to create a TCP connection because
has to be it has to be a secure channel
otherwise you can't can't control it so
All asynchronous messaging is off the is
off the table. This allow this will work
with just as well with asynchronous
messaging as synchronous messaging.
It'll work just fine where the
sender and receiver use a completely
different channel. Doesn't matter.
Okay?
Because there's no interaction, right?
So now you can get rid of all of those
constraints and then the latency for a
request is zero because the request
either goes through or it doesn't.
Whereas if it's interactive, you send a
request, you get a reply, you send a
response, and now you've got three you
got three passes across your network,
which if your network's loaded or
congested, you triple the your latency
always. And when you go to scale, that
doesn't scale well. And you know, so
so that's a that's a reason not to use
interactive.
So to re
two reasons, one asynchronous messaging
asynchronous and remove the remove
the latency at scale.
So to reiterate for the microphone
this is asynchronous which traditional
nonsspased authentication is not and
this also works at scale without having
to rely on the traditional mode of
exchanging several messages in order to
meet the same meet the same
functionality.
So explaining a little about the problem
statement, right? You know what's what
was the difference between KERI not
having CRA and now CRA existing and I'm
just maybe restating is the but we just
restated for the replay attack but so
was that a vulnerability and existing
vulnerability right now?
Yes.
Okay. KRAM has been proposed for quite
quite some time but nobody thought it
was important to
So, so in our authentication server, we
have a custom build replay
and so we can now get rid of that once
we upgrade KERI 2.0.
Yeah. So, that was traditionally not
covered by the KERI suite or KERIpy
as
it
build their own attack.
We wanted we wanted it to be something
that everybody gets for free. Awesome.
All right,
get me out of here.