Cole Davis ｜ Contract Credentials & Verifiable Identity ｜ KERI Conference 2026
Hey everyone. I'm Cole Davis. I am
the founder of Switchchord, which is a
music, we're legal tech and digital
identity company building products
in the music industry. That is one
brand under sort of an IP holding
company we have called Steamroller
Systems that is industry agnostic to
apply machine learning and
decentralized identity techniques to
legal workflows. So we kind of blend
the worlds of legal tech and digital
identity primarily using
decentralized identity. And I'm going to
talk today though not about music
because I always talk about music and I
wanted to change it up. And today I'm
going to talk about I call these
things contract credentials. So I've for
years advocated that legal contracts and
and verifiable credentials should be
sort of married together like a legal…
like I wanted to create a dual root of
trust like a legal root of trust and a
cryptographic root of trust and I want
them to be inherent in everything you
do when you prove you have contractual
authority. So I spent years looking for
solutions starting in the blockchain
world and then the W3C DID VC world
discovered KERI in 2021 and finally was
like that's what I need. Primarily
because it doesn't require like an
underlying ledger. I can get into why
the Switchchord stack is built the way
it is but for now I'm just going to
focus on the general concept. And then I
did a demo in the real estate industry
because it tends to be easier to
understand and you don't need a whole
lot of like domain specific knowledge
about music to really appreciate it.
Because you apply the tech anywhere,
anywhere you have a legal contract or
contractual authority or contractual
relationship you can apply this
framework to it. So that's what we're
going to talk about today. So yeah,
like credentials a lot of times at at IIW
and the W3C and the KERI community, we
talk about credentials proving who you
are. You know, you're a human. You're an
organization. I don't often see them
proving what you have the contractual
authority to do. It's like not a concept
that comes easy to people. But when I
explain this to the music industry, I
often use the example and this actually
did start to resonate of a mobile
driver's license cuz some states have
mobile driver's licenses and they sit in
their Apple or Google wallet. So I
explain, driver's
license is a credential issued to you
from an issuer. It has claims about what
you can do and it's kind of digitally
signed and you can prove to third
parties that you have the authority to
do something. And so that's easier for
people to make that mental leap of oh
okay okay. So, you know, the contract
credential is kind of like this, but it
tells me I can sign documents over 10
million dollars cuz I have this authority from
the board of directors or I can enter
this building because my employer has a
lease with the building owner and I am
an active employee with the right to
enter the premises. So what I
wanted to do was the way a lot of
people talk about creating like
verifiable presentations or or capturing
claims from different credentials and
presenting them about you. Oh, I'm Cole.
I graduated from TCU. This is my GPA. I
have this job. Like okay, cool. I'm more
interested in the commercial
applications of this like as far as
commercial transactions go. So I want to
be able to say I'm this organization. I
have the contractual right to do this. I
have contractual right to do this. Like
I want to be able to pull select from
different contracts that give me the
authority to do transactions on a market
and I want that to be instantly
verifiable to third parties who want to
maybe do business with me. Because it
gets into that Ronald Coase world of
like transaction cost. How can we reduce
transaction cost? Verifying
counterparties and their reputations and
all that and their authority to do
things is like really really important
for transaction costs. So if you can
reduce some of this technology, you can
have more transactions on the market. So
that's what my concept of a contract
credential is is like what if they're
the same thing. What if the contract is
the credential? Like what if you can
hold your lease up to the smart lock or
what if you can, you know, the stock
option agreement or this stock
purchase agreement is the stock
certificate. Stop taking the
contract here and then the authority or
the thing it represents over here and
like no make them the same thing and
have a shared cryptographic and legal
root of trust. So that's basically what
this is. There's you know an authority
gap like credentials they don't model
contracts they live in separate systems.
You have a contract in your rights
management system or or contract life
cycle management system. And then you
have the operational aspects of the
contract, what you can do or what you're
required to do or can't do. Those
tend to live in different systems. What
if we collapse them into a single
system? You know, what if it's all the
same? Like it's a really weird concept,
but it's really powerful. And we've been…
Did you have a… saw hand for just a
second?
– I have a question [inaudible]. So
what's the difference between a
credential, a role and the terms that
the ACDC can define? Is that kind of
combined or
[inaudible] there as well?
– It's flexible enough to where you know
like the vLEI, ECR and role credentials
and stuff are sort of derived from this
whole general technology but it's a
little more specific. This is more
general. This is any employment
relationship, any board granted
authority, anything can be modeled into
this framework using ACDC. You can do it
with W3C VCs too, but there's
just like limitations there that ACDCs
give you. Ability to chain credentials
and they give you a better ability to
pull in legal pros and the Ricardian
concept. And ACDCs are way more powerful
to the concept of a contract credential.
You can do it with W3C VCs. You can do it
with whatever you want as long as it's
cryptographically verifiable data that
is derived from a contract. But it
needs to all be like one big signed
object. So, the way I think about it is
okay, you have a legal pros. I can't
remember if I actually have like the
three. Yeah, I do. So, I'll focus on
KERI ACDC's what the what GLEIF came up
with how you can take that. So taking
the legal relationship that is embodied
in a contract that's usually a bilateral
thing. It can be multilateral. It's
usually a bilateral thing. You can
model the relationship. So I landlord
give you tenant the right to enter
premises for one year for this rent and
you can do x y and z. So you can model
that relationship between counterparties
and assets. It doesn't have to have an
asset subject to the contract, but you
can model it. So in the music industry,
model it as far as what you can do
relating to copyrights. Copyrights have
in our system DIDs. They could have AIDs.
It doesn't matter. And so you're
modeling legal relationships between
organizations, people and things through
contracts. So the contracts are like the
the routing mechanism for the data. And
you pull in the AIDs or the DIDs into
the data model that is behind the legal
pros. So you got like, it looks like a
PDF or a Word document but you can use a
markup language you can have a data
model, you have JSON… Party A is
whatever Acme systems. Acme systems can
have their AID or DID in the data
model and so you're modeling… yeah it
looks like a English name but you're
pulling in the identity the
decentralized identifier with all you
know the key state and stuff and then
that whole object is what's going to get
signed so you're attesting
to this is our relationship it is
embodied in this thing and this thing
can then generate these credentials that
has a one to one mapping to the legal
contract and a one to one mapping to the
identities and the one to the
counterparties and a one to one mapping to
any assets that are like the subject of
that thing. So we're that's what we do
is model legal relationships. So why
KERI? I mean, you guys probably
already know all of this, but AIDs,
it's a short talk, so I
can't go into like why I stumbled upon
KERI and what I was looking for, but I
didn't want… we were modeling the legal
state of a copyright. So, let's say four
different music companies own a
copyright. It's very common. Okay, cool.
We're going to model the copyright as a
DID. Okay, who are the controllers of
the DID doc? Hm. This should be the
owners. So, we can model that through
the contracts that give those four music
companies ownership. They can all have
DIDs, controller properties. Cool. Oh,
shoot. They want to rotate their DID. Aah,
we're all using the same DID method that
relies on a ledger. Ah, so now I have to
explain to like these big well-known
music companies: I need you to interact
with like the Ethereum blockchain. It
just doesn't work. And I wanted all of
them to be able to manage their key
state separately. And so that's… I
discovered KERI and I was like, that's
what I want. Like everyone needs to
manage their key state separately, but
you can still compose a full like chain
of title as far as assets go. It
just also happens to work really well
for contracts, too. So, KERI AIDs, the
base layer. ACDC's have a lot more
power than W3C VC's. You can do it
either way but ACDC's again sort of the
the rule, you know the
Ricardian part, the attribute section and
then the edge capability to chain
credentials is really important. The
the TELs and the KELs like being able
to anchor a credential to a TEL which
is anchored to a KEL is really
important because if the landlord, if the
lessee stops paying the landlord, it's a
breach and they revoke… they
terminate the lease. You want the
credential to automatically revoke so
that the tenant can't get in or the
tenants authorized you know delegated
employee can't get in, you know, you want
the whole thing to break at once when
there's a breach of the contract. So the
contract should be like the actor in the
system. And vLEI, like GLEIF's already
done so much work here with sort of
bringing this into what we consider
legal workflows. And so
this stack is a great way to do
this. So yeah that this is sort of legal
pros. So let's say in the R section of
ACDC you can actually have you can have
the actual pros or you have the
digest of it as a SAID. You have the
structured data. So the attribute
section which is you know think of it
just JSON like term one year rent
$100,000 square foot 4,000. And then
you can have the edges. So you can be
delegating contract like
contractual authority. Which is
really important because that's how
things work in the real world is a lot
of times like the actions you take are
from a couple different contracts. Maybe
they're in a chain, maybe they're not.
Either way, you can sort of like compose
it into a proof using this stack. So
I pulled just a random
corporate or commercial lease building
lease from the SEC's Edgar platform.
So this is an actual commercial lease
that was used by big sophisticated
companies. So what you can do is you
can have let's say they were negotiating
this lease. So they can negotiate in
Word using a markup language. you can
sort of put it into the data model
that would then populate the ACDC
attribute section or it's the same thing
as the JSON schema of a W3C VC.
So you're you're tying the schema to
the pros and then from there, yeah so
let's say we're doing it for an office
lease. This is kind of what the ACDC
fields would look like. You've got
the issuer AID. You can have the
attribute section which is the deal
points. You can have edges which I'll
show you for this one. We can create the
access credential from the lease
credential. You can have rules all
the technical aspects of an ACDC.
So one way to show how this can become a
chain. So let's say they sign that data
object. Cool. And now we've got a
credential that is derived and
cryptographically married to that
contract. Any asset can
have an identity. Assets should have
identities. So the building can have an
AID. In our in Switchchord all the
copyrights have DIDs, DID:web DIDs
just for simplicity. We did an
implementation with DID:Webs to show
that KERI can be used in that system.
So all of our assets should have
decentralized identifiers and then the
controllers of those assets should be
the controllers the owners in the real
world either ownership or like
administration rights. All of this can
be modeled. And so within this example,
this building where the commercial lease
is has an identity, an AID. And then
you've got a less or an AID, the lessee
with an AID. You have the lease
contract. And you can derive the access
credential from the lease itself. So
like the lessee can issue it to itself as
an access credential. There's lots of
different ways you can do this. This is
just one example to kind of show what it
would look like. So again, lease
credential. So the contract credential
that's derived from the contract
using Sam's like the I2I versus the
NI2I. So that would be
the issuee, the lessee
issuing it to themself and they can now
say like I have it from this contract
and it can be then shown to a smart
lock. this references the building
identity, the issuer like in this case
this is just a lessor
creating it themselves but, let's say, we
I build a building with someone else
then we can actually have a contract
that says all right I own 50% you own
50% and that contract can then create
like the building ID there's different
ways you can do this there's not like
one set way it's really flexible so
you've got the building identity that
gets pulled into this that gets pulled
into that derived credential that you
can show to a smart lock. So this is
that the I2I operator just one example
of what you can do here. So this would
be the lessee of the lease contract
granting themselves an authority
contract. You could probably do it
without that. I was just trying to show
a simple example of how you can
have chained delegation from a single
contract.
Like you could probably just have
this be the lease credential too. But
you know if you're issuing this instead
of issuing your employees like you know
entrance badges, you just issue it as a
credential their phone and then they're
they're basically the ones doing a
delegated access credential from
their employment agreement credential
which then goes to the lease
credential where your employer is the
tenant. Like so that's how you can
build these chains that can then like
automate legal processes.
The rule section you can like Sam's
done very forward thinking here with
sort of putting the legal pros in with
the credential itself. This is kind
of
this kind of optional like if you were
to still do the same framework of a data
model in a legal pros contract and the
whole bundle is signed. You kind of have
it already, but you can get even more
granular. And this is what is really
helpful for selective disclosure. So
like you don't want to show the whole
contract. You just want to show I have
the right to do this one thing. Like I
don't need to show you smart lock how
much rent we pay. I don't need to show
you any of that. It's just like
selective disclosure for a human proving
attributes about yourself. You don't
want to show your home address. You
don't have to just show that you're over
21. So it's the same thing. You can
selectively disclose or graduated
disclosure your contractual authority
which is extremely powerful to build you
know if you're building towards trust
with a counterparty. This would be
the office AID. So creating a digital
twin is represented as an AID. Again
this one is issued from an ACDC that
the lessor the ID like attests to the
building. I own the building. This is
the information about the building and
here's the building AID. You have a
smart lock that knows I control access
to the building AID and so you can build
logic into that but it knows I am here
solely to let people into this AID. If
you show me something that does
not line up with his AID, you're not
getting in. If you show me something
that is to this Aid but is revoked,
you're not getting in. If you know like
the smart lock becomes
you don't need like a central
registry anymore. It's like the
credentials from the contract and the
smart lock just knows it. It's a
mental leap for a lot of… like if I were
to take this to market as you know a
product for say commercial apartment
like apartment managers or commercial
building managers they'd be like what?
But it's really powerful. It cuts down
on like so much infrastructure that's
currently required. So yeah graduated
disclosure super helpful. You know
you can for for this example you could
just say
to different verifiers
you can disclose different things. So
again like the smart lock you don't need
to disclose the rent term or the you
know well maybe the term but not like
the amount of rent but to your like a
financial auditor maybe you need to do
the whole thing to a third party. The
graduated disclosure of contractual
authority is incredibly powerful. It
just versus whole showing them the whole
contract. That's not good. You can just
show what you need to prove.
– Litigation, you might want to just say
even if it is a litigation.
– Oh, totally. Yeah.
– Could could you repeat the
question because…
– So in litigation, say
there's litigation over a contractual
provision, you know, there's all
sorts of
what's evidentiary rules. I took
evidence in law school, but I'm not I'm
not a litigator. I'm a corporate lawyer,
corporate entertainment lawyer.
There's lots of rules for that, you
know, the judge can order things
redacted, but this would be a
bulletproof way to redact things, you
know, so you don't have these
boneheaded, oh yeah, the PDF is redacted
with a black bar, and you can like
delete the black bar, you know, like you
could actually have cryptographic
opening up that and and then you can
really dial in who has the ability to do
that, you know, like it's crazy what you
can do. So yeah, this could certainly be
applied. You know, if there was a
litigation over this commercial lease,
like, okay, you go to arbitration
instead of litigation. So the
arbitrator, a mediator, okay, maybe you
don't want to show the arbitrator. It
it's really cool that you can
selectively disclose things and know
that it's true like
cryptographically
know that it's that that's the state of
this contract. So revocation would
kind of use the KEL and the TEL
framework to say all right lease
terminates the lessor would create
revocation event in their TEL that's
going to tell the smart lock that at
this time period with our key state we
revoked this credential that was issued
with this signing key in our KEL and so
that's how the lock would the smart lock
just walks the cryptographic operations
all the way back and it's like eh, you
know, it gets to the point of sorry,
this thing's been revoked. So yeah,
it's really powerful to be able to
present contractual authority. You know,
the easy thing to think about is like
proving it to a human or an
organization, but it's like no, no, no,
how about a how about a software system?
How about you're trying to get into a
certain secure database in your
organization and only certain engineers
have that? Like hm that could be done
through the employment agreement and
like so it's really powerful when you
start thinking about it in these
granular ways and then as soon as you're
fired you don't have to do anything else
you know like it's done it's like
everything breaks versus oh my god we
got to log in to this system and revoke
his authority and this system revoke
like everything
once you start to view the world this
way I can't undo it like I view the
world differently that this there's this
inter in interaction between contractual
authority. And then like
your rights as a human and it's it can
all be kind of bound up and it would
be cool if you could pick and choose
from all of them. So like I work here, I
live here, I am employed here, I have
the contract right to this and I can
just take what I need to to prove
anything. So I focus on the
commercial transaction elements. The
vLEI again you can model this based on the
GLEIF route to the QVI to the legal entity
to the role credential and the ECR.
So that's a little more specific to the
GLEIF environment. This is an abstraction
of that like anything can be turned into
this. so in we could even
abstract the GLEIF one to say okay the
board of directors there's five
individuals they all have AIDs they all
agree in a written consent to give Karla
authority to sign contracts up to
ten million dollars, cool they digitally sign this
pros looking consent that creates the
board consent credential. The credential
itself can be chained to the employment
credential of Karla. Karla's credential
gives her certain her employment
relationship ship gives her certain
rights. The board has now given her
certain rights. We can pull those
together and now when she tries to go
into Docusign, she's asked to present her
authority credential, which can be a
derived credential. The contract is 20
million. Karla needs to get more
authority. So, it's a much
more abstract and granular notion, but
it's the same general framework. And
that's powerful because we know it works
like GLEIF is in production and it works.
So, I'm trying everywhere I
can. I'm trying not to reinvent things
that already work. So yeah,
I didn't have time and I
don't think I really can. Like I've
gotten pretty good at vibe coding
legal products. I built it myself as a
lawyer to automate things, but I tried
to build this and it was just too hard
to do the actual, you know, KERI stack.
So, I built like a simulated version,
which I'll walk you through. So you got
the AIDs of all the parties. The lessor
will create the building ID. You then
sign the lease. The lease then populates
the schema of the hybrid legal
contract populates the scheme of the
ACDC. The attribute section. You
then derive the access credential from
that. So it's an issuer the eye to eye
transaction from lessee to itself and then
lessee can present that. The smart lock
would then verify back.
Okay, so I vibe coded this.
This is based on the ACDC like IETF,
whatever it's called specs. So
everything's like very much to spec.
I didn't have the time or
capability to spin up all the
infrastructure to make this real. So
you've got this contract is like I said,
this is a real contract. I found it on
the SEC's website. I was like, I want
something, you know, it's 45 pages,
really dense, really complex. And I
used that for this demo. So, this would
be the inception event for let's see,
this is the lessor. So, the property
owner, and this follows, you know,
everything that you technical people in
here are familiar with with all of Sam's
fields. Same with this one. You've
got the AID in there, somewhere. I think
it's the I and then you've got this
building. So, this digital twin with an
AID, you know, public key and then it
shows
it shows where. So, again,
I don't have the ACDC white paper
IETF spec memorized. So, I get kind of
lost when I'm looking like which one is
the actual issuer, but it would be AO6.
There it is. Okay. So that's the one
that's the lessor. So now we've got
AIDs for the lessor or the lessee in the
building. So then
we would
issue the building identity credential.
So this would be issued by the lessor
that attests to the building and gives
the attributes about the building.
This is establishing the idea of the
building that can be pulled into this
concept of contract credential. We've
got the lease. So, I don't know where I
put the PDF if I had it, but so this is
the actual language from the lease. This
is how you could take a markup language
to then so it would actually say, you
know, that in the pros version, but if
you look at it with X-ray vision, you're
kind of seeing this behind the scenes.
And then this is what's populating
the ACDC schema or for a W3C it' be
just like the JSON in the VC schema. Um,
so that's how you're having like a one
to one mapping between the contract and
the credential. And then that whole data
object can be signed. So you've got
ideally the same public private key pair
is signing the PDF as it's signing the
data model and the credential. It should
all be the same. That's how you can like
bind everything together. And then
you've got, let's see, lessee receives the
credential now acts as the issuer. Oh,
this is where just to show the delegated
and the chaining mechanism. This is
where the lessee can create its own access
credential. Let's say this is for an
employee. So they issue it to the
employee.
– I'll ask a question, but please repeat
it as well for your mic.
– Oh yeah. Yeah, definitely.
– What, it's a bit off topic, but how
much time do you think will we have
to endure before this becomes all
graphic like with puppets? Lessor, lessee…
You can click on them.
– Yeah, that's what it should be.
Totally.
– What do you think? What kind of… Please
repeat the question.
– Yeah.
– How soon? How much time?
So, I mean, this was me. I built this I
built all of this in about 4 hours
late at night when I needed to get
you, you know, was due. I forgot what
the due date was for the slides, but I
was like, "Oh my god, I still haven't
done them yet." So, I did everything
using Claude and Cursor in including
building this in about four hours.
So, like I could probably turn this into
a much prettier UI. This is
basically a oneshot attempt.
I mean Opus 4.7 did all everything
you're seeing here is like me working
with Opus 4.7.
– I'm just unaware are there already
toolkits to to make it more graphic
graphically? – So the question is on like
UI/UX of all of this. I don't know.
Decentralized identity tends to have
a pretty bad UI/UX in general. It's hard.
Some companies have done a much
better job than others. I would
prefer to see it. Again, I'm really just
trying to show just like how it works,
the nuts and bolts using the actual
ACDC spec. But yeah, there's no way I
would show like build a product that
looked like this to like an apartment
manager. There's zero way. This is all
behind the hood.
– I think that's the solution, I think, to
what you're saying is I don't think
there's going to be
a oneway fits all way to view all this.
I think it's going to be individual
apps.
That are that are encapsulating it all.
Yeah. I mean, so we built this
amazing platform for the music industry.
It was five years ahead of its
time which is why it was hard to get off
the ground because no one knew what we
were talking about. We're taking
songwriter agreements. We're dropping
them in. We use AI to extract everything
about the legal relationship between a
songwriter and a music publisher.
Populates a W3C VC issues the
songwriter. So now we've got this
connection verified connection from the
writer and the publisher. Writer writes
a new song drops in the information
right here on their phone. Boom. Shows
up instantly on the publisher side. It's
tracking from the contract. It's almost
like the data is getting stamped by the
contract as it goes through the pipe.
It's amazing, but no one understands it.
The identity thing, no one cares that we
built this cool thing where you can like
click the credential, it flips over and
shows the JSON schema. Everyone's like,
how does that help me? So that product,
I don't want to say it failed. It was
like a great product and it actually
this one feature of that product is now
what is getting a ton of interest and is
working for us and we will Trojan horsey
identity stuff back in eventually but
but yeah UI/UX is just hard with this
stuff.
– So more comment than question at this
point
on this model from a physical
security standpoint you said you know
this is a management company for an
apartment building. Most places today
have a keypad out in front that you put
in and it calls up or whatever lets you
in.
They're made by two manufacturers.
You can buy the three keys that open
that box everywhere in the world.
For $18 and there's a button inside that
overrides the system and opens the door.
So to your point, if it was on the
phone, you could completely do away with
that. – You have biometric. You marry
biometric to cryptographic to legal…
– That would save these folks…
– So much money cuz they they have to go
pay insurance. You got to pay insurance.
Anytime there's a risk, you got to
insure it and that's a transaction cost
that doesn't need to be there. That's
what I'm saying. Like
this magic cryptography can just like
really reduce transaction cost
everywhere you look. And and like I
said, once you see the pattern,
it's really hard to unsee. Now
everything I look, I'm like, "Oh god,
why do we do it that way?" But
yeah, so this would be great. And this
would be instead of, you know, most
apartment complexes don't let you do
Airbnb, but people still do it because
you can find ways to trade the key fobs.
Like this technically kills that. Or you
can put in place rules and governance
that says you may rent out your
apartment, but the other person must be
verified and have a credit score over X.
Like you can build in the logic. They
get the credential, they buy a metric,
they show it, they go in. It's
really powerful what you can do with
this stuff. – You have five more minutes.
– Okay, cool. So this is the example of
showing it to the smart lock and this is
what's happening is it's checking this
is like checking all the KELs, the
TELs, traversing the nodes, you know
again that didn't actually just happen
with the true KERI stack but this is
true to the ACDC spec and like how it
would happen and so okay access granted
you know this is the tenant that was the
tenant with that AID they can get in
24/7 to sweet 105 open it up and then
this would be what happens if
the tenant doesn't pay their rent and
the lease is terminated. Therefore, all
building access credentials of employees
are automatically revoked. That's what
this one would be. Let's see. Attempt
access with revoked lease. So, it kind
of does the same thing. It's
running backwards and checking the TEL,
seeing that that edge on the lease has
been this TEL was revoked. It has the
registry AID, the TEL sequence. You
can, you know, check the signing keys at
the time. Access denied. Reason,
upstream credential revoked, lease
contract, lease is terminated. So, yeah,
that's kind of like a, to me, much
easier to understand than the music
stuff, and it's fun to apply
this to other things. So that is
that's the demo. That's that. And I
think that is kind of the end of
the presentation.
So yeah, that's what we're doing.
[applause]
So I guess we have
five minutes for questions.
– Yeah.
Yeah. So what's the… Have you studied
you got a lawyer [inaudible]? Have you
studied the enforcability angle of this?
– Yeah, I mean there's
no enforcability issues cuz you start
with the legal pros contract as the
base, you know, so
yeah, it's all enforceable because you
have it all like you've got it, you
know, different states. in Wyoming's
been pushing the boundaries on this and
others are you know smart contracts are
legally enforceable like blockchain
based smart contracts. That's fine but
we're not going to get rid of human
communication and legal pros like it's
it's not going away anytime
soon. I don't think we're going to have
some domain specific coding language
where the language you write is the
contract and it is the code.
Like I just don't see that happening.
And so I think you have to take this
sort of hybrid approach of
you know there's disputes. It's going to
have to go in front of some sort of
judge or arbitrator or mediator or
something. And they can't read the
KERI, you know, they can't read the
ACDC spec. It's not going to happen. So,
you still have to have that original
legal pros. You can pull it out, you
can hash it, “SAID” it. I don't
know how it's Sam likes to pronounce it.
It's different every time.
Said it.
Said
said. Okay. You can said it, you know.
So, it's just a hash digest. You can do
whatever you want, but just don't
think you'll ever get around needing a
contract.
– Is it just me …
KERI is incredibly powerful,
but it's very hard to explain to people.
You see, have you seen that?
– Yeah. KERI especially. So, like
when I explain to the music industry, I
can't bring up KERI. I just have
to talk about
basic JSON and W3C.
[inaudible]
make it easier for consumption.
– I think it just needs to be in the
back end of products and I think you
just can't even really
explain a lot of it. It's like most
people don't know how the internet
works.
– It's got to be user experience.
– Yeah. Like 99 people% of the people
don't understand how the internet works.
– [inaudible] That's exactly where I am.
If they can connect to the
business aspect of things, they go.
– Yeah. Now, that I mean that's what we're
trying to do. Like we're getting closer
and we've been working at this for four
or five years now and it's like we're
finally getting somewhere.
– We have to stop other
– Oh yeah. Totally.
– Just do it.
– Just do it. Just do it. Just use it.
Make people fight you about it.
Yeah. [applause]