So…
I'm gonna start
and just talk about KERI development
and deployment
and can you hear me good? Does it
work?
Is it good?
Okay, sweet.
[inaudible]
can start for development on your own
and that includes maybe doing your
own plugin for Locksmith and developing
your own API for witnesses and
watchers.
So I want to talk first about the KERI
infrastructure that we have.
[inaudible]
and the watchers which is pretty much
you've seen this the diagram a lot
in the past few days but for the
requirements the
only thing that we really need is Python.
We recommend the version 3.13
3.14 had some issues with some repo.
So 3.13 should be fine and then
Libsodium because this is what
KERI uses for its cryptographic
library.
So first we'll go with the wallet first.
It's a Locksmith. The role of
Locksmith on this wallet is to generate
the AIDs to sign it, to have the key
pairs secure and to store and verify
through your KELs and finally the
OOBIs.
Nothing more, I think, to expand on it.
It's just basically the basic function
of a wallet.
And then we're going to go through
deploying it. So we have just three
parts that we're going to go through
individually and basically first I'm
going to show you the repo and how you
can set up the environment with its
dependencies and how to run it and
everything, every deployment that we're
going to go through are going to be
local
and I can explain that for a while
later. So first you have the public
repo for the Locksmith which is on
the KERI Foundation. Note that what
I'm going to use in this presentation
for the demo is from a branch of this
repo which is the KERI Foundation
branch. It's not the main branch that
I'm going to use because the KERI
Foundation branch has the KERI
Foundation plugin that we're going to
talk about later. I'm also going to
try to show your attention on the
docs that are provided by the repo and
I'm just going to show you a bit through
those docs. So the developer guide in
those docs kind of explain what I
explained before. So if you need a
reminder, you can just go to the repo
and then read it. But first it's
going to be Python 3.13. And then to set
up your environment, you just have to
follow the commands that are on the
developer guide. Pretty easy.
And then finally to run it, you have the
Qt resource regeneration. And once you
just copy paste and run those commands,
you can just run this one. And then
hopefully a lot of initialization logs
will pop up and then hopefully you will
have your Locksmith.
I'm just going to run it myself if
I can show you.
So, I'm just gonna
activate the virtual environment and
then I'm just gonna… maybe I can just…
So here we have our Locksmith.
I just created a vault, but we can…
I make a new one…
call it presentation.
No passcode and then, here you go.
So here…
– A vault is just a logical grouping of
a of AIDs or?
– Yes if you're familiar with the
KERIpy code it's the same as a habry
which is where you host your AIDs and
which is where you have your key pairs
and all that stuff.
Okay.
So here you have the KERI Foundation
plugin which we're going to talk about
now if I can there you go. So the reason
why we have a KERI Foundation plugin is
why we have a EKRI Foundation plugin is
actually because of a boot server that
we have.
So the boot server what is the boot
server? Well the boot server is kind of
the in between be in between before
between Locksmith and the watch
witnesses and watchers. And the role of
the boot server is to provision the
witnesses to your wallet. And now you're
gonna maybe a question that you might
have is why can I not just talk from
Locksmith directly to the witnesses and
watchers? Well, the reason for that is
the witnesses and watchers API.
So when you look here for example
for the witnesses API you have actually
two servers. So you have the boot server
and then you have the witness server.
The boot server, if you pay attention to
the API,
this is the one that actually creates
the witnesses and deletes them. And the
problem is that the boot server is
private. So it's not publicly
accessible. So even if you try to send a
request to it, it will not respond.
But the witness server and the
watcher server those two are public. So
once you have your witnesses and your
watcher you can publicly access those
however you want. And same for the
watcher API this is also private. So the
reason is that we have our boot
server which serve as the one who
will call the private APIs to get the
witnesses and watchers and the f the
KERI Foundation plug-in acts as a
bridge between the Locksmith wallet and
the boot server. Currently the boot the
KERI Foundation plugin is in charge of
onboarding witness registration watcher
resolution and off management. And when
we're talking about on boarding we're
talking about kind of setting you up
so you can have your own witnesses
And watcher.
Now an important thing to note is that
For the at least locally the KERI
Foundation sorry the boot server has
to be on the same machine or server as
the witnesses and watchers so it can
talk locally as I mentioned before
because the APIs are private.
So
so yeah so now let's go through the
plugin before we go through the boot
server. So I want to go to the plugin
and how you could if you wanted make
your own plugin.
So if you go to the Locksmith repos
repository and if you go to the plugins
and the base py it has a bunch of
classes that allows you to create your
own plugin. If you look at the
plug-in.base it has a bunch of method
that you can override to create your
own plugin.
For example here is the KERI
Foundation plugin that is in the plug-in
folder. You can also look it up on the
KERI Foundation branch. It is using
the plug-in base, the witness provider
plugin and the account provider plugin.
Then it has
u for example here you can see that it's
overriding the plug-in ID function
and the initialize function. I'm not
going to go into too much detail as to
how you can or what you should put into
into those methods, but at least know
that it's there. And if you need the
references you can just look at the
KERI Foundation plugin in the
repository to maybe get some in
inspiration.
Okay. So now I want to go through
the witnesses. Oh, no, sorry. I want to
go to the boot server. And just to
remind you, the boot server serve as a
public API to provision your
witnesses and watcher. The kev boot is
also available publicly. So if you want
to look at it, you can. It's on the
KERI Foundation repository. You can
look at it. See how the code works.
And to run it very simple create your
virtual environment. And then here are
the variable that your that your G
foundation boot needs to talk to
the witnesses and watcher. I'm going
to just show you also to do a demo.
So
So here I have my KERI Foundation
boot server. I'm going to
activate it. And then
Just like in the just like in the
slide that I showed, I'm just going to
cop copy. I'm not going to install the
dependencies since I'm already done it.
So I'm going to go here, paste these,
and then run it. So now you can see that
it's running here. And if I go
Oh,
let me Bam. Because I need to refresh
it. Sorry.
Oh, I also need to
I also need to give Locksmith
the
the address for the
for the
boot server. So here and then if I run
it back
my Locksmith
can get in.
Oh why is it?
Oh maybe because
Oh, already connects, I guess. H, it's
already connected to the boot server, I
guess.
So, I actually can't see it, but
usually if you look it up on the K
Foundation plugin, it should show that
you can service an AID and connect
witnesses and watchers to it.
You could try deleting your local KERI
home.
and then start fresh and then should
recreate on that.
Oh, I make a whole another repo.
I could
Yeah, go ahead. Go ahead.
I could I could do it at the end
probably. I just want to go through
the whole slide and maybe I'll do
another demo. But so let me finish the
slides first. Go to the witnesses of
course have the role of the witnesses
and what they do the anchor the events
and trying to keep the authenticity
and make sure that everything is correct
of course because we're the witnesses.
So same thing we're going to go through
the witness the repo the environment and
how to run it locally.
So first you can get the code on the
witness repository in the career
foundation.
It also has docs. So I have the
developer guide. Same thing just make
sure that you have lip sodium.
How to set up your environment.
And then one thing about the
configuration
If you were here last time Ryan
you talked about it and how it works. So
I'm not going to repeat it again but
just suggest surely that the curls here
will be the address that the witness
server is going to use.
And then to run the witnesses, you can
use the first one or I usually use the
other one. Let me
show it here.
So I have it here. Let me activate
the
Oops.
And then let me take Oops.
Let me write this. So scripts
and then
so there you go. So you have my
witnesses running
and if you if you look at here you can
see the public server address I mean the
port which is 5631
Sorry the private one which is
internal and then external which is the
public one at the 5632 port which is
the default one unless you change it in
the configuration and then you can see
your witnesses and their own AID.
Now to develop with witnesses
You have the API which is given and
shown in the readme file of the
repository for the witnesses you have
different of course action post
delete but I'm going to go into the post
and here basically have the
the whole post function it's a falcon
app so it's in under the witness
collection class And if you look at it
closely,
you can see that when it receive a post
method, it will first check for the AID,
check that it's a valid AID, and then it
just creates a witness
Gets the OOBIs and sends the data
back. That's all it does. So, if you
wanted, you could check for I don't
know, check for more things. But if you
want to start developing witnesses and
changing maybe how they behave, this is
where you would go. This is just an
example of the on post, but there's also
the ondelete. There's also all the all
the public
actions and API that you can change
which would also be under
Under this. So it's in
withnetwitnessing py. So if you want to
change anything go here.
Now the watchers
same thing that we're going to go
through public repo of the watchers in
the current foundation.
This one doesn't have docs yet. I
suppose we might either add it later.
But that's from the readme. You can
but that's from the readme. You can
I don't think we can install from pi
yet. Correct me if I'm wrong. Yeah, we
can install it from pi yet. So, just
clone the repo and then install the
environment or hopefully with the from a
virtual environment.
Same thing same thing for the
configuration. The curls is also the
address from which the whater server is
going to respond to.
I'm going to also
have it in here. So, my watcher,
where is this? So,
so here. Just going to activate it. And
then
if I go
bam.
Then just copy this.
All right. So if you I'm just going to
go back to the slide.
But here you can see the same thing as
the witnesses. It shows your address
public address for the watcher
server private and also the watchers
running. I can probably show it
better on here.
You can see they have the watchers here
as well as their IDs. And then you can
see that it's going up because the
witnesses are running. So, they're all
checking the witnesses.
So,
A quick note that is important
is that the W witnesses and watcher are
supposed to run together. They're not
supposed to be individually
running. They have to be together.
So, first would be the witnesses and
then the watchers have to be
deployed together.
Same thing for the watchers. you
have the same API and you can find the
Functions for them in this file here.
I took the post for the watchers that
provision the watcher.
So to finish what we have is this
architecture technically that we have
the wallet that can make public API
requests but mostly if you want to just
have witnesses and watchers provisioning
it would be through a boot server that
then talks privately to witnesses and
watcher server in their own environment.
I think that's all I have. Unless
do you guys have any questions?
Yes.
Thank you.
Given that Kir is a protocol and again
given that Kir is a protocol and again
protocols not companies. So why
would you want to make changes to
weaknesses or watchers? I thought that
was like common infrastructure or am I
wrong?
Am I like for example in this?
Yeah. Yeah. For example, you can add
some more checks or you can have u we
were talking about weight limiting
for example on how much a person
could provision witnesses. You could
limit it or you could expand it.
Also another thing that you
could note
For example for the plugin if I can
find it I think it was here. Oh yeah.
So, for example, for the KERI
Foundation plugin, all it does right now
is just onboarding. So, it's pretty
simple. But if you really wanted to, you
can make your own plugin where you
include payment. So, people go through
the payment first and then it would
provision your witnesses and watchers
and your watchers can make sure the
money was transferred.
Yeah. So, it could it could go through
then off authorization for some account
approve account management and
approvement.
Approval.
Approval. There you go. that's the word.
So, yeah. So, if you want, I think what
would be more interesting is probably
doing your own plug-in first because
that's when you could decouple that
from the witnesses and just handle
everything in your own plugin.
One thing to note also that this
witness service that we're talking about
here doesn't necessarily if you're
manipulating in that on post handler,
you're not necessarily manipulating how
the witness code itself works. type
you're just you're just manipulating the
layer basically the API layer of
communication to
so you can expand
so you're really not modifying any other
just adding extra functionality
auxiliary functional
right exactly
got it
and if
of course being open source if you
wanted to go in and manipulate the
witness protocol some way for your own
version you that's on your on your own
yeah and I think oh wait
I think if to look here for example
This is all it does just calls create
witness but then everything after you
can you can probably
add more functionalities for yourself
for example for tracking or for like
stats if you wanted to but that's up to
you so I'm just trying to give you an
example of where you would start and how
you could start
that create witness method weaves down
into the car pie
Yeah,
cool.
great. Thank you.
Yeah, no problem. So, if you don't have
any questions, then I think I'll give
you back 20 minutes.