Okay. So, welcome to the session on
secure asset transfer protocol. I'm Ned
Smith. I happen to be Sam's brother.
So I've been introducing myself as
so I've been introducing myself as
Sam's brother for a long time.
I'm the younger one. But I have a
30-year career at Intel and then another
eight years in industry. all of it
related to security. So Sam's the
newcomer in the group to security just
so you know. And I've also been a
pr prolific inventor. So I have over 500
granted patents
and I've been interested in
Doing some work in the IETF. Most
recently I have been looking at the
SATP protocol in one of the working
groups in the IETF. So I'm going to just
give you a quick overview of what the
IETF is as a standards organization and
how the SATP group fits in there. So
IETF is the acronym engineering task
force. It's really a standard setting
body that's recognized internationally.
It is the body that defined the internet
protocol. So it is all of all
things internet originated in the IETF.
The organization itself is
structured around different areas. So
there's a internet area, a routing area,
security operations, general
applications and real time. There's a
few others that I didn't mention here.
And within the applications in real time
area, also called ART,
there's a working group called Secure
Asset Transfer. And they're the ones
that are doing the work to define a
secure asset transfer protocol.
And I'm going to talk about that the
rest of this talk.
So to dive in here, there's a what
you might think of as the canonical use
case in SATP to drive the technical
You know portions of it. So I'm going
to walk through this use case. It's
essentially a token issuance use case.
And this token the tok in this
use case it's it's built around this
something called the asset reference
token or art not to be confused with the
working group. But it's it's a sort
of think of it as a reference token for
you know for working through the
you know challenges associated with
building
Systems around tokenized
assets
and stable coins. So in this ca in
this use case the token issuer in step
one issues and declares an asset that is
then given to an artifacts
registry to make it persist there so
so the so that the artif the u you know
the asset is known to exist. In step
two, the issuer mints a token. And
we're using the acronym network
one or NW1 to re refer to the
token issuer side of this exchange.
And they mint the token and in
this token, there's sort of the value
part or part one, which is the part that
is on the chain. And then there's
something called context data or part
two which refers to any artifacts that
are not onchain or maybe partially
onchain but in some way represent some
stability to the stable coin asset
and that linking will be
the importance of that linking
will come in a little bit later
in the context of the asset network.
So in this case, they've minted the
minted the coin and then there's an
entity that is the interface to the
asset management network. So we're
calling this, you know, network one,
asset network one. And that's
where you interface to whatever is your
distributed ledger technology, whether
it's a public, private, or even a
monolithic
Network.
And then in step four, the gateway reads
a token from network one which we're
calling the SATP gateway one. And that
then in step five interfaces with the
artifacts registry to collect the
additional data that's there and is
and it's validates that prior to the
asset transfer. And then in step six,
this is sort of the jumping off point
for actually doing the transfer over the
SATP protocol. And the idea is you're
transferring an asset from gateway
one or the g the token
issuers domain into another network
which is receiving that asset.
So what are the sat entities? There's
there's something called the originator
which is the entity that owns the asset
and then the beneficiary which is the
entity that's receiving the asset.
There's a set of hosts that are in
the model for how that exchange happens.
So there's the gateway which are the
endpoints of the protocol. There's an
asset network or an oracle that is the
controller of all the domain assets.
Anything that's relevant to the context
in which that gateway operates is
represented in by this notion of
an asset network could be one or many
hosts.
Then there's the user application or
orchestrator which is the kind of the
controller or the entity that's driving
the you know the asset transfer that's
coordinating the resources and
and giving the instructions to the
gateways to do to you know present their
assets on the protocol.
There's another entity which I call the
host owner. It's not in the first
iterations of the protocol. It's not
really called out directly, but it's
implied in the some of the some of
the message exchanges that appear in
stage one of the protocol. So I'm
calling it out as it's a leg it's a real
entity and we'll call it the host
owner for now just to make the slides
more clear but it's the it's these
entities that are responsible for
administering the infrastructure and are
the ones that it represents the entities
that are responsible for
You the that are legally
responsible for the for the asset.
There's also something called an
artifacts registry. Think of it as a
directory that maintains asset transfer
context and makes it u persistent
for whatever additional
You investigation that's needed on
the asset. So think of it as it
there's some way to make it's it's
something that provides the audit trail
for the protocol.
So here is a view of the architecture
for SATP.
One of the main goals of this
architecture is to essentially implement
a an atomic two-phase commit protocol
for the asset exchange. It's
fundamentally decentralized. In other
words, there's no assumption that the
originator and the beneficiary are share
a trusted third party relationship.
the there's a tokenized and
non-tokenized assets. So, not everything
is on chain per se. But it can exist
and it is relevant to the to the
exchange of assets.
It needs to be audit auditable and
and the assets need to be durable.
There's also the notion of a canonical
identifier, which is to say that the
representation of the identifiers and
the information that are known to the
originator don't have to be the same as
the representation of identifiers that
are known to beneficiary B. In other
words, the
the attributes that are in
common have to be negotiated or created
as part of the protocol.
But it's not requiring that the that
the asset ident the asset identifier has
to be
Morphed into a namespace that's
defined by the protocol or the
artifacts registry.
There's a need for asset versioning
pinning and roll back. That's part of
the two-phase commit requirement. And
It's al there's also requirements for
provenenced asset transfers. In other
words, you should be able to unwind this
This asset transfer and be able
to identify all the stages in the
transfer after the transfer has
happened.
And so as you can see in the
diagram, the protocol is divided into
four stages. Stage zero, stage one, two
and three. And
and you see the artifacts registry kind
of in the middle. It's not really a
separate entity. and I'll talk
more about why that is in a second.
One thing to note is that the author
the authority model in this in from
the perspective of the architecture in
the first series of drafts there is
an assumption that's implicit that it's
X509 certificate based and so this is a
bias that finds its way into the
specifications and it just it there's
nothing there's no normative text that
says it has to be X509 but the way that
the people are thinking their bias
towards X509 thinking and so that tends
to be an uphill battle as you
contemplate integrating you know KERI
concepts into this.
And so part of the initial investigation
that I did into this environment was to
look at well what would it take to
integrate vLEI authorization into a SATP
architecture.
And so I sketched out kind of how you
might do that. So we have we have the
sort of the standard GLEIF and QVI and
LLU entities represented and then we
have the within the domain the SAT
domain you have something I'm just
calling the SAT domain which is which
is whatever is the appropriate way to
identify that organization. So here I'
I've just coined the term
originator.acample.org
or beneficiary.acample.org
to just capture that idea. and
the point the point is it becomes an LEI
holder
and then there's the you know the O the
O and ECR entities those are also
represented now not you know these
these entities aren't aren't defined in
the architecture or in any of the
specifications but there is something
you know there is somebody that is
the CEO for example that can that you
know has the legal responsibility for
the asset and there is something that is
responsible for you know provisioning or
issuing credentials to the hosts.
And then on the on the on the asset
and then on the on the on the asset
side we basically have some
requirements. You think of these maybe
the legal requirements for the asset,
but the asset authority is
someone that you know has legal title or
ownership of the asset. They have the
right to disposition the asset or to
transfer it. It needs to be a
non-repud non-repudiable authorization.
And there's this notion of express
delegation and recorded disposition as
well as effective date and some other
legal requirements that have to be
met in order for this protocol to work.
But it's not defined yet in the in the
Set of specifications of how to do
that.
One other note is that from the
perspective lei that the actually the
hosts are not are not legal entities.
They're devices and there isn't the
notion of a an in the in lei there
isn't the notion of a credential that's
appropriate for a device. And so but
it could be anything. It could be a
certificate. There could be a did
but you could also have a KERI KEL as
the credential but it's not specified
in this you know there isn't anything in
the specification that says that it
can't be anything any of these but
like I said before there is an
assumption that it's probably a
certificate
all right so
how did so in 2023 this working group
was formed and the working
group kind of sat down and said okay
what do we want to work on what charter
should we bring to the working group and
Of course one suggestion was well
let's start with stage zero that's the
first part of the protocol u but it
became clear that people were not really
clear about what should be in stage zero
and so they said let's start where we're
least confused which was stage one. So,
the first set of protocols begin with
stage one. And I'm going to just briefly
walk through stage one, two, and three.
If you have questions, chime in. But
it's basically just kind of the it's the
easy part basically. but the
important aspect of stage one is there's
a there's sort of a handshake that says,
"Hey, I want to do a transfer." So you
propose your transfer and then the
the recipient then acknowledges the
request and then you begin the
transfer. Part of that proposal is to
provide all of the contextual
information necessary in order to
perform the asset exchange. And so what
you see here is a list of is a
snapshot of the transfer pro protocol
message and then kind of the body of
it which is the transfer claim which is
where all the ugly data shows up that
provides the context for the being able
to transfer the asset.
The interesting thing though is the
transfer context identifier is supposed
to be negotiated in stage zero but we
haven't defined it yet. So it's just a
placeholder,
a string. Trip means string.
Then there's these other things that are
showing up which refer to domain
bindings. So there's the verified
originator entity ID and the verified
beneficiary entity ID. These are strings
again undefined as to what is in the
string.
Then there's a bunch of information
about the context of the various
devices. And so there's the originator's
public key which presumably is there
to be able to verify the identity of
the originator. So you got the identity
the originator's identity plus the
originator's public key which can be
used to authenticate the identity.
And then there's some of the other
and then there's some of the other
entities here. So there's the gateway.
There's the network.
There's also you know identities and
and credentials for both the gateway,
the network and the identity. And then
down at the bottom there's this notion
of the owner
Which again which is not which is not
well defined but it asserts that
there is some entity within the
gateway that is the legal owner of the
asset.
So one of the in one of the recent
meetings that was sort of observed that
hey there's in this transfer nit
claim there's all of this information
but as we contemplate looking at stage
zero it seems like a lot of that
information already exists somewhere in
stage zero and do we need it all here
and so that's kind of setting the stage
for the next slide but basically
This my interest in this started with
a draft that I did called
Satpi binding and it's it's you
essentially populating some of these
values for with the assumption that
if I had if I had an infrastructure that
looked like KERI underneath what
would what would it you know how would I
integrate that and so that's
that was sort of the genesis of that
That draft
one of the other outcomes of doing the
draft was to define media types for the
various payloads that are CESR
specific. So it proposes
Additions to the Ayanna registry for
CESR payloads.
So moving on we have the H2 protocol
which is essentially locking. So before
we can actually do the exchange, we need
to before we can transfer the asset, we
need to lock the asset. So very simple
request response kind of locking. It's a
it's a you know not fine grain locking.
It's a global lock around everything.
And then we have a two-phase commit
protocol which includes in this the
notion of minting a new re a new re
asset in the in the beneficiaries domain
and burning or destroying the asset in
the sender domain.
All right. So there isn't this notion
of hey I transferred the asset. It's
just bookkeeping in some sense.
Right?
All right. So now the working group is
almost done with the specification
for the architecture and for the
protocols from stage zero to stage
three. They're in review by the working
group and the area. And the way that
the process works is when the working
group believes they're done with
something, they issue a last
call on the specs which basically says,
you know, that the period for
providing feedback is ending. Please,
you know give us give us your
feedback because we're going to then
move it to the next phase which is to
deliver it to the area directors and
then on to the u the what's called
the internet engineering
group. So, IESG is their
acronym. So what it means is
If all of those reviews are
successful then it will progress to RFC
status.
Okay.
So
Since they're kind of done with
The stages one through three they're
now rechartering to look at stage zero.
And then so in the context of that
what are the what are the objectives or
requirements for a stage zero portion
of the protocol. So one of the one of
the important aspects is that this
notion of a transfer context identifier
needs to be defined. What does it really
mean? What are the properties of an
identifier for the transfer context?
How do we represent asset
how do we represent asset
identification?
How do we represent asset ownership
and validation?
How do we represent the authorization
to transfer?
There's also the exchange of travel rule
requirements for in financial u
context where
It's basically saying how do we know
what information has to be included
in the transfer in order for the
appropriate context to be represented
equally on both sides.
How do you represent gateway ownership
and validate that? How do you
negotiate the transfer? There's also
information about the asset itself. You
know, how do you classify it? And
then there's something called mutual
attestation which is which is a
future requirement but it's essentially
saying we want to be able to get
information about the environments in
which the hosts operate to better
minimize or mitigate
Risks associated with potential
attackers.
So here's the stage zero protocol.
I'm not going to go through this in
huge detail but I want to draw your
attention to step one which is a request
to transfer a context and there's a
tokenized artifact record which is which
correlates to the part one of the token
that gets issued. So there's some
information in the token that is used to
to generate an identifier which we'll
call the transfer context ID.
And then there's a binding of the
transfer context ID to other assets. So
within the context of the domain,
there's could be a variety of digitized
artifacts that are off-chain or domain
specific that are tied to the
token in some way but not in the token.
So there's a binding step and then
there's a propagation step in step
four which is to say now that I have
this context for transferring an asset I
need to notify the beneficiary and
say hey I'm going to we're going to
we're going to progress with this
asset transfer.
So that happens in step four and
five. Step six is basically giving
the beneficiary the opportunity to bind
some of its assets to this exchange as
well. So we have the DR2 from the
beneficiaries side that's binding assets
and then it returns with its
propagate in the other direction to say
in the context of the current transfer
transfer context that we're exchanging
here are my attributes that I'm adding
and so what happens then in step
eight is we now have
we have the senders set of
assets, the beneficiary set of assets
and context and then we update the
registry with a with a with the transfer
context. So this is saying now that
we've established the context we're
going to make it persist in a registry.
And that happens in step 8B.
One thing to note is that
the registry doesn't have to be a
single registry. It doesn't have to be
in essence a trusted third party. It
could be separate registries. So
Network you know network one could have
network you know network one could have
its own choice of registries and network
2 could have a different choice of
registries. they would have the same
information in them because of the
protocol we've negotiated that but
they don't have to be the same registry.
the point I want to make here.
And then and then we go through the rest
of the stages one through three
transfer the asset. But then in
stage zero there's a step nine which is
sort of after the asset is exchanged
there's a finaliz message to the
registry that basically says yes the
whole thing happened correctly and
you know we're done with the with the
transfer.
So my observation here is that the stage
zero is a lot like an inception event
for an asset transfer.
And so I think some of the creative
thinking around this is to take a look
at the registry architecture in KERI
and say what can we you know leverage
from that architecture and in and to
influence the direction of this
SATP protocol in terms of the registry
design.
And then of course just by the way since
all of this since the registry contains
all of this state and context can we
simplify you know stage one protocol
like you take some of the information
out of there it seems bloated otherwise.
All right. So what are the desirable
properties of an artifacts registry?
This is not a complete list. This is
sort of current thinking and so there's
an opportunity now to influence where
this goes. And so if there are other
desirable properties we can we can
entertain adding them to the list or
working to have them added to the list.
U but the general sense it's append
only. This seems to align with
the assumptions that we make for
You know KERI logs and
transaction logs availability which is
to say hey I can have replicated
registries
you know we're not the spec is not
trying to limit
The structures in any way to prevent
prevent replication or redundancy
audit editability, canonical
preservation, we talked about that
durability
Which is database
Concept as well as
discoverability, domain isolation,
extensibility, privacy provenance
and verifiability. So these are all
you know the illities there may be
some others. So and they're open
to suggestions for what other
properties you think you need.
All right. So let's talk a little bit
about future of SATP. I mentioned
earlier that they are anticipating
in integrating of a tested hardware and
and context. So just a little bit to
observe the motivation for how that for
why that's important to them. So if you
think about it in an asset transfer, if
there's a failure
Early in the transfer, the cost of
recovery is much lower than if it
happens late in the transfer. So you get
this sort of u exponentially in
increasing cost curve as you progress
through that protocol.
And so one way to help to prevent
Failure is at least from the
perspective of you know attacks is to
introduce trusted platform hardware.
Well this idea of a trusted platform
blueprint which is has at its core a
trusted platform hardware component. So
the idea is think of the blueprint as
identifying a set of a set of you
know hardware, firmware, software,
system, software components that all
work together and can attest to their
nature
Using industry standard at
astation protocols.
So the blueprint says, hey, I've got
this trusted environment and I can prove
to you that it's a trusted environment.
So some of the properties of this are I
have a hardware isolated execution
environment. So my gateway runs within
this you know environment that is
walled off or sealed off hardened
against a variety of different attacks.
So that's a preventative approach.
the hardware that's built on top of
isolated containers or what's called
confidential container technology
That a lot of the vendors are
providing. So it turns out that all of
the major silicon binder vendors are
are supplying to the market their you
know acronym soup of confidential
container technology. Question
how much do I got left? Well, but
then you have there's a window of time
for people to transition out.
Okay.
okay.
Sorry.
All right.
So I got I'm almost done. So we got
about 10 minutes it looks like. So
important in point here is the industry
is building you know hardware supported
isolated execution and they ex the IETF
expects for things like SATP gateways to
run in those kinds of environments.
And then and so further down there's
something called attestable hardware
root of trust and something called dice.
This dice is technology that I've worked
on personally. I'm one of the primary
authors of the dice specifications
in the industry and all of the major
industry players have adopted dice. So
Nvidia, ARM, AMD, Intel and then
standards organizations like the TCG and
OCP have all built around the
notion of a dice hardware route to
trust. So it isn't it isn't you know
vendor it isn't that you have a
variety of different technologies based
on different vendors. They're all
working to have a common open hardware
representation for hardware rooted
trust.
So what is atestation? This is maybe the
most you know abbreviated you know
part explanation of addestation that
I've done. But basically in a nutshell
The way addestation works is to
improve risk management. You think of
it from this perspective of this sort of
flow of information. You have like the
SATP gateway which is the atttor.
It's providing evidence to an
addistation verifier who produces a
result which is an assessment of how
trustworthy the platform is and then the
SAT bait SATP gateway which is the
the you know the beneficiary or the
which is another which is referred
to as the relying party in this
architecture writes their information to
the attribute registry. So in addition
to all the other stuff that we went
through in the protocol in the registry,
there's also device addestation
information that then could be used by
Along with the other information in
the transfer context used by an actuary
to make an assessment of what the risk
is that's associated with this asset
transfer. And if you think about, you
know, how value that could be is
whenever there's an asset, whenever
whenever you're transferring asset,
there's risk of something going wrong
and you know, who's responsible for
for compensating
something goes wrong. So, chances are in
large amounts, you know, high value
asset transfers, there's going to be an
actuary there that's providing some sort
of compensating transaction to offset
the risk.
Okay, so
last slide. What are the opportunities
for SATP that are sort of essentially
KERI aware? I think there's three of
them. One is what does it mean to have a
KERI enabled trusted platform? So you
might say, hey, one of those layers
should be like the KERIpy library.
And we might take a look at the KERI
controller and say shouldn't shouldn't
the you know the hardware route of trust
and the low in the very and the layers
that are sort of at the fundamental end
bottom end of this stack be KERI
capable such that when a verifier is
verifying not only not only the you know
the car the KERI related
information but also the device
certificates and so forth that are that
are behind the add a station that
that you know verify that
that the infrastructure associated
with those credentials are also
you know KERI enabled
So that's one thing another is the is
so that's one thing another is the is
enabling the artifacts registry with
ACDC technology so we've already if you
if you're attending Sam's talk on the on
the earlier here this week on the
registry architecture. You notice
that there was an there was the
notion of a of a
a set of what I what I would think of
as the you know the witness
watcher pattern associated there which
is to say I could have a registry
which is I could have a bifurcated
registry where one registry is
acting on the on the behalf of the
gateway way one and then another one is
acting on behalf of gateway 2.
and then the third one is the lei
enabled asset transfer. So, so this is
builds on work that I've already started
in that sense where you know
essentially what's what we need to
do here is define how to provision
the other SATP hosts like the
gateway and the network and so forth
with KERI credentials
and so we can have a you know an
entire hierarchy that's built around the
the KERI credential and the VI a
ecosystem.
So that's it. Any questions?
So do you think let's say hypothetically
I'm being brought in with a group of
advisors to advise on a capp trade
program where they're looking to have
the emissions allowances in a digital
form. There are some groups advocating
for a tokenized blockchain based
approach. There's me arguing for ACDC
life. This country is interested in
having a liquid market because
allowances could be traded for, you
know, if you can reduce your emissions
more, you can sell your allocations
to others who cannot. So, they need to
buy the market. Could this potentially
help facilitate a market for
trading and represent allowances?
Yeah, the major motivation was the
observation that hey, there's a bunch
of,
you know, blockchains out there, they're
all proprietary in a sense that they
have different consensus algorithms and
different formats and whatever. But you
need to people want it to move their
coin or their tokens from one to one
network to the other and there's no you
know industry standard way to do that.
So SATP was designed with that
motivation at heart. So if a cap trade
is try is trying to essentially move one
kind of asset from one kind of
blockchain to another kind of blockchain
and maybe backwards the other way. then
that's just an asset exchange
which is just a which is an extension of
the asset transfer. You just do another
asset transfer in the other direction
and then it's an exchange.
But I so I think it would work. It's
there's no design I don't see any
design goals that would prevent it from
working but that particular use case
might not be in the forefront of the
minds of the designers.
Yeah, it's probably not.
Yeah. So,
so I have a question.
Yeah. So the bias toward X519 is there
any sense in the community that
that the risk of the security
vulnerabilities of X509 are materially
problematic for
just
so the question is given the bias
towards X509 is there any sense of the
problematic aspects of using X509 in the
forefront of the minds of the various
other designers? And the answer is no. I
don't think they thought about it.
Okay.
Right. So that's a conversation that
will come up in the context of stage
zero discussion.
So it's a it's a great timing for this
group to engage with that effort. That's
what it boils down to.
We're having conversations with
the certificate authority about
integrating VI into group certificates.
Would that make this implementation
easier if the actual certificate was
there was being added if you still
needed to be integrated down to the
gate? So it would make it easier if
somehow the working group decided that
they didn't need to do the extra work to
allow
Extensibility where extensibility is
needed on the credential type because
right now there's some you know
high-level wording and then some precise
examples based on
something in the middle that says Hey,
this credential structure is
extensible and here's how you extend it
and here's how you say that it's a
different type of credential and here's
the type
and that's something that I'm trying to
get in there but they said no you're not
going to do it in stage one it's already
it's already working group last call
right but like I said there are stage
two stage zero might say well we're
going to put all that information into
the registry and so all you really need
is