Okay,
it is 3:15. So 3:16 now.
So I'm going to get started.
Welcome everyone to my second talk.
It's going to be a lot less complicated.
I can tell you that because I don't want
to delve into any of that anymore. We're
just going to talk about the history of
Key State. We're going to talk about our
philosophy investing in the trust
spanning layer, what it's been like to
be at the ground floor and pushing it
forward going forward into the future.
So, yeah, we've been here six years.
We've got a partner right over here,
we've got a partner right over here,
Will Dalquist. Thank you for making it.
And this is a field report about,
you know, what we've done in this space.
And thank you all for being here,
everyone who's been part of our journey
from the beginning.
Okay, so the idea really is simple. Evan
and I actually had a conversation about
this earlier. Capital creates
reality.
It's it's pretty profound when you think
about it, but it can simply be said that
when you place money in something you
believe in, you bring that thing from
the future into the present. And
when we saw KERI, when we found Sam
out of the wreckage of the sovereign
debacle,
We saw a future that was worth
believing in. And it w it was
profound.
So, so yeah, this we're going to
talk about the rest.
All right. And so this is the protocol
moment like what is KERI, right? Every
internet wave needed a protocol layer
first. The identity layer is being built
now into the open under the name KERI.
And the protocol is not a product. It is
a service
public service. Every wave of the
internet value needed this protocol. It
starts with TCP IP. It emerges with
HTTP and URL. Then we have SSL and TLS.
And finally, we have really the epitome
of security in the internet as we know
it in the form of KERI. Right? In this
we're making trust portable and the
operators are being funded right now in
this room.
So yeah, what is KERI for those that
don't know? It's a self-certifying
identifier that travels
cryptographically verifiable, portable
across jurisdictions, rotatable without
losing history. The protocol is stable,
the governance is real, and both are
open.
So
in essence right when we first started
There was this is really just a spec.
Sam came out with a white paper which
was had every bit of the ingredients
that needed to establish the trust
spanning layer but no one had yet out
built out the essential infrastructure.
And when we started actually and
Timothy Ruff thank you for introducing
us. We got pitched the idea of
Provenant. Provident was a an idea
in the mind of Randy Warshaw. He wanted
to bring verifiable communications
natively to SMS, RCS, calling, VO vice
IP, etc. And it's only now six years
later finally coming to fruition for
example. And so, Provenant is one of
these three levers that we have in
the KERI ecosystem,
right? Oh, sorry. This is more the
philosophy of it. Excuse me. All right.
So, the three actual approaches we
want to take in terms of deciding what's
actually investable are the following.
The first is industry adoption. You have
to identify a vertical which distinctly
can be owned by the company we are
bringing into reality. Right? And then
the second is actually technical
development. We want unique features
that's only possible to be created in
KERI that no one else has created
before. And then finally we want to
emphasize the human talent emphasizing
humor human resources that we can
attract to actually make this real.
So you need all these three things. If
you have tech without industry, you
essentially just have nice theory,
right? There's nothing to apply to. you
can't help anyone's problems and you
just have nothing to fund. If you have
industry without tech, you essentially
have synergy, synergy, synergy. You
choose logo and you can't ship
integration and you lose the edge. And
if you have both of these, but you don't
have the right human resources, you
essentially have a beautiful idea that
completely flames out. I've seen this
personally where visions of really
advanced technical ideas pushing forward
proof of work. For example, I' I visited
New Zealand twice to fund a specific
company that was pushing the edge of
what was possible in blockchain, but the
team just wasn't right. They had the ear
of the New Zealand government but they
could not bring it home because the
leader did not have the appropriate
direction to anchor in real economic
realities. So right now within our
strategy we've identified three key
roots of trust. The first is GSMA.
And within each one of these entities
and within each one of these entities
we've actually funded, we really want to
direct them to actually colonize and
leverage the trust that a root of trust
has within a given ecosystem. So the
GSMA route within telco is a clear
showstopper, right? When you have a
phone number that's verifiable, that
means you have an UBY introduction at
your fingertips and that KERI is not
just a figment of the internet. It
actually starts to span multiple
different communication layers. So, it's
a great utility there. Secondly,
as well, we have direct trust and vital
alliance being emphasized by healthcare.
Vital initiative.
Oh,
yeah.
Was that changed?
Direct trust.
Okay. Okay. Vital initiative. Excuse me.
So essentially right direct trust
leading this we're Jared and team are
well maybe Jared do you want to speak
about it a bit?
Yeah well I'll tell you the thing that I
found most interesting about the work
we're doing with
trust is how analous it is to work
obviously there's there's industry
but
If you think about certain
evolutionary tactics in nature, there
are different paths like lobsters and
crabs and claws. They don't have the
same ancestor, but they came to the same
use case at the end of it.
Well, you kind of do have the same
ancestor
in the same room, but it wasn't like I
ever worked with randings and how are
you guys tackling problem in your
industry, which I think gives stronger
validation to both missions.
The way that you win with a B2B focused
KERI play is to go from the
regulators, the standard bears in the
industry and convert them to the project
and then they will bring the rest of the
industry into
right. I mean I say this a lot. I
think, you know, the goal for me is
promoting harmony within different
investments in our ecosystem. We want
canopy shyness. So, you know, Provident
doesn't tread on healthcare's toes.
Healthcare doesn't tread on a yet
unnamed third company. We're going to
fund in defense's toes. I can't wait to
bring you all to show off this next
team. They're going to be fantastic.
But yeah, and the idea is really getting
but yeah, and the idea is really getting
back to those previous principles. you
know, we have this beautiful network
effect in the form of KERI. We can
share in the things we build, the
learnings we have. But P and you
could even hunt together, but what you
catch is what you catch, right? We want
independent revenue streams that are
coni converting independent users and
adding to the overall network effect of
KERI as VC it. Which builds into
also our final route of trust which
would be the SEDI state endorsed digital
identity. Now that we have
organizational identity via the VI and
personal identity endorsed by the
state of Utah, we have both ends of what
essentially amounts to a trust
ecosystem. I think we can actually start
Really creating new trust services
that previously weren't weren't
possible.
So yeah, let's go first into
Provident. This was the hardest.
We had to break really tough ground. It
was there was like in Texas, right? I
actually was born in love, Texas, right?
And the Spanish actually colonized
that and they called it Yano Estacado,
which means the stake plains. And
the reason why they called it is because
there was this thin layer and by thin
it's like several inches thick of
capstone that covered the entire
west. And so breaking through that
capstone is tough. But once you did, you
could put a stake in the ground and know
that it would be there in perpetuity.
And for us, proven was exactly that.
We've been hammering down on this
stake for like literally six years now
and with GSMA we finally have it in the
ground.
So you know building out open
verifiable communications
was did not just come overnight. You
know, initially we actually thought we
were gonna have an exit within a year,
right?
And the reason being is that we had a
and the reason being is that we had a
precedent, right? Timothy Ruff had come
just recently out of Credential Master
selling to Salesforce. A beautiful exit
within nine months, wasn't it?
18.
18. Oh, okay. Okay. Sorry. Excuse me.
But there was a really quick turnaround.
And so a lot of the members of key state
itself actually thought, okay, great. we
we'll just have we'll do the same play.
We're going to appeal to one of these
regulatory bodies that needs the
services Provenant is bringing and
they'll snap us up and we'll have a nice
turnaround. But it didn't turn out that
way. So we actually had to pivot our
expectations on what Provenant was into
a much deeper technical play in
colonizing the GSMA root of trust.
And really also we funded it quite
and really also we funded it quite
heavily but they also had not only to
pierce telecom but they also had to
build the first QVIS the first wallets
the first means of
I'm sorry
you don't mean to interrupt but I'll
just add a comment when you have a break
right I mean just go ahead
so think about provident as often
happens with startups and by the way the
co-founder the co-founder of credential
sitting back there in the corner, Allan.
And you know, we went from zero to
exit in less than two years, which was
amazing. But if that was your
expectation
well, with
Well, yeah, we and this was a naive
expectation. I'm being quite honest with
you, actually.
But Provident pivoted twice.
That's right.
Provident piv pivoted from original
telecom focus to thinking that being the
world's first QVI was a business.
Yep. It wasn't.
Y
it was a good thing. It was an important
thing. They broke important ground
business
and then pivoting back to telecom.
Yep.
And it's it's dangerous and hard
and some investor to make pivots
and some investors will evaluate a
startup as to whether they've made any
pivots and if they haven't that they
haven't been listening to the market.
I actually don't think that's quite
right. I think that they did know they
they did pivot away from oh my
goodness this is failing me but
anyways but they did pivot from their
first approach but when they had to
become the first QVI it was a necessary
step they had to take to actually
convince the regulators that existed
about the legitimacy of the VI and
essentially the leverage to convince
them to use KERI
that and I'm in agreement with that the
pivot was where they would make money
the Ah, that's right.
They thought there would be a business
in one place, pivoted to that.
Yeah.
Decided it was and decided to pivot away
from the business model.
That's right. That's right. Cool.
Thanks.
So, yeah, exactly. And going into
this, they had to build alongside their
product wallet infrastructure VI and the
f the first QVI. They had to build
Java SDKs to for KERI these pie
libraries to be usable. And then
ultimately what amounted to the
verifiable voice protocol which is what
OBC itself is using to have branded
calling verifiable branded calling.
So and telecom as an industry is a
pretty substantially in need of what
KERI provides. You're seeing a 25%
decline year-over-year from 2024 to 2025
in terms of SMS trust. 72% of us
consumers, including myself, I don't
answer phone calls that I don't
recognize. I'm sure. Do if you guys
get a phone call that you don't
recognize, do you answer it?
Only if it's from China.
Okay. Okay. They might have a cookie for
you. You never know.
So, so really it says to how much
this public utility has been abused and
how much it needs a trust infrastructure
like KERI. There's 80 billion in
fraud losses in 2025 and start
shaking as well was just insufficient.
It's built on X509 based
infrastructure. It's not enough to
actually solve the problem of spam. Mr.
spam guy here is nodding his head in
approval. Yeah.
Cool. So now let's go to healthcare.
So healthcare was actually our second
so healthcare was actually our second
investment.
We Sam came to us. He said hey I've got
we Sam came to us. He said hey I've got
a brilliant proposal. Philheler is
going to be the CTO. Jared Jeffrey is
going to be the CEO and we're going to
take healthc care headon. I mean and
Jared maybe you could talk about it.
What was your initial expectation
founding healthcare? What were your
thoughts there?
Well, we've pivoted. We're on our third.
Right.
Right. So, we were wrong twice. I think
we'll probably come back to some of
those concepts later.
But one of the things that we
initially thought was
that the
the pain of insecurity in this industry
would be sufficient to drive adoption of
new technology. What we found very
quickly was the industry gives a whole
lot of lip service
to this issue of patient harm by
way of cyber security. And in the
boardroom that all goes to
right
and so for
us as we kind of initially started this
I was like well I believe that can solve
this problem.
I know that we have but Ive always the
expectations of my team to know that
listen healthare runs on cold glasses
the industry moves very slow
technologies and that gets worse when
you're talking about technologies that
identity
do you think do you think and this
just occurred to me actually the notion
of data loyalty could actually whip
these guys into shape
so yes probably
it's it's going to be a long to get them
to fight on something like that, it
would have to be forced.
Well, well, but that's what I mean.
Enforced from STI from SEDI down,
regulators down.
Yeah. It would have to be regulatory,
right?
Well, well, anyways. Oh, sorry. Go
ahead. See I spent years a few more
understanding
the issue is the consumer
of what to ask for
unless that really gets in front
You don't know what to ask for
push these companies to move that
fast
right which is why I think the data
loyalty framework network if applied
could actually incentivize right.
Yeah. What happened to the data by
right? How much of privacy to give up
between just two weeks of March 2020?
Just look at that before during after.
Sure.
So if you go through those parameters
and understand how people are
interacting and secondly how fragmented
the digital touch points are.
That's another area to look into and say
okay where is the where is the
commonality getting in where is the
critical mass? These are all critical
inputs because even if you look at from
their angle the digital engagements has
been completely different.
So there is opportunity here but it
comes with letting the consumer know
what to ask.
Very good feedback. Thank you. I
appreciate that. Well that aside,
excuse me for bringing us off track.
Bringing this back healthcare. So, we're
bringing this back healthcare. So, we're
still high on the on Proven,
contributing to Provenant. There's a lot
of liquidity milling around in the
macroeconomic space. So, we place with
healthcare as well. Jared, like Jared
said, you had to pivot several times. I
think Jared epitomizes actually a
tenacity that I think is admire
admirable because the amount of funding
we actually gave Jared as opposed to
Provenant was marketkedly less. And I
think what they've done to produce is
is substantially more proportional to
the amount of capital that we've
actually contributed. So Jared is an
exemplary u showcase of what a founder
should be like in order to survive tough
times and we'll we'll go over like what
I learned from that later. So yeah
healthcare just the overview quantum
ready fish proof network security for
healthcare data layer. You've got
production watchers, you've got
witnesses, you've got cryptographically
signed and transit gateways. The
vertical is healthcare obviously the
layer is like an overlay essentially and
the idea is to sign every transaction.
so again they built production
witnesses you have watchers at the ed
edge intransit gateways and as well I
mean the Locksmith the Locksmith
stack that Phil has demonstrated several
times is extensive. This is a full end
toend credential life cycle management
For the healthcare ecosystem.
And can I just put a comment on that
one? One of the questions that Phil got
a couple of times he's been demoing the
the wallet is the question of do you
think this is going to be the end UI for
the wallet? And the answer is no.
Absolutely not. Right.
But we can't worry about UI challenges
until this exists. So part of the reason
we put that into the open source is
because I mean I'm I'm operating on a on
a on a very
resource constraint
shoestring budget is what he means.
We produce we produce because we focus
on the things that matter most. Right.
Right.
So part of the reason we put that into
open source understanding that right now
the UI is very KERI developer oriented
is to invite this community to come
together and say okay let's do the UI
work on this right let's make this thing
sing for all the different use cases
that will exist in the ecos
so do you do you think that the UI
itself has substantially been
influenced by the more you learn about
KERI as time goes on
so yes and no I think really what we
found is
as we grow we need to hide KERI to
everyone
so that for them it feels like
everything else that they're used to. I
so during Seni conference Phil's
demonstration of how to log into a payer
portal with Senn
Yep. I don't actually think that any
of the legislators that watched that
presentation had any idea the magic that
was happening there. And that was by
design, right? We wanted them to look at
this and we wanted them to say, "Yeah, I
logged in with Google this exact same
way."
Cool.
Exactly. Perfect. So all of that to
say that the stuff that we put
into the open source, the watchers,
the witnesses, the wallet is an
invitation. It's an open invitation to
the industry to say go build on top of
this. We've given you the
production ready code to go pay
attention
and didn't you also have several
feedback from
potential customers and adopters of your
technology that they wouldn't even adopt
the technology if it wasn't open source.
Yeah. So, so
one of the things that everyone in,
Entrepreneurship, particularly tech,
has to contend with now is that the
stock standard mode of defensibility for
companies has completely dissolved in
the last year. And it used to be that
you were going to stand a proprietary
code, you would get a patent on those
things, and then you would basically
rent off of that patent with your code.
Claude makes that completely
useless.
I have watched videos of people just
walking through the UI of a platform
with an AI agent and the agent can then
on the back end code that for you.
Absolutely. This defensible mode of
the last 20 years is no more. Which
means I think that you need to find
other modes. And in so doing, the
code that you used to hold on to so
dearly now becomes only valuable if you
put it into open source and let the
community let the not the AI brain but
the human brain and collective make that
code more valuable. J Jared's pointing
at something very essential that
key state understood getting into this
that most of this these funds that we
put into these companies would be going
to open source development, right? And
there's there's a fine balance, right?
Not everything should be open source.
There's a time and a place for IP to
there's a time and a place for IP to
be leveraged.
Yeah. Our gateways are not open source.
Right.
Right. And exactly like the open
source is to invite people to
participate in the ecosystem and you can
provide what is uniquely yours on top.
Right.
Just wanted to follow up to that source
code is not patentable. It's
copyrightable.
Sorry. Yeah.
It's a it's a big difference.
I think I think you are the foremost
authority in making that declarative
statement. Anyway, the issue is
that's how open source works is by
copyright,
right?
Because since you assert the
copyright, you can decide what to do
with it.
Sure. And it depends on the license you
use for said copyright, right?
Well, yeah, that's your choice.
Yeah, exactly.
But you're ass you're asserting
ownership in order to give it away. But
you have to assert the ownership first.
Mhm.
I want to throw something out in an
assertion that I would love to have
challenged if someone disagrees with it
and it's about where open source is
appropriate and where capturing IP is
appropriate where the line is and I
think there's actually a new line a new
bright line because of AI
and I think it's bright
and let me just throw it out there as an
idea
and that is if your
Code your protocol is something that
you need multiple parties to adopt.
There's an issuer holder verifier or
there's two sides. If it's a two side,
if it's multi-sided at all,
I don't think there's a choice anymore.
But you have to open source
from strategic necessity.
Otherwise, you're trying to be the
platform, what I call EUM. Everybody use
me and I will be in the middle and
everybody use me to be the bridge of
everything. But that's only if it's
multi-sided.
I think it's 180 degrees different if
it's single-sided.
I think if you do not protect
your architecture, you copyright
code, but you can patent architecture,
right? So, you can patent architecture
and if you if it's single-sided
architecture
and you do not patent it, you're going
to be destroyed in a New York minute by
every AI copier that there's just it's
too easy for them to just take it and do
it. And I used to feel that everything
was open source and make fun of
everything IP,
right? But now I'm starting a company to
take advantage of the setting momentum
and I started doing product design and I
invented something and I'm like, "Holy
cow, this is single-sided. If I come to
market with this product without any IP,
I'm going to get exploded in a minute."
And so I just defensively apologies to
you, Steve, because I've been I've been
criticizing you for your very pro-IP
perspective, but I realize the
distinction. It's whether it's a
single-sided product or multi-sided.
Multi-sided, open source, single-sided,
you got to you got to patent it any way
you can or you're going to get raped as
soon as it gets public.
Robert,
yeah, just a question to your challenge,
and I'm not saying it's either way, but
would you say the FICO score has to be
open source now since that's proprietary
yet multiple sides?
No, it's singlesided. Each one of those
score each one of those credit rating
authorities has their own proprietary
way of doing it single-sided to them in
their own environment. That's why they
keep it proprietary.
I guess
that's why there's three. If it was open
source, everyone would use the same one,
but they each have a proprietary one.
That's a good example,
Steve.
So, let me follow on to answer your
question, but I agree with Timothy.
We agree.
Yes.
But the issue is the reason
it's good to have KERI open source is
because your goal is uniform adoption
right
multi-sided
you yes multi-sided I'm just trying
to put it in a different language that
you want everybody to use it because
then you become interoperable
that's right
and that's different than coming up
with secret sauce to do something
and you want to keep that protected. And
so both the app world and the open-
source world are indispensable
tools. We use a different time.
Right. Exactly. The timing matters and
to what degree.
So, and honestly, it's it's still
something that I think we're working on
in terms of our understanding, but
Jared and the healthcare team, I think,
have the right approach. A lot of this a
lot of this sort of steady support for
example with the watchers the witnesses
The wallets it needs this level of
open- source licensing to allow for
that network effect to propagate and
again we knew we knew that coming in
that this was going to be a little bit
of this sort of allowing the fruits
of our labor to be freely appreciated.
So yeah, I on healthcare in particular
To speak on what the opportunity was.
If breaches were a contest, healthcare
would be numero uno. The third party
ransomware origin is pretty
extensively documented. There's hundreds
of millions of US patient healthcare
records stolen. And the most serious
of attacks actually affect real life
care environments. Jared, I think
didn't we have the first case of someone
dying from ransomware?
There have been a number of cases where
they said this probably was because of
ransomware. This last year BBC
finally put out an article and said,
"No, no, we can clearly state that
this person died to the hospital they
were supposed to go to but couldn't."
Y,
they would have survived. So,
yes, rans and it's it's worse than that.
Most of these attacks are not
individuals looking
Most of these attacks are nation state
actors that look at healthcare as a
critical infrastructure.
It's the
well and this is a key thing as
well. One of the big and we're going
to talk about macroeconomics in a bit.
One of the big investment thesises
that's emerging as we speak is defense.
Right? We are literally as we're in
World War II right now. It's not
completely physical. It's not ballistic
necessarily. It's more information based
state-based actors have been performing
these attacks I don't for decades now I
mean North KERI Iran classic examples
this is not just like fanning the fear
flames but it's actually these are real
outcomes that we have to protect against
So here's a table so to speak of sort
of where the capital has been moved
it's not that great okay we still have
some gaps that we've identified. I
think we're addressing the wallets at
the edge with Locksmith in particular. I
want to see more use cases emerge that
feature wallets and credentials being
used in production. I honestly I
think the gap in supply chain is
massive. Verifiable Trade Foundation
Led by Stefon Wolf has been
spearheading this sort of approach now
for three years now. Yeah. ever since
Stephan Wolf left GLEIF and what
they're building to will be a
multi-billion dollar opportunity. It
just needs to be realized and the
problem of verifiable bills of leading
is one in particular that's quite hairy.
Getting that recognized across
different domains of trust. And so
and then again having capital allotments
to future SEDI initiatives is something
that will open the floodgates for
startups and also KERI as a whole.
So US Utah is just the start.
so US Utah is just the start.
So yeah we're going to go into what
this taught us.
Again when we first started most of
again when we first started most of
the members of KState Capital were very
Assetrich. We the crypto boom had
just finished in 2020. We were like
we're sitting on our laurels. We have
this incredible technology in form of
KERI and we actually did not properly
allocate resources in a way that was
considering the fact that this flood of
capital was going to subside and it did.
It did in a way that was substantial.
We're talking about an order of
magnitude less capital available just in
terms of depreciation of assets and
how we allocated risk. For me that's
unacceptable going forward. It's not
something that I can do for myself, I
can't do it for my family, I can't do it
for my founders and the industry
as a whole. When capital actually
creates opportunities and we're
allocating capital irresponsibly, it
creates danger for our entire ecosystem.
So, we need to actually have a means of
measuring
the risks we take in an appropriate
fashion. Another thing that I we've
learned is that before the contract is
set, no one's your friend. I mean, it's
really easy, especially when you're in
These sort of highly intellectual
pursuits where you have to share
ideas in order to validate and verify
their authenticity. But when
you're in a business negotiation, all
all hats are off. It's a matter of
survival in many ways. and you two are
feeling each other out in real time as
to the integrity of each one. And so
that respect is established in the
negotiation process. If you can't stand
up for yourself and have the Timothy
says the crucial conversations,
then there is just no basis of trust.
And when the dolge becomes the
desert, then people are pointing
fingers. You're like, why is this
happening? There's a lot of confusion.
and you don't have a relationship that
can actually stand the test of time. So
a lesson there
knowing our founders. So this is
something that I've really learned
personally. I have. It's amazing how
distinct every single one of our
entrepreneurs are and understanding
their nuances, understanding what makes
them tick, understanding the their
strengths and their weaknesses both
while you're evaluating and also after
you've placed capital. I mean, you don't
just go away after you place money.
Having equity in a company means being
part of that company, right? If you're
not actively contributing to the value
generating process, and it doesn't have
to be on the you're not boots on the
ground necessarily selling this stuff,
but you can open opportunities, you can
introduce new capital. And you
can learn how to speak with your
founders. Communication is so key. And
so maintaining that dialogue and
checking in and keeping things
accountable is the way we've kept this
ship afloat, right? We've kept this
thing on track. So whenever something is
needed, we always have an ability to
call each other and that's essential. So
knowing your founders, communicating.
So and we heard this like two distinct
so and we heard this like two distinct
times. So obviously you invest to allow
people to create something new, but you
cannot be attached necessarily to the
first iteration of that vision. You have
to be able to pivot what you've created
and formed an emotional attachment with
when you get enough signals from the
marketplace that you're not going to
make it or this is not working right.
So essentially when you have creativity
so essentially when you have creativity
without flexibility it's just an
attachment and this is sorry go ahead
Jared
say one of the things that I one of
my mantras is that creation is a
destructive process
by virtue of creating you will tear down
and try again
creation is a destructive process
right to make an omelet you got to break
a few
classic.
And finally, I think the key thing is
patience. When you have a vision for
something that is special, when you've
you've tested it and you know it's true,
you've done what you can. Having the
wisdom to know
when not to do things, when to just wait
for things to mature over time, and to
let your founders do what they do best,
I think is the key. We're only
just now after five years of investing,
seeing fruits from this labor. And I
think it's going to be accelerated
growth. I think we're in our teenage
years, so to speak. So and we'll see
how far you know our core
companies go but I think being
patient is one of the best virtues you
can have as an investor.
So and these are the three principles
I'm looking at right identifying the
right market
finding the right technical ecosystem
and then having the right team. And
so when you have all these three things,
you have a recipe for success, I
think, in terms of finding a an
investable opportunity in this space.
So we've been funding the teams from the
front lines. We're seeing that KERI
becoming the trust spanning layer of the
internet. And the job is to keep
filling in the gaps, recruiting new
roots of trust and
sharpening our filter, making sure that
we can understand what is a good
founder, what is a bad founder, a good
opportunity, a bad opportunity, and so
on and so forth. So we're still
looking for investable opportunities. If
you have any, please come my way.
I'll give you a card and we'll talk.
So, thank you all for your time.
Right.
You work with other
try and help them understand what the
the import of the digital
identity ecosystem is. What are some of
the biggest things that you hear in
terms of reticence to invest? Like how
do you like what are the you hear from
other investors when you bring to them
identity based deals like
well I think the uncertainty the
technical barrier is big having an
ability to communicate what this is in
plain language to someone that isn't
technical is one of the biggest up what
one of the biggest barriers I think
also
liquidity is it's an unconscious
limiting factor in a lot of this right
right now we have it's not the best time
to raise I mean, if you have a if you
have adoption, if you have proven
revenue streams, you can raise, but
it's this is not a zero interest rate
environment any longer, right? So, I
think a lot of this comes down to trust.
You have to build a relationship
actually with the person you're
introducing the idea to. If someone
knows that you're a smart guy, they
trust you. They may not know what you're
talking about. They may not know what a
key rotation is, what a KEL is any
of this stuff, but if they have your
trust, then I think you can convince
them to place. And that's how
literally what it comes down to. But
what's up, Will?
Yeah, I was going to add to that for
Jared's question here, too. From my
experience, conversations and trying to
persuade investors to take a leap into
this industry and this ecosystem, the
largest hesitation has been
just the vast scope of the problem that
is trying to be addressed and solved and
convincing them that of the idea that
there is a technology there is a plat or
a protocol y
that has the ability to address that
issue that they see as just almost you
know unsolvable
right or they just presume that it's
always going to be this way
and then there are so many others trying
to do it
right
the fact that there are so many that
have tried and failed or have
tried and succeeded at various levels,
you know. So, that's been the largest
amount of hesitancy that I've seen.
Okay.
So, two
two questions that probably are related,
but you know, a lot of times you
know, investors during a pitch or
whatever will ask about exit strategy.
Yeah.
Right. Meaning when are they going
to get paid back as an investor
basically,
right? and you know this is the
kind of bet that you know may take a
while to pay off.
Exactly.
Investor perspective and so be
interested in your color on that. And
then the other one especially you
know perhaps with healthcare and proven
that are starting to gain some traction.
It's not going to be too long before
they're looking for a rounds.
Yes.
And so how do you see your role in
helping secure a rounds?
Well I think one of the one of the
interesting things that
You know, in a traditional equity
market, exit is a binary, right? You
either have an exit or you're waiting
for one. You can be bought out. In
private markets,
also a valid exit.
Not really, honestly. Dividends are a
bad, they're a poor choice. Every time
you take a dividend, you're taking away
from the reinvestment opportunity of the
company to actually push it forward.
Going public is a long shot, right, for
many companies. So, what is what do you
look for an exit strategies pitch?
No. No, no, too many.
Well, well, in this case, it's like just
building as much value as you possibly
can as an acquisition target is
smart. I think there's a lot of
potential innovations we can actually
leverage around
tokenized revenue
That I think are fascinating. Right?
In this case, if you actually have
market adoption in terms of
infrastructure that has a longterm
productive yield and that's that's an
asset and if you can actually sell that
up front, right,
you can have
liquidity without necessarily having an
exit, right? And I think within five
years there will be plenty of these sort
of new sort of levers that companies can
actually pull that previously they would
never even dream of doing, right? So I
think it's going to be less of a binary
thing and more of a it'll be more of
a liquidity friendly equity
investment market.
Okay.
But that's that's that's out of
my scope. I don't know whether or not
that's coming.
And then with the A round, if you have a
just a thought or we can take this
offline if we're out of time. I'll
get back to you on that.
Okay, cool.