Phil Feairheller ｜ Infrastructure for Security ｜ Keri Conference 2026
Hi everyone. Thanks for showing up
today. My name, for those of you who
don't know me, is Phil Feairheller and
the CTO and co-founder of healthKERI.
We are specializing in bringing KERI
technology, as the name would suggest,
into healthcare, in particular data
exchange in healthcare to help
facilitate trust across the healthcare
ecosystem. I realized I forgot a intro
slide, so I'm just doing it without a
slide.
So, in my job, I end up teaching KERI
very often to a lot of different people,
in particular people who have never even
heard of it before. Sometimes maybe
they've heard of PKI, sometimes they've
heard of X.509s, but they've never heard
of KERI. And this is one of my favorite
slides to teach KERI because it starts
at the very bottom of the layers that
make KERI the security protocol that it
is. And when Sam first asked me to do
this talk on KERI infrastructure, I
immediately thought of this slide
because the infrastructure that I'm
going to talk about is very clearly
spelled out in the layers of security
that make up the KERI stack. So, I
won't do the whole spiel that I usually
do for this, but very quickly, starting
at the bottom of the self-certifying
identifiers and CESR, for folks that
who know PKI, I always like to say that
KERI solves the two hard problems of
PKI. One is creating a cryptographic
binding between the identifier and the
first set of keys, and the second hard
problem it solves is key rotation,
creating the cryptographic binding to
every other set of keys. And we are able
to do that with CESR, which is our
encoding format for exchanging
cryptographic primitives at scale.
So, the next layer up is pre-rotation
Key Event Logs. Already touched on what
pre-rotation is, and the Key Event Logs
are of course the data structure,
append-only data structure that allows
us to communicate changes in our key
state that anyone else in the world can
verify without ever having to phone
home. Layer three delegation distributed
group multisig,
that is something that we only talk to I
only talk to when I'm dealing with more
advanced audiences, talking about
KERI's ability to do delegation both at
the identifier level as well as
attenuated delegation with ACDC
credentials and distributed group
multisig is one of the more fun
technologies in KERI. I love working
with it. I love building it when we were
at GLEIF, but we don't really dig too
much into it. And so then if you think
about what I'm going to talk about
today, the wallets and then the watchers
and the witnesses, the first three layers,
one through three that I just talked
about are all in the wallet. So I'll be
able to demo most of these,
actually all of these capabilities today
with the wallet. It's our wallet called
Locksmith. And then when you get to
layer four, witnesses and watchers,
those are the other components that I'll
talk about today that we've donated it
to the KERI Foundation for open source.
And those are of course the layer that
allows us to make our Key Event Logs
available to other people and keep an
eye on anyone else we're doing business
with, keep an eye on their key state.
So the Locksmith wallet is an
application that we've built over time.
It actually started as a pet project of
mine because I was tired of using the
command line. Most of the work that we
did at GLEIF was done building out the
command line and then actually creating
the entire
GLEIF-authorized representative system
with the KERI command line. And
at one point I just got tired
of
[laughter]
using the command line over and over
again particularly when trying to demo
KERI to people. So I just started
playing around with what it would look
like to create a wallet and took the
KERI command line from KERIpy and
just started building little features
one at a time into this and eventually
it became a tool that I was using all
the time and we figured it would be very
useful and started making it a
production quality wallet.
The core of it is open source and what I
mean by core and I'm going to be demoing
it here in a minute, you'll see the core
is basically all the KERI
functionality. Just core KERI
functionality for working with your key
state locally, creating what we call
vaults which if you know KERIpy
they're called Haberies. (Sorry Sam,
couldn't call them Haberies in my
product)
Creating identifiers inside of those
vaults, doing delegation, multisig,
Provisioning
witnesses is actually on our on our SaaS
platform, but working with witnesses,
doing key rotations, etc. We also
have sections for all the work you do
with a credential, so uploading schema,
issuing credentials, granting
credentials, doing the whole IPEX
exchange, as well as receiving
credentials and using them in various
ways. There's no server required for
the core Locksmith wallet. You can
create all of your stuff locally for
everything that you would need to
potentially share with someone, we have
an export feature. So, if you create an
identifier, you do a couple key
rotations, you want to share it with
someone, you can just export the CESR
of the Key Event Log and email to
someone.
And then finally, it's extensible by
design. We'll get into that
quite a bit. When we first started
adding features for our SaaS platform,
and the healthKERI SaaS platform is
really just KERI infrastructure.
We're allowing folks to provision
witnesses and watchers and use them with
their identifiers for doing business
with each other, we realized actually it
was just because of where we put it on
the user interface, it looked like a
plugin. And we thought, well, you know
what? If we do really want to donate
this to open source, we're not going to
donate that part of the product to open
source, so why not wrap the interaction
with our SaaS services into a plugin API
and make it so that anyone can provide
plugins to that system. And so, I
believe later today or maybe tomorrow
we'll see some of the gentlemen from the
KERI Foundation who have taken this
open source core and integrated their
own plugin to deal with their own SaaS
services. And Two presentations this
afternoon. Great. On just that? Yeah.
Excellent.
And so, what we've also done with it
over time is part of the business
that we're getting into, you heard Jared
talk about today, we're starting to
bring the vLEI into healthcare. So,
we're helping folks with the issuance of
credentials, particularly vLEI
credentials. So, we've added a new
component underneath our plugin for our
SaaS platform that is a credential
issuance management protocol or
plug-in. And so that will interact with
a server component, really wrapping all
of the hardest part of
of issuing the vLEIs is managing the
multisig identifiers required and the
coordination between participants and
how they see the credentials and how
they interact with each other,
notifications, etc. when issuing
credentials across an enterprise by
various parties who may not be sitting
in the same room all the time.
(Let's see where to go.) So the
KERI core already talked about it a
little bit and I'm honestly not really
sure where to go to the demo, so I may
just tell on the slides and go right
over soon, but
this is just all the basic stuff you
would do with a with a KERI
system. So create your identifiers,
manage them, do rotations, like I said,
export them, share them with other
folks.
We've broken out group identifiers into
its own section. We initially
experimented with having it as just
another type of identifier you create
and that was a little bit unwieldy, so
we have our own separate group
identifier section. The ability to do
delegation with any identifier that you
create, you can send challenge
responses. I already mentioned the
credential schemas and then working with
witnesses
and watchers, as a matter of fact. And
then kind of tangential to what you get
with a normal KERI wallet, but much
needed is a full notification system
integrated with KERI messages that go
back and forth. So if you receive KERI
messages like IPEX messages for a grant
that you were given, they turn into
notifications inside of the user
interface, kind of separate from the
actual IXN message itself. (What's next?)
The plug-in arcitecture is the part ..,
Down at the bottom here, this is the
healthKeri plug-in and this is what
you would access to be able to reserve
resources on our SaaS platform in much
the same way that you would go
reserve a VM from Digital Ocean or from
AWS. And so we tried to keep that
comfortable for people who are used to
dealing with cloud services to say, "Oh,
I need another witness. I can just go
rent him, if you will."
And so when you go into that
Plug-in, you will see the ability to
access identifiers, witnesses. We
give you the opportunity to publish
credentials,
we're going to do a lot more with
that in the future once the KERI
Foundation starts working on observers
and registrars. This is just kind of
a lightweight version of that. We
have a connections feature which steps
kind of outside of OOBIs if you just want
to do quick connections with each other
and you know the other person is using
Locksmith at our SaaS platform. And then
watched identifiers is our watcher
network. And I'll talk more about that
later.
Mailboxes so that you can get
these messages sent back and forth to
each other. And then finally servers and
profiles I'll touch on when I do the
demo.
Okay, so we're going to stop
there and I'm going to switch over
To the demo. So this is Locksmith.
Again, I have two of them running here.
(I don't know how awkward that is to see
on the screen. Maybe I'll just center
them both.)
(With the overlap there, that might be a
little bit awkward.)
I have two Locksmiths here so
that I can demo some of the features of
going back and forth between them.
As I mentioned, we call [them vaults, red.]
Your database environments which you
can separate out groups of identifiers
within a KERI system, we call them
vaults. And so we have the ability to
create a new vault. You can give it a
name. So I'm going to go with Alice.
And create a vault. One of the things we
focused on here is making it very
simple to do very simple things. So when
you're creating an identifier, there's a
lot of things you can do and it can be
very complicated and complex to
understand what all the knobs and
buttons do on creating an identifier.
Same with creating a vault here. And so
we tried to make it so that in the very
simple case, if you know what you're
doing, you just need to do something
quickly, type in a name and go and
you're done. So that's what we did with
creating in a vault you could creating a
vault. You can do two-factor auth with
it if you want. Not really that
meaningful or important, but you can cuz
someone requested it from us. So, now
I'm going to open the vault.
And here I am in a KERI environment.
Over here on the left-hand side, I have
my menu which gives me the ability to
work with all the items I talked about
before. Identifiers are my local
identifiers. Remote identifiers are
those with other people who I'm
doing business with. Group multisigs,
credentials, proxies, and the
settings. So, I'll just touch on
the settings very quickly inside of
here. These for those of you who have
worked very closely with KERI under the
hoods, these are various knobs and
buttons you can turn to configure your
environment whether you want a temporary
data store where if you want to change
the directory where we store things by
default, etc. We have a plugin that
I'll be demoing tomorrow that interacts
directly with Locksmith for gaining
access to getting things signed for you
Submitting IPEX grants so that you
can log onto a website, that sort of
thing. You can configure that here as
well.
Going back to identifiers. As I
said, we try and make things very
simple. So, I'm Alice and I want to
create an identifier. I just did. So,
now I have a KERI identifier. It's got
a Key Event Log, only an inception
event. And if I look at it, you can see
that I created it. It has a public key.
No witnesses or anything like that
yet. And there's my Key Event Log. So,
that was really easy. And that's one of
the things that we really want to
emphasize here is how quickly we can do
things. Now, if we want to get more
complicated with it, you can go into our
advanced configuration and you have all
of these options available to you. You
can we can do a keychain if you want to
do a hierarchical deterministic
keychain. You can create that here. You
can have a salt which you can look at,
copy and paste, and save in your one
password so that you could recover this
identifier and all of its keys in the
in the case of a catastrophic event.
If you're a little more
concerned about security, you can just
do a random key so that you could never
get it back if you lose your keys.
Underneath that, we have our signing
thresholds. So, you have the number of
signing keys in the signing threshold.
This is only the M of N support. We
haven't built in the support for
fractionally weighted thresholds yet. We
will eventually. Some of the other
features when you create an identifier,
you can go with establishment only or do
not delegate. And then if you choose
delegation, you can delegate from some
other identifier, whether it's a local
or a remote identifier. So, I'm not
going to create any of that right now.
We have our remote identifiers.
(That's actually a problem.
I'll come back to that in a minute.)
And then in our group identifier
section, if you wanted to go ahead and
create a group identifier, you give it a
name, you select your local identifier
that you want to use to join that group,
and then you would select your other
participants.
And again, a group identifier is
exactly like any other identifier in
KERI. It's just that the keys are
shared across different machines. So,
all the other options for specifying
your thresholds, whether it's
establishment only or do not delegate,
all apply in here as well.
– Quick question. (Yes) Is there a
discovery built into that
drop down for adding group?
Yes, so the other participants would
be coming from your remote identifiers
here. So, any identifiers that you OOBI
with and you've connected with become
candidates for joining a group
multisig. So, you already have to know
about their Key Event Log, and that's in
that's because of the protocol used to
create a group multisig. It involves
taking keys from individual
identifiers from all the participants
involved. And only the public keys, we
don't share the private keys. So, that's
where they came from.
– Is that a different concept than like a
connection, a more general connection,
or is it specifically scoped to
Multisig
group identifier? When you say that,
are you referring to remote identifiers?
Yeah. So remote identifiers are just
ones you OOBI's with. So, in KERIpy, I
think they're called 'contacts' in KERIpy,
that's what the remote identifiers
are here.
It could be anything. Issuing a
credential to receiving a
credential from, anything at all.
(real quick, I realized I
forgot to do something, so you're going
to see a little bit of behind the scenes
here.)
(Because I realized I don't have…) – [Inaudible]
[laughter]
What do you mean?
We're going to
restart my two Locksmiths.
(And I knew I was going to make that mistake.)
We should be good to go
now.
I'll re-center and size them a little
more.
We were in the middle of
creating Alice, so we will open up her
vault again, and we'll go over to remote
identifiers. Good, there they are. Those
are the two identifiers for our SaaS
platform. And so, they are configured to
load when I And these are
configuration options you can add when
you package and ship your version of
Locksmith. Those are OOBIs that he will
automatically resolve when he starts up,
so that he has access to them here. For
in our particular case, verifying the
signatures against our SaaS platform
for gaining access.
Let's go over to the healthKERI,
SaaS platform. This is
our 'getting started' screen, creating an
account within healthKERI. And the
reason why I'm doing this,
it won't take very long, but this gives
me the ability to provision witnesses,
so we can talk about the witnesses that
we have, and then also to start watching
identifiers inside of the healthKERI
watcher network so we can see the
interplay there. And then I can talk
more about what we, you know, what's
going to be available for all of you
folks to start working with. So I am
in Alice, so I will very quickly create
Alice and this is one of the key
differentiators of what we do with
our SaaS platform. There are no usernames
and passwords. There are only usernames
and KERI identifiers. So you aren't
uploading a password here, you're
selecting a local KERI identifier ..,
(Hold on.)
(Create a new one.)
I'm going to select my healthKERI
identifier to use and that will be the
identifier that the public key and
Key Event Log of that identifier will
be stored on our services and anything
that I send to the SaaS platform API will
be signed and encrypted and anything
that it responds with, will also be
signed and encrypted from their AID.
So we have all of our communications
between our local Locksmith plugin and
our SaaS platform secured with what we
call ESSR which is 'encrypt send sign
receiver' which is a protocol
that's built into KERIpy.
So I'm going to continue into
the account creation. This is Alice.
She's on the internet.
'Alice
at
healthkeri.com'
Create an account. Now when
we first created our SaaS platform, we
based everything off of an individual
user and you would provision your own
witnesses and watchers and that
immediately was revealed to be
very much too limiting because
people would want to share accounts. So
we switched over to a model where we
have teams and if any of you are
familiar with using Digital Ocean, it's
very much modeled off of their
approach for how you share resources
across teams. And this came in
handy later when we started working with
provisioning services inside of
enterprises where you have maybe a cloud
service that needs an identifier and it
also needs things like witnesses and
watchers, how you bring that server into
your platform so he can start doing
KERI things and reserving resources
from your KERI account. So this is team
'Alice .. [@]
healthkeri.com' and we'll continue to
access code and as of right now we don't
have billing built into our system so we
just base it off access codes. I hand
out access codes when people want to get
an account on our system.
And so I've created a couple for this demo.
– There's no vLEI
integration where you're collecting
their role? No, not in this. No, we
don't require a vLEI to gain access to
our to our platform. Okay, so I've gone
ahead gone ahead and created an account
Inside of healthKERI. I've added a
team to that account.
And now I'm going to add an identifier.
And this is a little bit of an awkward
step but one that we were required to do
for all of the other things you would
want to do on our SaaS platform. And what
I mean by that is when we provision
witnesses, slightly different from what
many of the other witness
deployments are right now, when we
provision witnesses, we provision them
only for a single AID. So every witness
that you get on our service will only
ever witness for the AID you gave it.
And that's a security measure and also
it helps us keep the scale of all the
witnesses very low so that we can
have a lot of witnesses because we know
each one will only ever witness for one
AID. And so in order to do that, we have
to give it the AID to witness for.
So that's an example of why we had to
create a first step that when you want
to start using our system, you have to
give us an identifier to start working with.
– Are there any special caveats for
group identifiers? No.
– They have separate witnesses?
Correct. Absolutely, yep.
In addition to that,
if I have, for example, maybe an
identifier on a phone and I want
witnesses for it, I can actually do that
as well from here (and I'll show you how
you integrate with that later).
When you first upload an account
identifier, it can be a remote
identifier that you OOBI'd with so you
can get resources for some other
identifier or a local one from this
wallet. In addition, we added a
feature of making this identifier
publicly available and that's just the
healthcare platform global OOBI system so
that whenever you upload an identifier,
we immediately create a new OOBI for you
that you can hand out to anyone and
it'll work for all roles within your
system. And for those of you who know
the details of KERI,
if you OOBI against a specific role, you
only get back the responses
for that role like for a witness. So,
this just gives you everything back with
one single OOBI. So, I'm going to upload
Yep, got to select it first. I'm going
to upload the Alice identifier.
And you can see that now our SaaS
platform knows about this identifier.
It's associated with our account. It has
our sequence number.
And broken out on this grid is both the
local sequence number that I have on my
machine and the sequence number that the
remote system has for me. And those
can get out of sync if I do a bunch of
rotations and don't come back and update
healthKERI except for when watchers are
involved.
And so now it's also public.
From here I'm going to jump
back real quick to
the wallet side of this
application, not the healthcare platform
side, and talk about our
credential management system. So, inside
of here, we have the ability to issue
credentials. We broke credentials out
into those that you have issued, those
that you have received, and then
accepted offers is something very
particular to the demo I will be doing
tomorrow.
And for those of you who were here at
SEDI and saw me do it yesterday, it's
where we have integrated IPEX
protocol into our OAuth servers so that
you can do a credential presentation of
an offer without the actual credential
itself and require the site to sign your
terms and conditions before you give
them the full credential. Those signed
receipts, signed offers show up here.
And then finally we have the ability to
do schema.
We can upload schema from any source.
I'm going to go ahead and grab the QVI
schema just cuz I know it doesn't have any ..,
Doesn't have any chains on it. So we put
the OOBI in there and it automatically
pulls out the SAID for you just so you
see you have that tuple of the
identifier as well as the OOBI. And then
this is another use case where we looked
at it and said, "Okay,
credential registries make sense to me,"
but that's cuz Sam has explained them to
me about five times, maybe probably more
than that.
It was really hard for us to explain to
people what they're doing in that first
step before you're allowed to issue
credentials. You have to create a
registry. Well, what's that? What name
do I give it? "Where does it live?" And
so instead of doing that we tried to
hide all that and this is open for
debate. This will now be an open source.
So if folks don't like this it can be
undone, but we've decided that instead
we've added a step to uploading a schema
that says, "I want to use this for
credential issuance." So when you select
that, you select an identifier who's
going to be the issuer for that
particular type of credential. And when
you load the schema, not only does it
load the schema, but it has now created
a credential registry behind the scenes.
So that is completely hidden from the
user and we think that's probably a good
thing,
but again open for debate and we're
willing to accept feedback on that. Did
you have a question? – Yeah,
Did you issue a credential registry per schema type?
Yep. It was just a an allowance that we
made to try and make it a little bit
easier for the user.
When you come into our issue
credential screen, (I'm not going to
issue any credentials but I just want to
show you really quickly), you select the
type that you want. We dig into the
schema and present fields for you. These
are as typed as we can make them based
on the JSON schema in each of the
credentials cuz you cannot specify
formats and stuff in schema
if you don't want to.
Calling out required fields and stuff
like that just to make credential
issuance a little bit easier
for the user without hardcoding into
this app knowledge of any specific
schema type.
Okay, so now we're going to go back to
the healthKERI plugin.
And
there we go. Perfect example. So this
this identifier is now out of sync and
that is because I created a credential
registry with it which had which had to
create an anchor into my Key Event Log
and now he's out of sync, so you can see
that the remote server doesn't have my most
up-to-date key state.
So I'm just going to go ahead and update
that. And so this tells me that I'm
going to be taking the local key state
where I'm at 1
and pushing it up to the remote server
who is at key state 0 for this and
updating now we're in sync. So he now
knows about my most recent key events.
So now we're going to move on to
witnesses and this is .., (Does it make sense
to go back to the
slideshow?)
So yeah, so I'll just go over this slide
very quickly.
So this is witness as a service and as I
mentioned earlier this gives you the
ability to reserve individual witnesses
for your AID. Any number of witnesses
you want. We have geographically
disperse witness infrastructure so you
get to pick where you want your
witnesses deployed, how many you want
deployed and then you get to pick your
threshold that you want of those
witnesses and our user interface will
default to the most logical threshold
based on the What's the name of that
algorithm?
The Kawa algorithm. So the
number of witnesses that you should have
in your threshold versus the number of
witnesses that you have.
So as I said reserve a witness as easily
as any cloud resource. The core of this
is open source. I know we're going to
see demos of the KERI Foundation folks
who have already put it into production
in their systems.
it is a multi-tenant system, so you can
put it on one
VM and reserve as many witnesses as you
think that VM can support. And then what
we've done behind the scenes for us is
that we spread that out across multiple
hosts and we have a round-robin, and I'll
talk about how we deploy all this later,
that we can then pick from for any
particular region.
We have added, actually I added, to
KERI core, at the very beginning of my
work at healthKeri, the ability for a
two-factor auth for witnesses. So we have
a one-time passcode that you select
that you authenticate with the witness.
He gives you back the one-time passcode,
then you have to enter that anytime you
do a key rotation. And that's to make
sure that your witnesses won't just
accept the Key Event Log for you from
anyone. You have to provide that
one-time password with it. There are
other ways to do this. We could use our
our proprietary API with the ESSR to
accept events for your witnesses, but we
thought that was more vendor lock-in
than we really were comfortable with, so
we went with this one-time password
solution. They are
non-promiscuous. They will only witness
for the people for the one AID that you
reserve them for. Each witness has its
own dedicated key store, so there's no
mixing of keys in like a MongoDB
or anything. They each have their own
private LMDB and we manage that across
multiple servers. This makes it fairly
scalable, pretty easy to deploy, and
designed for and in our case implemented
with geographic distribution.
(Let's just see the screen. I don't
need to talk through this.)
So here we are. So let's add a witness.
So when you open up the create a witness
screen, it will of course make you
select an identifier, so I'm going to
select Alice. In our system right now
we have four regions deployed. We have
New York, Frankfurt, Singapore, and
Sydney. And you get to choose where you
want your witnesses deployed. So I've
already chose I've already selected
Alice as the identifier that I want
witnesses for. I can add as many as I
want in each region. It gives you a
suggestion of a name for that witness in
that region. You can name them anything
you want.
If you want to, I'm just going to go
ahead and reserve a witness in each of
the regions.
And then I'm going to choose an
authentication method.
Trade-off here between security and
friction, ease of use.
We've given you the ability to have
an individual one-time passcode for each
witness that you reserve. At four,
that's really onerous, so I wouldn't
even do it at four. At 12, I couldn't
even imagine it. So, we also give you
the opportunity to do a batch one-time
passcode. One-time passcode for all of
your witnesses for this AID, and that
way you can only enter it once, only
enter one code once when you do a full
rotation.
So, we're going to select batch,
create our witnesses, and you can see
here I've now spun up four witnesses.
Pretty fast. This is actually witnesses
spinning up in our SaaS platform. It's
very light touch for getting a single
witness to spin up.
Each one has its own identifier. You can
see them here. They're non-transferable
identifiers, as you would imagine. Here
are the OOBIs right here that you can
copy and paste if you wanted to.
You can also toggle on QR codes for
those OOBIs. So, if you're doing this
for a device that's on a mobile phone,
and you need to scan in these so that
you can now gain access to them for that
device, you can do that here with these,
QR codes. And then finally, we provide
the opportunity for you to right here
grab those OOBIs out of this screen and
just introduce to all of them. So, I'm
going to go ahead and do this. I'm now
OOBI'ing with each witness individually
and saving him into my database. And
then we did the authentication step,
where I called into the
witness, and this was really tricky to
get right because this like sort of a
trust a TOFU (trust on first use) case,
where that witness wasn't authenticated
anybody, but he would only accept things
from me. So, I was able to sign one
request to him to get the one-time
passcode back from him, and it was
encrypted between the two of us. So, now
I have the one-time passcode here. I
can, again, I could scan that into the
one-time passcode feature on my phone or
in this case I'm going to copy it and
put it in
one password so I can actually
do things with these witnesses
afterwards.
So, I don't know if any of you knew
this, but
What's that?
– We need your one password? No, I use
my fingerprint. You don't have that
again.
– I just wanted you to type it out for us on screen
Nope.
So, I don't know if you knew this, but
when I discovered this like wow, that's
cool. They have they have a one-time
password support.
Yeah, absolutely.
Yeah, they have a they have OP command
line, very cool. Two words or two
letters, I love that.
Then finally, the last step would have
be of course rotation this in. I could
just go do this manually, but we've
added the ability to do a rotation right
here on the screen. It brings up common
defaults that you'd use. You want your
new your next keys or signing
thresholds. We select the TOAD, the
TOAD = threshold-of-accountable-duplicity
accountable duplicity of three, which
makes sense for four witnesses.
And these are the four witnesses we just
created. You can add more or remove here
if you wanted to, but we'll just go
ahead and rotate them in. And of course
now it's asking for my one-time passcode
so I'm going to go over here.
(I'm very paranoid cuz I'm
going to wait till it rolls over
to the next 30 seconds.)
1:30
There we go.
Now I'm going to grab that.
Paste that in here and do a rotation.
And we've rotated. Now I have all
four witnesses rotated into my
identifier. You can see over
here on this side. I'm now at sequence
number 2. I was at sequence number 1.
All four witnesses gave me
receipts. There's my threshold. There's
my new public key. And because this is a
remote identifier and we know that we're
given the opportunity to just go ahead
and upload the new event that you just
used to rotate in those witnesses into
your upstream server. So, we'll update
that. I'm now done with this. You
see here I've created these four
witnesses. These are my account
witnesses. You're now paying for them.
They're a monthly service, but very
very cheap. The controller is Alice.
This is each of the AIDs for those
witnesses, and these are the regions
that they're on. So, I now have
witnesses spread out around the world
for this identifier. So, someone would
immediately now have to attack four
different places around the world to
eclipse [attack, red.] my witnesses. And that was
pretty easy, right? I think it was
pretty easy.
Thank you.
[applause]
And then if we come over here, you can
see that we have updated to our new
key state to this remote server
To our remote SaaS platform, and
we're now at sequence number 2. If you
click on this, you can see this is the
public OOBI I was talking about cuz I
said "Hey, make this guy public." I
5 minutes left?
Oh, man, that went fast.
I'm not even close to done. All right,
well all right, let's see if I can do
this really quick. All right, so let's
get to watchers really fast.
And to do that, I'm going to create a
whole new account. So, let's create Bob.
Create. Open. Add identifier 'Bob'. Now
you see how fast this can actually work, right?
All right. So, I think I
copied. This is where you get to
see remote identifiers. I grabbed
Alice's OOBI, so I'm just going to
paste her OOBI in here and connect, and
now I have Alice. So, now I'm connected
to Alice. I'll go over here. Oh, no, I
got to create an account ' Bob'
I 'boob'-ed, oh, jeez, sorry Bob!
(That was a zero. It wasn't a second O)
Continue to account access ' Bob'
Wonderful.
[laughter]
– Want to use the healthKERI
identifier for that?
[Meanwhile, Phil is typing and speaking out loud]
These are one-time access codes,
by the way, if I didn't mention that
before.
We're going to grab Bob, paste.
Paste, continue to invites, no invites.
Go to identifiers. Let's add Bob an
identifier. Although, I don't think I
need to do this, but anyway, you can
just see how quick this is. And now,
let's go to the last step, watcher
network. So, very quickly, I want to
mention that we initially implemented
our watcher network the same way we did
witnesses. You have to rent individual
watchers and assign them to watch
people. So, if I wanted to have like
five watchers watching Sam's AID, I'd
have to go and get five watchers and
I'll say watch Sam's ID. That way, it
was it didn't work well. I talked with
Sam about it. He said it's no more
secure giving them VMs inside of our
infrastructure than if I just created a
global watcher network. And so, that's
what we did. We created a global watcher
network. So, instead of having to worry
about renting your own watchers and
assigning them and managing them, we
just tell you
tell us an identifier you want to watch.
We'll distribute it across our global
watcher network for you at random in
different locations, and we'll keep an
eye on it for you. So, that's what we've
done. So, getting a watched identifier
is as simple as selecting one of your
remote identifiers and say watch. He
immediately pulled the key state for
that watcher down, and now telling our
system to go watch that identifier. The
value of that, of course, is that now I
can come over here to Alice, and in the
regular KERI side of the plugin (lock
that)
(Hm? 2 minutes? Well, I did that pretty
quick then!)
I'm going to rotate Alice's
identifier, do a key rotation. (I got to
get my a one-time passcode.)
Grab that. 15 seconds should be plenty.
Rotate. There, I've now rotated. I have
all four witnesses
Pulled down for him. And if
everything works correctly, Bob will now
get a notice that Alice
has done an update. This takes a lot
longer than I wanted it to doing a demo,
but that's because I have all my numbers
kind of spun down. There it is, it just
showed up. Just so I don't burn my CPU
out. So, I just received a notification.
This is again the integration of
notifications into our
system.
The notification is available in the
open source plug-in, and you can
integrate it anything you want. So,
whatever you add to the to the health
KERI if as a plug-in, you can integrate
into the notification systems to drive
that as well. Now that I see that I have
new key state for Alice, we made the
decision not to automatically pull that
key state down for you. So, I would just
go into my watched identifiers. You can
see that he is now Alice is now out of
date, and I want to do a sync, and now
I'm up to date with Alice.
So, one last thing I'll point out is
that's all well and good, but I'm
doing it manually. Where this really
comes into play is when you're deploying
servers into enterprise infrastructure,
and you have a server that has an
identifier and that is let's say for
example an OAuth server that's
validating vLEIs coming in, but needs to
keep up to date with the key state of
any of the identifiers that it is now
interacted with. You can provision it so
that it can connect through this
authorization server feature inside of
our SaaS platform, so that it now has the
authority to ask our platform to watch
identifiers on its behalf, and it will
and I'll talk a lot more about this
tomorrow. It will then have a side car
running that is its local watcher that
integrates with the healthKERI we
watcher platform to keep up to date on
key state changes so that anyone that
you're using towards anyone that is using you
to authenticate into a system can do a
key rotation anytime they want and
automatically get updates.
I just real quick I'll go to questions I
guess.
[applause] Thanks everyone.
– How diversified is the watcher set
that you're running? So, right now we're
in four regions, and the same regions
that we are in the witness in the
witness network that are on different
data centers than the
witnesses are.
So, yeah. We have
I think three servers in each of the
regions. And we just pick them at random
when you ask us to watch. We do four
watchers. So, pick them at random, one
in each region.
And that's easy to extend. (I didn't even
get to how we're deploying the services.)
No, it was only 40 minutes.
I know. I realized that when you told me
I had 5 minutes left.
[laughter]
All right, great. Thanks, everyone.
Dismissed. [applause]