Okay, I'm going to start
since we're over time already. I'm
glad to be here today.
Title of my talk, as you can see, is
digital identity needs a legal
foundation. So if you were at SEDI
summit
with the first two days of the week,
this is related to the things I said
there and just kind of goes into a
little bit more detail on how the legal
foundation actually helps us out. So we
spent a lot of time talking about, you
know, the cryptography and key
management and all of those things.
But I think the hardest part of digital
but I think the hardest part of digital
identity is actually
the
not the technical things but legal and
institutional right so spent a lot of
time talking about governance and you
know sometimes it's can be kind of
boring but ultimately I think it's what
gives us the foundation for making all
of this work. So, think about where
we're at. We've got decentralized key
management, authentic chain credentials,
Serialization formats,
Serialization formats
Some implementations, open- source code.
some implementations, open- source code.
So, the technical foundations
are largely there. That doesn't mean
they're done. Doesn't mean they can't be
improved, but we've made real progress.
We also have things that we're still
working on like tooling and ecosystem
and developer experience and all of
those things that make it work.
But we need to get adoption. And in
order to get adoption,
we have to
get rid of some of the fundamental
blockers. Now, I'm going to talk about a
couple of them today. Not necessarily
all of them. I mean because you know
there's no end to blockers when you're
trying to do something this big. But
there's a couple of them that I think we
can we can help solve. So Sarashin
How to say his name Mukapage I think
is how you say his last name. I haven't
heard it said so I'll say it that way.
Recently wrote a book about what he
called the a book a paper what he called
the proof gap. And for him, the proof
gap was the idea that we still rely
largely on centralized institutions to
be able to prove things about ourselves.
So, our education, employment, whatever
licenses we have, you know, benefits
we're entitled to, all of those things.
When proof is needed, we can't generally
present it directly, especially
digitally in a way that somebody else
can easily verify. So even worse, I
mean, if we lose that proof, we have to
essentially go back to those
institutions one at a time and confirm
something about ourselves, right? So, so
that could be a real problem.
Back, you know, 50 years ago when
back, you know, 50 years ago when
everything was based on paper and kept
in filing cabinets, that might have made
sense because it was really all you
could do. But I think everybody in this
room acknowledges that we can do better
than that in a digital world and we
should do better than that, not just
take that old paper filing cabinet model
and move it forward.
So
sometimes people think of the proof gap
as a technical problem and it certainly
is that. There are technical problems
with moving this centralized filing
cabinet model into the digital world and
trying to decentralize it and create
something that's better.
But I think we can think we can ask
but I think we can think we can ask
ourselves about the problem of
governance. So the
there are lots of ways that we have
worked out how to
Transfer trust
in the physical world, right?
One of those is very familiar to
one of those is very familiar to
everybody and that is credit cards.
60 years ago,
we didn't have this problem because we
didn't have credit cards really at all,
right? There were bank cards and might
maybe had a card from your department
store, right? I remember people had
Sears cards that you could use at Sears
and nowhere else, right? So they were
all centralized, single domain and Visa
first and then others followed came up
with this idea that we could have a
coalition of banks put together ways
that they can work together. So this
involved technology, how are we going to
technically transfer information? It
involved rules and processes. It
involved legal agreements. Involved all
of this. And collectively we call that
thing a trust framework, right? All of
those technical and legal and regulatory
rules that make all of that work. But
even today, right, if you're a merchant,
you've got multiple ones of these that
you have to interact with. Now, it turns
out somebody saw that problem and there
are all kinds of companies. There's
actually between this guy and those
guys, there's like four layers of
companies that make this all work. in
order to make it easy for him and for
you when you go in, right? He doesn't
have to have six different terminals and
all of that because somebody's solved
that problem. But still, it's a problem.
Now, imagine what happens when we've got
not five different banking system or
credit card systems. We have thousands
of different credentials. Now we're
trying to navigate this island, the sea
of islands where each of these is a
separate trust framework with their own
rules, their own governance. Maybe they
share some technical underpinnings, you
know, at least at least we could hope
for that. But it's still a problem if
every category of credentials requires
its own private trust framework and
every verifier has to somehow be inside
each of those trust frameworks. It's a
nightmare, right? Instead of four layers
between the merchant and the credit card
companies, we'll have a hundred layers
between, you know, you and all of the
different things that you might need to
verify in your life. Now, private
governance can solve some of these
problems, right? And we've seen lots of
efforts over the years. IRA is one of
the most recent, right? that tries to
create a coalition of
related or like-minded maybe
organizations who can come together and
create a trust framework that is
interoperable right and you know I think
they all kind of have this vision of
well we'll just get big enough that
we'll solve this problem it won't be a
problem because we'll just get big
enough that everybody will be part of us
but you know Visa is not part of
Mastercard and they never will
And that's always going to be a problem.
So a different way to solve this problem
is to have something underneath all and
connect them. Okay, but that's just one
problem. There's another problem. I
talked about this in my talk on
Monday and that is an economic problem.
So in the mid 1990s,
Netscape had essentially solved the
digital identity problem for at least
the web. I mean, they had a pretty good
pretty good idea, right? We'll have
servers that will have certificates and
we'll put certificates in browsers
and your browser certificate will
identify you. We'll proof your identity
with these certificates. I mean, in
this day and age where you can
essentially get server certificates for
free, you may not remember, but back in
the day, certificates were really
expensive because they were all proofed.
Right now, they basically just link a
domain name to a key. That's all they
do. But if you want a real proofed
certificate, they cost money. Not only
because it costs money to proof you, but
because the company is putting
themselves out there and saying this
information is correct. So, they're
liable, right? So, they cost money.
People, turns out people were not
willing to pay money to shop and to bank
and all of those things. They wanted it
all to be free. So
we standardized on servers will have
certificates and people will have
passwords and just kind of waved our
hands and hoped the problem would go
away because there was money to be made.
So here's the two problems, right? How
we scale trust, right? How do we create
trust frameworks that are more
universal? And second, who's going to
pay for this, right? who's proofing the
person using what authority, what's the
legal standing, all of those questions.
this is where I think SEDI can help us
with both of these problems and I'll and
I'll talk about them in some detail.
So as far as scaling trust, SEDI
doesn't provide any kind of universal
trust framework. That's not the answer,
right? What SEDI provides instead is a
foundation that trust frameworks can sit
on. Right? So we have something that is
firm underneath a firm legal foundation
for all of these other things that are
going to happen. The second help that
SEDI can provide is on the economic
problem because turns out that the state
already has lots of infrastructure
for doing this, right? They already
proof you, right? part of you know if
you look at your driver's license we
have a couple of people from Europe here
so they may not be familiar with
this idea but if you look at your
driver's license which is the only thing
we have to prove who we are there's a
little star on it you know what that
star means
real ID
it means the state proofed your identity
so this was started in 2005
when earlier than that maybe 2002
two. It was right after 911.
It happened. It happened. It happened
before 911 because I remember I was CIO
when they started talking about this.
This was early 2000s, right? So,
proofing your identity. And at the time,
the motor vehicle division, the driver's
license division said, "We don't want
anything to do with identity. We're not
an identity
provider. This is not us." Well, let's
see how that worked out for him. So,
anyway, you have the old star. They
already proved your identity.
So, let's talk for a minute. I think
most people at this point probably have
an idea of what SEDI is, but let's just
make sure that we're all on the same
page, right? So, SEDI doesn't give you
an identity, right? In fact, the SEDI
legislation specifically says an
individual possesses an identity innate
to the individual's existence and
independent of the state. which identity
is fundamental and inalienable. So SEDI
doesn't give you an identity. They're
not an identity provider, right? That's
a nice term. Instead, what it is, you
create your identifier or identifiers.
the state proofs specific attributes
about you
and then links those attributes to you
In a cryptographic way, not to you to
to this identifier, right, that you
control, right? In a cryptographic way.
So, you can kind of think of this like a
notary, right? The state is endorsing
your identity, not giving you an
identity. They're just saying, "Yeah,
this identifier, we looked at the person
who controls it, and that really is the
name and the birthday and the address
and whatever other attributes might be
part of your setting."
So set is not just one credential.
Like I said, you create an identifier or
identifiers
and then SEDI
is a credential which links those
identifiers to I'm sorry those
attributes that the state has proofed
and endorsed to that identifier.
Now there could be other government
now there could be other government
credentials that sit on top of that.
things like driver's licenses. We heard
Joe talk about offhighway vehicle
operator licenses, fishing licenses.
States are veritable credential
factories. They just love giving
credentials to people for different
things, right? So, states have lots of
them. Now, some of these will involve
guardianship, things like birth
certificates and school records, and the
statute includes that idea, right?
Others will be just things that you get.
And you know, like I said, I've got six
up here, but there probably a thousand
of them that states have. Most of us
don't care about most of them, right?
But also, other institutions can give
you credentials. So, you could use your
SEDI to prove who you are when you go to
the bank to get a credential from your
bank. or you could use your SEDI to
prove who you are when you're
registering for school and you would get
a school ID. So all of these other
credentials are essentially resting on
this foundation that SEDI has provided
and you can even issue your own
credentials. You may not imagine why
that would be interesting now but I mean
you know with personal agents AI agents
coming along this could be a lot more
interesting.
but it's not just people.
So there's also organizations. Now this
is not SEDI. This is different than SEDI
but it's related to SEDI and important
for what we're talking about. Right? So,
organizations already have firm legal
foundations in the sense that
you g register a business and the
commerce department gives you a
registration number and the IRS gives
you an EIN and all of these things that
come along with being an organization.
We don't care as much about the
organizations creating and controlling
their own organiz identifiers, but they
will, right?
State Department of Commerce generally
in the United States at least is who is
responsible for I for endorsing that
right so you could imagine a SEDI like
credential or it might just be their
business registration but anyway it's
it's analogous to the SEDI
organizations like GLEIF
are indispensable for businesses and
other organizations who need some sort
of global
reach, right?
I got an LEI just because I wanted to
see how it worked. I've never ever used
it for anything for my business. But
that but that's important, right?
Because there are some things like
government credentials and banking
credentials, business licenses that
would just depend on whatever
organizational identity you have,
whatever identity or credential
the organization has from the
Department of Commerce, but many might
require this global interaction. Okay?
Local restaurant might not ever need an
LEI and all of the things that go with
that, but a bank might.
Now
let's talk for a second about the legal
underpinnings of SEDI because this is
important. I mean first of all SEDI
includes a bill of rights. I read you
the statement that it says about your
identity belonging to you and being
inalienable.
These are legal rights not terms of
these are legal rights not terms of
service. Right? This is not a
click-through contract that you don't
read. And you know, if you want to
enforce whatever small rights they might
have left you in this 60page document,
you have to go to court. These are
things that you know, they're they're in
statute. They're in law. It also
includes selective disclosure. So the
idea that you don't have to disclose
everything on a cred in a credential
or in your SEDI credential in order to
use it you can just disclose the parts
that is necessary requires that the
system be built on open standards right
that it's not a proprietary system MDL
Even
So no vendor lockin anyone can
build a conformant
wallet verifier, whatever. Speaking of
wallets, it mandates a choice of
wallets, right? So, there's not just one
app that the state gives you. And if you
don't have that state app, you don't
have a SEDI. You can choose different
wallet providers. You can put your SEDI
in any of those, move it between them,
you know, whatever. It includes a
duty of loyalty which is like a
fiduciary requirement for identity
data which is a first right this is
revolutionary in the world of digital
identity.
And finally, like I mentioned earlier,
it supports the idea recognizes that
many people are
wards of a guardian and therefore the
guardian has to have the rights and the
abilities to KERI out
functions,
operations on their behalf. I don't know
what the right word is. KERI out what
what are they doing? acting on their
behalf. There we go. Acting. That's the
word I was looking for. Nice simple
word, not KERI out duties. Okay. So, so
these are all part of the statute and
important to why SEDI creates this kind
of legal foundation.
Now,
as I mentioned earlier,
the problem in this proof gap is that
when institutions make errors,
you basically are left to navigate the
correction process all on your own. Now,
SEDI doesn't mandate that everybody that
every institution has to do things a
certain way, but it does provide you
with a legal foundation. And it does say
that you have enforcable rights
related to your SEDI. So you have the
right to obtain SEDI credentials. You
have the right to have its attributes
amended as they change or need
correction. You have protections against
arbitrary revocation. There are only
certain circumstances where this can be
revoked.
You there's an in a complaint an
you there's an in a complaint an
enforcement mechanism for how you can
deal with problems that come up and
that includes both the digital
what's it called? A digital privacy on
budsman and the attorney general. Yeah.
So there are both of those that
give you the ability to seek redress if
something happens. So yeah,
just real quick, but it does not
include a private right of action. The
attorney general has to act on your
behalf.
Yeah, we tried to get that in there, but
they decided that was reach too far.
Yeah.
Rich too far. Yeah. Yeah. Okay. So
these aren't just like you know consent
form clickth through consent forms and
you know support calls that you make,
right? Th these are legal remedies that
you have the right to there are
legal remedies you have the right to
access if these things don't happen.
Now
like I said earlier this doesn't mean
SEDI doesn't
replace all of these trust frameworks
that exist. So I spent my career largely
in academia, right?
Academics is going to have trust
frameworks about what an accredited
institution is for example, right?
Visa is still going to exist as a trust
visa is still going to exist as a trust
framework for how
money gets transferred inside their
network. Those are all still going to
exist. But what does change is the idea
that they are or can sit on top of this
legal foundation, right? They can have
attributes that they know someone they
trust proofed.
Now along those lines, I want to talk
about two different ways of establishing
trust. This is a conversation I had with
Sam. At Smoking Apple six weeks ago
or so, right? Because I had just
written a blog post about reputation for
agents, right? And how and how all that
can work. But it's equally important
here, right? So there are two different
ways of establishing trust.
One is by obser observation,
right? You look at someone's behavior
and you say, "Sam seems like a nice guy.
I guess you know I'll get to know him a
little better and then you know you have
more interactions and you get you build
up that trust. The second one which I'm
going to talk about first I'm going to
talk about the second one first is
reputation by reference and the reason
I'm going to talk about it first is
because it's essentially how we
bootstrap things right so at the top of
this I have a diploma right so if you
want to know things about me related to
my education I can give you a diploma
right that is essentially reputation by
reference some institution is saying
that they did specific things and are
vouching for the fact that I met their
standards with respect to this course of
study, right? But who are they
and does this really belong to me and
what standards are they actually holding
me to? Now, if I tell you I have a PhD
from the University of California at
Davis, most people would say, "Oh,
University of California. I know that
school. I guess that's okay, right?" But
if I tell you I have a bachelor's degree
from Norda,
whatever, what is that thing called?
Norda
Medical Thing, you guys know down in
Provo. Anyway,
are they good? Are they acceptable? Or
is that a good institution? I honestly
don't know. But who does? Well, the way
you do it is this diploma can be a
credential
and it can be chained to my SEDI
credential which now means that I can
prove that this diploma was actually
linked to me or given to me. Right? But
it also can be chained to the
university's credentials and
identifiers. So they probably have an
accreditation credential or should have
one that came from their accrediting
body. And there's not just one, right?
So there would be an accrediting body
for the university. There would be an
accrediting body for the specific degree
program I'm in. All of those I mean
there might be dozens of these out here
that the that the university has. Okay.
They can you can also check to see is
this a legal business? Is it even
recognized as a business? So you know
that would be your commerce department
or GLEIF vLEI
credential.
And importantly when I present this
diploma as a credential
all of this can be checked automatically
right these chains can be followed. We
can check all of the credentials and you
know you can get a green light on your
system that tells you yes
this credential tell came is issued to
this person it was came from this
institution that institution is
accredited by this body and this body
and this body and it's organized in the
state of Utah and all of the things that
you might want to know about it.
So that's reputation by reference
and
steady provides a nice foundation for
that as do the organizational
Credentials that we talked about.
Okay. There's another kind of reputation
that I mentioned and that's reputation
by behavior. Now, in the physical world,
right, we just interact with each other,
and that's kind of how we figure out
whether or not
we like this person. We trust them,
right? The fact that I'm going to let
you fix my plumbing doesn't mean I'm
going to let you babysit my kids, right?
So, there's different domains of
behavior that we that we look for,
right? We use reputation by reference to
essentially bootstrap this. I needed
someone to come in and fix an oven at a
at a rental property I have.
I didn't know anyone, so I just used
reputation by reference, right? I looked
at reviews online to see, okay, they've
got a pretty good thing. Yeah, Timothy,
isn't reputation by reference also an
accumulation of behaviors?
It is, but it's at a distance, right?
it is, but it's at a distance, right?
So, we go back to this
All of these could be many layers
away from the actual thing that I give
you. Right? So there are accumulated
behaviors that lead to that diploma. But
why do I but it's not me who watched you
complete the degree. It's indirect. It's
the university who watched you complete
the degree and you're believing the
university. So there's an indirectness,
not a direct link. But either way, the
quality of reputation
can't be separ separated from an
accumulation of behaviors over time.
Correct.
That's true.
And so if it's a good restaurant, it's
done well. It's it's had good behaviors
which got that reputation. And what
you're doing is you're collapsing the
history because it's so well known. I'm
going to collapse the history and just
say I just need to tell you the name
of the organization. changing
the trust.
In reputation for you, you explicitly
trust the recruiter. If you're observing
the direct behavior, the only person
you're trusting is yourself. So, the
verifier doesn't have to trust anybody.
If they truly do reputation by behavior,
they can verify all of
So, here's a here's a different way of
thinking about it. Here's a different
way of thinking about it.
Trust always
always requires vulnerability.
Your trust requires vulnerability.
So if you aren't vulnerable,
you don't have to trust.
So the question here is, am I trusting
me? Right? I've eaten at that restaurant
before and it was pretty good, right? or
am I trusting the reviewers which is an
accumulation of behavior but I'm
trusting someone else in one case I'm
more vulnerable to mistakes than I
am any other right because it's indirect
rather than direct that's the difference
you're trusting a third party's opinion
of the reputation versus your own
that's right it's not it's not whether
it's based on behavior it's based it's
whether it's indirect or direct
right
so a different dimension but yeah So
right now the way reputation by behavior
works, one example of that is credit
bureaus, right? So credit bureaus
accumulate
all of your transactions and whether you
pay your bills on time and whether you
were late and all of those things,
right?
And they use some algorithm to determine
a credit score which is then paid for. I
mean other places other banks or credit
issuers, credit card issuers or
employers and others can then pay for
that credit score and get that for you.
Right? So that's one way that we do
behavior. Different way is say every
time I have a transaction with company X
or company Y,
I get a receipt that I paid on time, all
of these things. Now, this may not
matter as much for individuals as it
does for organizations. I mean you can
see the organizations could really
benefit from something like this because
it's big lots of money but anyway you
get these as credentials and now you can
prove to other people in combination or
apart whether or not you have behaved
properly. Now I have to say there's one
big problem here.
I can admit bad behavior. So doesn't
mean that these things are ever are ever
going to go away. I mean, I think
there's always room for things
that u
are looking for bad behavior. Yeah.
One thing though that the
decentralized model allows is that the
verifier can pick their own algorithm.
If I go to get a credit score, there's
like five algorithms.
Yeah. And that's and Yeah. And I was
going to mention that this model allows
for a marketplace of algorithms, right?
and for transparency in algorithms,
right? Somebody might say, "Oh, yeah.
Well, we use this algorithm for how we
do how you do scoring." Yeah.
I don't know if you were talking about
it, but you said at the bottom in
one case, you don't own your data. You
do own your data.
Yeah. And I'm gonna say that this is
the sort of issue legally that is going
to slow us down dramatically because if
you look at what the Supreme Court has
always said, it's that no one owns
facts. Okay, data is facts. You might
own the database that the facts reside
in, but no one owns the underlying
facts. So the solution to that is to
treat those facts as an unownable
commons. Okay? And like all commons,
navigable waters or the air we breathe,
someone has to be responsible. So going
back to the fiduciary duty of loyalty
and other fiduciary duties, you are the
best candidate to be the trustee over
your facts because you're more
interested in their accuracy.
I care about them.
Right. Okay. and the government has
a secondary fiduciary duty to make
certain that your rights in those facts
aren't abused.
Yeah, that's
but the point there is I think that's
what's going to slow us down because if
you look at these 80page agreements
where you just click I agree, none of
them say you own the data and you're
giving us ownership. They all say you
transfer whatever rights you have and we
accept whatever rights you have and then
the company goes out and says well we
own this. So it's a legal fiction.
Yeah, we I probably shouldn't say
own there. I mean control is a better
word.
Own is a problematic word in this word
for the reasons that you have
pointed out. And in fact, if
if I'm in a transaction with someone, we
both are parties to that transaction
and we both could have a credential re
to that transaction and we both control
that, right? And of course, that's just
two-party. It could be multi-party. So,
so yeah, it's it's about you have access
to and can control who you share it
with,
right? And just to your point very
quickly about transactions, you know, we
always sort of say, well, the newspaper
costs a dollar. Well, if I'm buying the
newspaper, I value the newspaper more
than the dollar and the publisher values
the dollar more than the newspaper. So
otherwise, the transaction wouldn't
occur.
Yeah. Yeah. There has Yeah. It's not
there's cost, price, and value. Right.
Right. And they're not the same. Yeah.
Even the word your implies ownership
data about you. Yeah.
Yeah.
Okay. So this whole idea of
reputation has lots of implications or
Ramifications for how we might
approach agent AI and how agentic AI
works with us. I mean this talk is not
about agent AI but I just wanted to
point out that this same foundation and
this idea of building reputation around
solid identifiers for organizations and
individuals
helps us in this space if you want to
know details how I think about it like I
said there's a blog post okay
or
One thing I thought of when I was doing
this actually is this idea of an
evaluator. You could imagine agents that
you employ that are evaluators. You
know, we talked about having a
marketplace of reputation evaluation
algorithms. You could imagine a
agents who are working on your behalf
for various things, right? Things that
you care about and ones that you trust
and you Yeah, I'm going to use that
agent because I, you know, like the
restaurants it recommends.
So what's the technology opportunity
here? If you're building
decentralized identity infrastructure,
SEDI is an opportunity, but it's not a
guarantee, right? There's a
SEDI sets out these requirements,
Open standards, decentralized
control,
that represent a high bar for how
this all has to work. And like I
said at the start of the talk,
there's the technical side of it, right?
Which is the which is not in any way a
small thing, but doing that at scale,
meeting the user experience requirements
that we might have, finding the right
economic models for the various parts
and pieces that have to work. Those are
all extremely difficult problems to
solve. So it's it's not a no-brainer
that oh SEDI came along good it's all
solved and we still have lots of work to
do. Timothy
you've got whole talks about this. If
you
in
have a legal basis in their giant
centralized digital system
use a lot of cryptography as well
component missing
and that's the decentralized nature of
setting. It's trying to have
a legal verifiable basis but also
decentralization meaning that you can
have different vendors in different
states and different systems and they
can issue in one place and verify in
another because they're speaking a
common
we hope
those systems that's that's
obviously the
but I mean but I mean I think this is
where you're going but that makes it
hard right
in contrast with ADAR in India and in
contra contst with what they're doing in
Estonia because they do not have that
property and they're not even trying.
It's a giant centralized system and
everybody phones home to the mother
ship.
Yeah, absolutely.
My point is just having those two
components up there describes ad hoc.
That's my point.
Okay.
And it does
go back to your point about control
because decentralization is about
autonomy and control ultimately.
Yeah.
So
Lesig famously said that code is law
and there's a lot of people who take
that to heart and it is true to the
extent that code controls what you can
do and what you can't do but I don't
think for identity that idea is quite
sufficient right that we need more than
code we need this underlying legal
foundation that SEDI provides for
individuals.
SEDI answers questions about who has
authority to revoke, when can they
revoke? That's just one example, right?
Who has the right to get one of these?
Code doesn't solve those problems. Those
are all things that we need legal
infrastructure which steady is at least
on the road to providing right. I don't
think this will be the last SEDI
statute. I think there will be more but
but nevertheless we're on we're on the
road to getting there. So
that provides this legal foundation like
I've said
We've got
code, we've got stacks that are maturing
And what we have now starting in May
is a legal foundation for all of that.
So
we've had some discussion going back.
I've got like two or three minutes I
think if there are questions. two
minutes I'm told. So, is there
questions? Happy to answer them.
Otherwise, I will turn you over to the
next one.