All right.
How's everybody doing? My name's Ryan.
I'm one of the team, the KERI
Foundation development team. We're
all pretty new to this gig, so it's kind
of a fun little trial by fire to be up
in front of you talking about some of
these things that we're only getting you
getting into ourselves.
I wanted to kind of take the temperature
of the room. Generally speaking, I know
we've got at least one person in the
back that wants to see specifically kind
of about deployment. How do we get
really started? We'll cover some of
that. What else do you guys want from
this particular session? Anything in
particular? Do you want or should we
just get into it and see where the
questions go?
Sounds good. All right. So, the
objectives here for this session,
we're going to do some overview of three
of the five W's. the witnesses,
watchers, and boot service isn't really
the one of the W's, but secondarily,
it's the web in general, deploying to
the web. Three of those five W's.
So, we'll talk about all of those things
a little bit. We'll do a
walkthrough, high-level walkthrough of a
deployment guide that I created that's
on the repo. When we get to that point,
There will be a link and a QR code
if you want to follow along. And
probably would be best to or easiest for
you if you want to see how it actually
works to pull that up in your own laptop
and just follow along. I'll just be kind
of taking high-level snapshot
Overview of that. We're not going to
actually do the deployment here because
I've already done it. But when we're
done with all that, kind of walking
through what that those steps are, I'll
give you a quick view of the wallet
launching and then actually connecting
to some witnesses and provisioning
witnesses and stuff. We'll we'll go
through that. So, here are the repos
we'll be dealing with. They're all under
the KERI Foundation GitHub account. So,
if you go to KERI Foundation, these are
the three that you're looking for that
we'll be talking about today. And just
for a I don't know that you're going to
follow along on your phones or whatever,
but that's the QR code to the to the
setup guide specifically, you can just
go to the KF boot repo itself, and
it's just right there on the at the top
level. You can click on it and pull it
up
to kind of follow along with that.
A QR, but
what's that?
Doesn't show a QR, but
Oh, sorry. I hadn't got that far yet.
Next step in my bad. [laughter]
I've got my double view here and I
wasn't looking at the right one.
So, but we've got some new people coming
in. So, these are the repos we're going
to be dealing with in this particular
Session today. For those who want to
just pull this stuff up, I would
recommend pulling up the setup guide and
just at least following along. I'm not
going to go through it like actually run
the code in this the setup guide because
I've already done it. So, but we are
going to go through it kind of at high
level. So, it'll be it'll be easier for
you guys to see what's really going on
by taking a look at that and just
following along as we as we go through
it. And it's all broken out into steps.
So should be pretty easy to follow.
So everybody got that?
Okay, we'll go on to I want to just I
mean I probably don't need to do this
with this group, but just to remind
everybody the core concepts of what
KERI's all about. First, it's about
keys. Above all, it's about keys.
And there's two different kinds of keys.
Who wants to answer? What kind of keys
are we talking about?
keys.
Not public and private. Yes, but there's
two different kinds.
Signing and private.
Signing and
rotation.
Rotation. That's it. Signing and
rotation keys. So, those are the keys we
talk about when we're talking about
KERI. You got to remember that there's
those are different things. And
always just kind of remember that's
how it works. The next thing that's one
of these core concepts is key events
themselves. anything events related to
those keys, those various different
kinds of keys. And within that sort of
context, there's a lot of ways we could
break it down, but I just for the sake
of this particular presentation, I
separated it into single and multi-
signature types of events.
And finally, the Key Event Log, the log
that keeps track of all the events.
Those things taken together are in
effect I mean it's probably
oversimplifying but in effect are the
canonical core of what KERI is all
about. Everything else is sort of in
support of this set of things.
So keep that in mind as we talk about
KERI ecosystem which this is a slide
from Sam's white paper as you guys saw
earlier today in Sam's presentation.
This describes what the different roles
of each of these different components
are.
So, the best place to go and get a real
deep understanding of that stuff is
Sam's white papers. And if you go to
KERI.1, he's got links to the white
paper, and he's also got a link to his
slide deck, which is related to his
white paper. So, I definitely recommend
going and looking through that stuff,
too.
But there's so there's the three core
components we're going to talk about,
Kiana. Now, I'm getting back to where
you your question you asked earlier.
Those three core components are and
we're sticking with the movie theme. For
those who missed it, my first slide was
a screenshot from a movie called
Witness.
So the first core concept or component
is a boot service.
Dumb movie jokes, right?
Second one, witness. We just talked
about that. And the third one, there it
is.
Watchers. Watcher in the Woods.
Keeping that movie theme alive.
So those are the kind of the core
components we're talking about here to
deploy this infrastructure that
Healthcare has so generously donated
into the open source world just in time.
Come on in.
You're going to want to probably if
you're you can kick that bag out of the
way and just toss on the ground or
whatever.
Thank you. Very pleasure.
Yeah. So for a lot of what we're going
to do today, I'm going to do a high
level walkthrough of some deployment
stuff. So you'll want to go back. Let me
just back up and I'll show you.
So you can get to
So for those that are just coming in,
you'll want to go to this setup guide on
the K KF boot
Repo because we're going to I'm going
to do a high-level walkthrough of that.
That's a very detailed with commands and
everything that you can use after this,
but we're going to kind of step through
it and I'll talk about it a little bit
Just so you guys can follow along.
And whether you want to do it live here,
probably won't have enough time for
that, but you can certainly walk through
the stat setup guide and actually do it
on any infrastructure you've got and it
should work for you. Great. So anyway,
let me get back to where I was. The
movie theme. Okay, a couple of quick
disclaimers. First of all, this is a
this guide is a very opinionated guide,
meaning that it's a it's one way to
deploy this infrastructure.
There's as you get more familiar with
how this works, you can start to
recognize that there's a there's a lot
of ways you could actually do this. So,
this one's going to pick one track and
be very opinionated about how to do it.
Doesn't mean that's the only way to do
it. So, keep that in mind. Second of
all, all these repos and all the
services that they run are Falcon apps,
which is just Python HTTP in the end. So
they're all Python processes. It's all
Python under the hood. So there nothing
really magic about that. It's all Python
stuff. It's all early work in progress
still as well. Well, I mean the
witness and watcher code is pretty
robust in terms of that's the stuff that
healthcare open source they're
using it in production.
So, it's pretty proven in that sense.
The boot service itself is a little
newer and we'll certainly go through
iteration and all of this stuff will
continue to grow and we'll iterate
on it as a team and as a community and
it will certainly get better and better.
So don't be too harsh in judgment of how
it is right now. It'll keep growing. And
finally, this is a demo only version of
How to do this stuff, meaning it's
all going to be on one host.
We're going to do a multiple witness
configuration on one host. Which is
not a production sort of deployment. It
we would not say do that in production.
It doesn't really give you much help.
As an example of what a production
and deployment might look like, again
with an asteriskish,
productionish,
this is a high-level sort of idea of what it
might look like in production where
you've got your wallet, you've got these
providers that provide witness watcher
service deployed on cloud
environments across the vertical lines
here or separations or maybe zones and
and or sorry regions and then
availability zones or the or the
horizontals. So in theory anybody who's
providing these services including a
private data center of your own where
you deploy this kind of a situation
where it's distributed across multiple
zones and multiple u regions and all
that kind of stuff is really the ideal
way to do that. And then from the wallet
side, the AIDs when it gets to that
point in the wallet, the plug-in could
provide multiple providers. You could
choose from either one provider that has
a good distribution into their cloud
environment or multiple cloud
environments or you could choose from
multiple envi different providers to
spread your witness surface out
as far as you can and have as much
availability and redundancy and all
that as possible. So that's that's the
kind of idea of how you would want to
deploy this in production at scale.
There's a lot of nuance and a lot of
there's a lot of nuance and a lot of
different ways to do that, but that's
that's what it might look like. So with
all that preamble,
let's get into the actual setup guide
itself. So base requirements step, which
is step one of this setup guide. Our
opinion of this in this guide is we're
using iuntu 2404.
So the latest LTS
It does depend on lib sodium
one of the libraries that's underlying
KERIpy and KERI you know the KERI
code in general engine x for in this
case for tls termination and reverse
proxying
and serbbot just to you know set up
certificates and stuff like that. So,
that's just the base guide setups.
I forgot to mention that. Oh, no, I did
mention it. Never mind. Sorry.
So, no, no real magic there. If
you're looking at the guide it's
pretty straightforward to get
these things set up. If you have any
experience with infrastructure at all,
Any particular cloud provider,
whatever. Our we set ours up on Digital
Ocean. I did want Yeah,
stupid question.
Do you throw that in a Docker container
or
No, I mean, you could you could Don't
tell Sam though because he does
not like Docker for this kind of a
deployment for security reasons, which
is
for development.
Valid. I mean, for development, sure,
you could I run Docker locally.
And you could certainly put this all in
and you could certainly put this all in
Docker and deploy it in that way and
into Kubernetes or any kind of
orchestration system, but Sam's
pretty adamant that there's
some major security concerns about that
approach. So, just be aware of that. So,
this is pretty much bare metal.
So, no production.
Yeah. Yeah. He according to Sam, he
would not do that. And so this guide
is bare metal. It's not really bare
metal because we're still in a cloud
environment and so it's not really bare
metal, but it's as close as it gets
these days unless you got your own data
center with your own hardware.
So,
any questions so far? Everybody good?
All right, step two.
Set up a service user that has we're
just going to call that user KERI.
And there's no login. We're so the
service user, no login on this one. and
we're going to set up some
directory structure. The setup guide
goes in a little more detail about this,
but generally everything's under opt
witness pool watcher and KF boot.
So there's some the guide as you'll
see has a broader structure and it'll
give you the command to create all that
stuff. Just copy and paste and it'll
just work.
Oh. What time are we
ending this session again, Henk? 4:00.
Okay, I'll keep that. Keep in mind of
that.
Five minutes.
Five minutes. In five minutes. All
right. Quick. Next. We set up UV and
Python. This particular version of
Python 3 3.14.0
for this purpose. There's some
dependency there for that
particular version. So we just kind
of pinned to that and UV is the
easiest way to manage that dependency
these days. Anybody that's dealt with
Python much UV is kind of the way to go.
Now we get into a little more of the
gut. That's just basic setup. Just to
get the environment in place. Now we get
into a little bit more of the guts of
this install. The so the witness
The repo is called witness HK. That's
the healthcare open- sourced version of
the witness infrastructure. The wit
opnet is the name of the package that
will go into pi. It's not there yet. So
the install in the guide is just an
install straight from GitHub over
HTTP. So it's just a UV install from
straight from GitHub with the latest
version of w of the witness HK.
But shortly after, I'm sure sometime
shortly after this conference, we'll get
it all into pi and then you can install
it from just with pip straight up. And
then of course the next one is the
watcher
Operational network or I don't know
what the op means exactly, but we'll say
that.
And then the boot service which acts
as kind of a control surface for the
witness and watcher provisioning and
deployment all or not deployment but the
Provisioning and communication
and stuff.
So
anybody following along actually doing
it? [laughter]
Nobody's actually installing it. I
wouldn't figure you would. But any
questions yet? We'll I'm I'm kind of
going a little bit quick through this to
get to more of a demo and then we can
get to questions about anything related.
So,
okay, next part of the setup is just the
config. And there are various
different config files that we'll have
to set up to make this work. The witness
config is called wit opnet.json. The
paths are all there on the setup guide
itself. In this particular instance, the
wallet will allow for a onewitness
configuration where you're with your
AID, you're going to set up one witness
or if you've got your configuration set
up right on the server, it'll allow a
three of four, meaning that it'll the
threshold, it'll it'll have four
witnesses available and it'll require
three of the four for it to be
considered fully witnessed. So this by
doing this four times, four different
instances of the witness service, we're
kind of faking on one host being able to
have that 304 configuration and test
it out without actually having to spread
that across multiple different servers
or data centers or whatever.
And that's what the configuration file
looks like. That C URL is that
URL is the will be the base URL of what
the witness communicates back to the
wallet for OOBIs and things like that
come as we get into that point. So, so
those as the as the guide
describes, you'd have a different copy
of that with a different port for each
one of those. Whatever ports you want
really, but in our case, we did 5632,
5642, 52, and 62. Those are the ports
that we're running on our
infrastructure.
Wattupnet.json is the watcher config.
It's very similar pretty much the same
structure just slight differences in
naming and the different port and in
theory you can I have not done this yet
but in theory the design is such
that you can run a network of watchers
as well we won't talk about that in this
particular session because we I haven't
actually done it so we're not quite to
that point but you can do that
and then finally we'll set or next sorry
next we'll set up some launch
scripts for Each of these services,
these are just shell scripts that invoke
the various different packages. Well, in
this case, it's just the witnesses with
the setups. Again, pay a special
attention to the HTTP and boot port.
Those will those will conf have to
those will those will conf have to
coincide with what we put into the
previous config. Make sure that those
ports align.
And that will be used for the public and
and that will be used for the public and
the internal private communication ports
that it'll use.
The 5631 in this case is the
internal local loop back communication
that it port that it uses.
And then the wnet similar thing watcher
and then the wnet similar thing watcher
network same thing. Same kind of
stuff. Set this up to your liking,
but for the most part that's that's
the pattern. So,
and then the boot script, the KF boot
boot service has a bunch of environment
variables that we have to set up to
make this system work, make it all
communicate well and keep track of
itself and all that stuff. The one that
we want to sp pay special attention to
in this particular thing this
particular demo is the boot witness
backends. This is a string of multiple
witness IPs with the with the following
pattern witness ID internal IB IP and
port and external IP and port. As you
can see at the end of this string here
it starts after the comment starts into
the next one. So, by doing that with the
mo the all four of those
configurations, that's basically what's
going to tell the wallet to allow a
three of four configuration because
we're telling it there's four different
witnesses to choose from. So, we've met
that requirement for the wallet to be
able to enable it.
Those IDs are AIDs or
they're just they're just arbitrary
witness IDs. You can call them whatever
you want. They're just an identifier
internally.
So they're actually like literal wit
wit one wit two that's the literal
name or ID for this purpose.
And then
and then
next step is
circus install. Now technically in the
guide I think the circus install is at
like set step four or five and then the
circus configuration is at step eight or
nine. For this presentation I kind of
combined those. Circus install you can
do whenever you want and you know before
you configure it. And circus anybody
know what circus is? Anybody? Okay. So
circus is a process manager. So, it's
the thing that's going to actually
manage the launch and the state of the
Python processes themselves, the
witness and watcher and boot service
processes themselves. So, we're going to
put together a config file as it shows
in the in the guide there. An any
file that has all the run scripts for
all those different things and Circus is
going to manage all that. So all you
have to do is run one circus command to
start them all up and you can get status
from it and all that stuff as opposed to
running them all independently.
And then along with circus we're going
to set up systemd with the systemd unit
so that systemd can manage circus so
that it boots on startup and you know
keeps the state and the logging of
the circus process itself. So it's a
little bit two layers deep when it comes
to that.
So you can restart these services
either with circus
Or at the global level with s
with systemd
and then finally
Engineext setup
to be able to if you want to have TLS
term termination in our case we wanted
TLS for the initial communication so
that was all encrypted and then
subsequent communications all signed and
all that stuff anyway. So you don't
have to set up the TLS stuff, but we did
in our case.
And I've done this on two different
and I've done this on two different
machines. I've done it on KERI
Foundation is providing
The one we'll show I'll show. I also
have my own that I set it up on as
well that is fully TLS like all the
endpoints are encrypted with you know
running over TLS.
And that's pretty much the long and
short of the actual setup. So if you do
want to try this out by all means go
ahead and you know follow through that
setup guide if you've got servers of you
want or your own you want to try it
on. I mean, you're going to have to have
them, obviously, or a Docker container,
whatever. You can just follow along
through that. And it should get you
up to where you're ready to try it
out and see how it all goes. So, that's
pretty much it for the setup guide
itself. And there's a couple more steps
in the guide, but they're mostly, you
know, setting up the firewall.
Tada. Yep. That's because my slideshow's
over.
Oh, sorry. Okay, I'm in the wrong. You
guys aren't going to see this yet, but
any questions so far?
Anybody have any
Come on.
So, what is the boot doing exactly? It's
it's going to it will create the AI.
It's a it's the basically the control
plane for the witness and watcher ser
network them themselves. So when we
first launch the I'll kind of walk you
through it. Let me oops wrong thing.
Let me get my display in the right place
and I'll
There we go.
me open up the right project here.
So this is in theory I think I cleaned
myself off enough that my environment
off that we're starting entirely fresh
with a new deployment. So we're
going to initialize a new vault. We'll
just call it test.
I'll give it a
passcode.
a new AID. So now I have the new AID.
Nothing special yet. Now all that does
is the local key the local AID and in
the inception event in the KEL
locally. So I'm not talking to anybody
yet. It's just a local KEL has an
inception event in it. You're not going
to see that here but that's where we are
at this point. And then from here I can
go into the car's KERI Foundation
plugin. This is this is an adaptation of
what healthcare provided for us. So Evan
did a bunch of good work to turn
this into something more useful for us.
Good job
and for all you to use. So you can see
it's connected
To this particular host which is the
KERI Foundation host. I'm going to
choose
my AID and the profile that I want,
which in this case is three of four. And
then when I click this begin onboarding
to answer your question Joseph, it's
going to hit that boot service to
basically make the introduction and
initialize the process of provisioning
witnesses, sending back the URLs for the
OOBIs and taking it through that whole
process of introducing the
witnesses, sending a rotation. Since
we've already done an inception, it's
going to do a rotation to rotate the
witnesses in based on what the boot
service is returning back from the
witness service. Does that make sense?
Ish.
Well enough. Get into the code, you'll
you'll get it.
So now fingers crossed. If I did
so now fingers crossed. If I did
everything right, this is the big moment
of truth when I'm going to click a
button and hope it does something.
for some reason. I' I literally never
seen that.
Looks like it's trying to do something.
Oh, it failed.
Am I connected to the internet? Make
sure that all works.
The Wi-Fi here isn't super fast, so
See if the one of
Yeah, we could try that.
So, you can see it's doing some stuff,
but it's bailing. I don't know what
that's about.
Oh, I might know what it is. Sorry,
I'm gonna KEL my session there.
I was running in debug mode. I wonder if
that's just slowing it down too much.
There we go. Getting a little bit
better. Can see all the stuff that's
happening here.
This is gripping.
watching this work, right? Everyone's on
the on pins and needles like, is it
gonna work?
Shazam.
What made a difference?
I was running in debug mode on my IDE,
which was just puts too much overhead
into the process. It was just too slow.
So, what I can do now with this
QR code
is I'm going to scan it into
I'll use AY for this one. Any
authenticator app should work fine.
Okay. Okay, so now it's I've got it in
my authenticator app and then I can go
back into the plugin
and this is just a demonstration but
I'll I'll go to the credentials. I have
a schema that's a test schema that we
use for issuing credentials and I
will
Local ident oh I gota I got to upload
the schema first. Sorry.
Downloads I think.
So I'm adding this particular credential
schema. Going to use that for issuance.
So is that's an ACDC?
It's just a credential just a schema
for a credential. It's not necessarily
an A or is it an ACDC?
That's a good question. I think it's I
think it's just a credential, but that
is a good question. I have to look at
it. It's just a test one that we've got.
And now I have to authenticate with my
authenticator.
And now I've issued a credential, which
is nothing more than a little test just
to show that it worked.
And there you go. That's a basic rundown
of setting up the W using the code
that healthcare
Has open sourced providing it to you
guys to all of us to start to build
on deploy on test with all that kind of
stuff. We're we're fairly new to it
ourselves on the KERI Foundation team.
So it's it's been a cool
exploration and a cool process. So,
Any questions
any
anything else you want to know about
witnesses, watchers deployment, any
of that stuff?
Yeah.
So, how is this whole infrastructure
different from what the packaging was 3
months ago when we done doing the
hackathon?
packaging.
Oh, I honestly don't know because I
don't know what was going on with the
hackathon.
This all this code came from
healthcare. So, it could be the same
stuff to be honest,
but I don't know what the hackathon was
doing. So,
I mean the de the witness
is from KERIpy.
Yeah, there's a witness inside KERI
Pie, but that was added by Phil in the
early days. It's wasn't like, as you
said, production grade. So a separate
service because you know KERI bite is
just supposed to be core.
Right. Yeah. Yeah. Yeah. So this is this
is a separate deployment a
whole separate project that is for
deploying witness a witness network
being able to put up a whole so as I
went back to in the in my earlier slides
in a production demo or a production
environment that variable that I was
showing you that had all the different
configuration in it that wouldn't be all
on the same host those would be pointing
to you know the boot service itself
would probably run independently
pointing to various different endpoints
across cloud and whatever other
infrastructure you want. So,
and you can run with a single
witness, but the wallet can't connect to
a single witness.
It can. Yeah, actually that's that's one
of the options in here. I'd have to
create a new one to go back to it. So,
you can choose one witness and deploy it
that way if you want. The ultimate
KERI idea is that you want to have a
lot of witnesses, but if you want to
just run one, you can certainly do that.
And it works just the just the same way
it does here.
It did in the demo anyway. So, any other
questions?
Is this useful? Yeah.
What does circus add instead of just
using systemd? Nothing really other
than it's just a nice little wrapper for
all the Python stuff, but you could do
it all with system Oh, systemd for sure.
Handle it that way just as easily.
Circus is just the Python native way of
doing systemd type stuff, right? Service
management
kind of. Yeah, it's not service
management, process management really. I
guess it's service management. Yeah.
It's it's kind of scoped at the project
it's it's kind of scoped at the project
level. I mean, Circus gets installed
with the project as opposed to at the
system level. Generally, I guess you
could maybe do it that way if you wanted
to, but generally at least what I've
seen, Circus is usually kind of part of
it's a Python thing that gets installed
with your dependencies as opposed to
being part of the server infra or server
toolkit.
And now I would like to do some tap
dancing for you.
Is that good? Anybody questions? Is this
useful to you?
We want to see everybody get out
there and start trying to use it. Get
it deployed, give us feedback, make
suggestions, whatever. Like I
mentioned the this particular
infrastructure that I connected to is
the healthcare sorry is the u KERI
foundation
u deployment of these services which
right now is for just demo purposes.
You're welcome to actually use it. I
guess I'll show you one. I don't
remember if Jay covered this or I
might have missed it in his demo,
but as it is right now, when you launch
the
Locksmith code, there's a few
environment variables that you have to
set up so that it knows how to go and
discover the witnesses that are avail
or the witness service that's available.
And those are right here that I
set up in my configuration for running
Locksmith locally.
So that's the host if you were going
to try to use this. That's the host you
would want to use to use our
infrastructure. We'll put that out there
somewhere at some point publicly.
Means that means that's part of where
means that means that's part of where
the UI
Yeah. So the so the first phase of it
when you first create an AID and click
the button it's going to hit this URL
here for onboarding to make its kind of
initial introduction. It'll use a an
ephemeral AID to make the first
connection and say that it wants to
connect and then from then on it'll use
the account after it's set up what's
called basically an account
relationship.
It will use the account URL for
subsequent
Some of the subsequent calls, some of
them go straight to the witnesses, some
of them go through the boot service.
Yeah.
A little tangential, but between the web
GitHub or the KERI Foundation GitHub
work,
it's a thin it's a it's sort of a blurry
line at this point, but the KERI
Foundation one came along later because
the KERI Foundation itself came along
later. And probably
if I were to guess eventually KERIpy
will move into the KERI Foundation org
if it's worth the trouble of moving it.
Maybe not. They're both SAM that
created both of them. So the
distinction is more logical than
physical. You know, it's not much in
other words. We created these ones in
KERI Foundation just because now that
the foundation exists, we want to start
kind of centralizing some of this open
source open source stuff related to
KERI into that particular or
cool. I mean I have nothing further
unless you have any other questions.
All right. Thanks everyone.
[applause]