And so we need to so accountability is
about imposing posing those things. So
since any since you can be correlated
anytime you share data with a second
party eventually with repeated
interactions they're going to know who
you are and then they can share that
with anybody they want unless you impose
on them some sort of liability that says
I'm afraid
or I'm I'm worried about the cost. I'm
worried about something that you've
imposed on me some externality that says
I'm not going to share this data. I'm
going to respect your data rights. So
any interaction system that does not
enable first parties to hold second
parties accountable is fundamentally
incompatible with privacy. It's it's not
going to be privacy preserving. It's
going to incentivize them to share your
data and violate your privacy rights.
Sorry about that. Good.
So how we do it
is we understand that the only thing we
can do
is to create confidential contexts
which are protected from third party
surveillance and within those contexts
impose liability on the parties to the
confidentiality that changes their
behavior. That means that we have to
either use a combination of economic
Legal, civil, contractual means or
regulatory means and potentially
criminal means. You know, I think one of
the Utah guys talked about whether or
not sharing your data was a form of
treason. He says, "Oh, that's a that's a
really that's a really great predictor.
You guys are all treasonous. we can we
can shoot you because you're because the
the law the law for treason is
death. So anyway, he was a joke, but
I thought it was fun to talk about
that. Right. So we want to create
control safe relationships where the
interactions are protected from
surveillance by third parties and second
parties are held accountable for any
information shared with or by them. It's
not just shared with them. It's not just
one way disclosure.
We also want to hold them accountable
for what they what they do, right?
Because safety is about what is incoming
as much as it is what outgoing. If I go
someplace and I want to be in a safe
environment, I don't want people calling
me names, being vulgar sharing stuff
with me that I don't want to I don't
want to see treating other people
badly in my presence. That's all part of
the environment. So you need to hold
everybody accountable for their
behavior. That seems very nanny state,
but actually it's what a refuge and a
sanctuary is. It's the ability for you
to decide what interactions you have
versus other what interactions the
internet forces on you. So we use this
model.
Okay. Basically two parties are sharing
information.
It's always from the view of the first
party. You're the first party. What else
did you care about? Third party
observers may obtain information in this
model indirectly metadata because they
observe metadata because this is going
over the open internet. The open
internet has to be routable. That means
routing metadata is public. That means
there is no privacy on the internet
because if routing meta data is public
then everybody can correlate who the
parties are at either end. It just takes
time. It is it is there's fundamentally
no ability for you to have that
interaction without it eventually being
correlated. So what you have to
understand is that metadata is the
problem. It's not the data that's in
here. It's the metadata about here and
the Supreme Court has defined it that
way. You have protections for content
data and no protections for non-content
metadata. So I can encrypt the content.
I can't encrypt the metadata and
therefore the metadata will always be
leaky. It'll always provide correlatable
information. So what I have to do is I
have to build an artificial construct
via tunnels so that I tunnel stuff
across the internet so that the tunnel
itself
is content data relative to the internet
so that its metadata is content at
another layer. And if I do enough layers
of tunnels, then I will have a layer
where the metadata is sufficiently well
protected that it can't be surveiled
from the outside. So we can make a
highly surveillance resistant
communication channel, right? So if
If the sharing is leaky,
there's enough metadata, right? Or
they're using intermediaries, then
they can surveil that. if there's any
kind of collusion, right? So, so the
way we're defining privacy is when third
parties have no knowledge of who is
sharing information, then we have
privacy with regard to third parties.
And confidentiality is when third
parties have no knowledge of what is
what was shared. So if the second party
shares with the third party, they broke
confidentiality.
If the third party if the second party
shares with the third party who they are
or who's in the party, then they broke
privacy. And so that follows the Supreme
Court definition of privacy and
confidentiality in terms of how we
reason about it. And it's
important because if we lump these all
together under one term, then we get
confused when we start talking about it.
So I try to be really clear and not
get confused about it. So this is the
the TSP and I leveled SP back
because the name of the protocol when I
wrote the white paper was secure privacy
authenticity and confidentiality and the
header to the header to the
introduction of the protocol says the
goal here is to get the best privacy we
can given we make no compromise
compromises on authenticity and
confidentiality.
So we start with the strongest possible
authenticity, confidentiality and then
work backwards to figure out what's the
best we can do. And the reason for that
is that in my experience as soon as you
compromise on authenticity and
confidentiality you end up with more
leakage pass more opportunities and the
net result is you have less privacy
overall. Whereas if you start with
privacy, you make hard trades that you
can never recover from in on the
confidentiality and confident and
authenticity part. And that means fraud,
that means identity theft. And if
you're worried about somebody knowing
who you are because your metadata got
leaked and tracking you, then you then
you have to make a judgment decision
saying, "Well, what's what's more
important? they know who you are or they
steal all your money, right? For most
people, stealing all your money is a
much bigger harm. Now, there are corner
cases where knowing who you are can be
really bad, especially if you're a
criminal and you're worried about
going to jail, right? But that but
that where you're a dissident and you're
worried about being repressed.
So, the core of the protocol is a triple
tunnel.
So, we have a tunnel between A3 and B3.
Oh, here I can do it over here. Can you
guys see the cursor showing?
No cursor.
It was there a minute ago. Oh, I guess I
guess it disappeared. All right. Anyway,
so it's a triple tunnel. So I
have three pairs of identifiers. A3 B3
A2 B2 A1 B1. So endpoint A has three
identifiers. Endpoint B has three
identifiers.
Those identifiers are not mutually
correlatable. They're independent
identifiers. What would make them
correlatable is if they were exposed in
such a way that the context
correlated them, but they're they're
high entropy identifier. So they
don't intrinsically convey any
information that says they're related.
So the fact that it's B1, B2, and B3
doesn't mean anything. They're just ran,
you know, pseudo random numbers, right?
The other the other the other important
distinction is to understand that
clandestine surveillance and counter
surveillance for clandestine stuff is
purely ephemeral
because clandestine says,
I'm not detectable. I'm I'm going to
minimize my detectability as much as
possible so they can't tell what's
happening. Covert says I have an overt
detectable
identity
that confuses the surveiller into not
looking underneath the cover of what I'm
doing so they don't detect the thing
that I'm doing. And for persistent
counter surveillance, I want to I want
to be covert.
If I'm if I'm clandestine, usually
that means it's a very short op. It's
only going to happen for a short period
of time cuz eventually I'll start to
leak stuff. And once they start to leak
stuff, there's nothing stopping them
from come getting me. Whereas if I
cover, they're confused. They go, "Wait,
well, no, he's he's not a problem,
right? We don't we don't see that.
And the covert stuff allows me to hide
things in ways that I can't hide it if
I'm clandestined. So the idea is that
we're basically creating two cover
identities to hide this guy. And so they
have to pierce two covers. They have to
burn two covers to get to get what
get what we're doing. And the reason
it's two covers is because
intermediaries. So what happens is I
create and I'll go to the next one.
I'm going to introduce the concept of
relationships. So remember I have three
three pairs of identifiers. So I have
relationships between two identifiers
and the relationship can be birectional
or unidirectional. And this is important
because
A can talk to B using a different
triple tunnel than B talking to A. And
that removes a form of correlation of
metadata. So we don't necessarily want
it to be birectional. We want we want to
be completely independent and be
unidirectional or not. What that does is
that we can then define a relationship
graph of all of our identifiers
and everybody else's identifiers
and every pair of identifiers forms a
relationship. And in that relationship
we have routing data and we have
identifiers on both ends of each of
those relationships. And what we're
trying to do is make it so the metadata
in those relationships is hidden so that
it's not surveillable.
And when I say not surveillable, not
easily surveillable. Everything is
surveillable, but you know, you want
to make it hard enough. And if you think
about this, this is a selfidentity
graph. This is all of my identifiers and
my data and attributes. And a
relationship graph is just the
intersection of multiple identity
graphs.
Right? So when I go when I was here,
I got controller A and notice it he's
got multiple identifiers A 1 through 4.
Right? So his identity graph is that
subset of this graph, right? But when he
then forms relationships with B, then
then those two graphs intersect.
So that so if you haven't figured out I
I love graphs everything my brain just
works in graphs. I just everything I
everything I think about is just like oh
I can graph that right and then I can
reason about it. So relationships
properties I know this is a little small
there's a lot of them a cryptonym is a
cryptactly derived pseudonym with at
least 120 bits of entropy that so we
don't have any ability for anybody
to discover
anything about it because it has enough
entropy and AID is a cryptony that is
also securely attributable to one of our
key pairs right you guys know all this
stuff but some people that cack
especially when we present the tsp P
which is like sort of the trust of P's
generic version of it. They don't
understand these things. So
relationship is just a pair of two AIDs.
So two AIDs because they're with high
entropy are uncorrelated.
There's no from an information
theoretical sense there's no knowledge
that one AAD provides about the other.
People say things like, "Oh, they're
super they're super cookies or they're
super correlators." From an information
p point of view, they're not. The only
thing that correlates them is the
context of their use. They themselves
have zero correlatability. They're
totally random. That's what high entropy
means. So, if I don't use them in the
same context, they can't be used to
correlate me. The only way they can be
used to correlate is if I use them in a
context and the context leads to
information that allows the correlation.
It is the context that is the
supercorrelator not the identifiers.
So a context is a set of events. So we
got to define that two contexts are
disjoint with respect to an AID when the
AID appears in one or more events in one
set but does not appear in the event in
the other set. If they're disjoint,
they're not correlatable.
Right? So the goal is build non-cor
build disjoint context. We want to
partition our context.
A relationship is not a communication
channel but the event sent over
communication channel may be a context
for the AIDs in relationship. So as
soon as I start sending information I
create a context and that context may
correlate me. Interaction graphs are all
about correlating using context to
correlate things.
A partition is a set of contexts with
mutually disjoint relationships. I'm
being kind of mathematical here. Any set
of relationships using one relationships
identifiers may form a partition. So
that's how we get
disjointness. We only use an identifier
in one context.
And if that context could potentially
form a partition, therefore I'm not
correlatable outside of the context.
Partition relative to other contexts.
Any two member two member contexts of
a partition may be correlatable due to
other information associated with those
contexts, but the partition
relationships by themselves provide no
correlatable information. Partition
relationships are by themselves not
mutually correlatable. The relationship
isn't the problem. It's the context.
Think context when you're worried about
correlation. Don't think identifiers. We
sort of have inverted that when we talk
about linkability because we say
cryptographic unlinkability is about
identifiers. No, it's about how you use
the identifiers in what context. That's
where the correlation comes. It's a
subtle nuance. It's subtle. I get it.
But it's very vitally important if we're
designing protocols to understand that
subtlety. So an AID common to any set
subset of events within a context
provides a perfectly correlatable
feature across those common events in
that context. Now why do we want
perfectly correlation within a context?
We want perfect correlation within a
context so that we have accountability.
That's how we get accountability. You
can't do something and not have me know
that you did it. So I have
non-repudiation. I have absolute ability
to point the finger at you and say you
did that. If you leak if you leak
information, I know you leaked it. So
the so as soon as we weaken this and
use identifiers that are not perfectly
correlatable, we lose accountability.
And so the whole goal of what we're
trying to do is to create safe contexts
we just threw away. We threw away before
we even built anything. We started with
something that's broken and we can't
build it. We can't build it from there.
We have to start with this and then we
have to isolate the context.
So within a context secure
attributability together with perfect
correlatability across that context
ensures reputational trust. I just said
that in a different way. Accountability,
right? If I put a gun to your head, I
know what you're going to do. Right?
That's reputational trust. Yes.
Do you see any situation when you would
want to not have accountability?
Oh, yeah. There's lots of situations
like that.
I'm not precluding those.
But when I'm talking about internet
safety and I want to I want to have
valuable relationships with value to me,
then they're not valuable unless there's
accountability. Yes.
So the signal people really
emphasize deniability.
Yeah, that's a really good question. So,
I can look up two papers for you. The
BYU security research group did two
several papers they published and they
asked the question, is deniability
actually what they say it is? And they
and the answer was no. People want
accountability, not deniability.
I' I've heard that as well. I've also
heard studies that no jury has ever used
this alleged cryptographic property to
do.
That's right. That's the other thing
they found out is just that they
claim it, but it but they won't the
judges and the juries won't enforce it
because they don't see it as a
is as something that they can
adjudicate
and I believe it actually breaks
down the device case, but that's a
separate Yeah.
It doesn't work in any sense.
Yeah. But the conclusion was
it's a false concept. it's
fundamentally designed as a way to
advertise the fact that you don't have
the good properties you want but you
have other properties that if you're
criminal sound like they're good and
actually they are for criminals, right?
But you're not, but if it doesn't
protect you, the noncriminal, it's
actually it's actually harmful to you,
the noncriminal, because you're the one
who's going to be exploited by the
criminal who has deniability, and you're
expecting that you have some recourse or
protection, and the law says, "No, no,
we're not going to give you protection
because they don't believe they should
protect criminals." And deniability
says, "Oh, you're a criminal then, so
we're going to go after you anyway." So,
I'm I'm summarizing, but you should read
the papers. They're pretty good. Just
look up BYU and deniability. There's two
papers. Yes.
In use cases where you might need
deniability like voting, you wouldn't
use this. You'd use a different
protocol.
Yeah. Because one of the thing one of
the core tenants of voting is that you
can't you don't want to allow
repression of voters by exposing their
votes. You want to have a blind vote.
And so if you can tell what a voter did
and what they said and hold them
accountable, then that has all
kinds of bad effects.
So you would use your you'd use your
KERI
for the ticket and then you exchange
the ticket.
Yeah. You want you use KERI for the
voter ID, not for the voting.
Yeah.
Partitions balance. This is the
reason why we talk about partitions.
They balance these two things. strong
authenticity and strong confidentiality
within a context. So that's one side. We
get accountability when we have
authenticity and confidentiality.
Confidentiality isn't really about we
actually get we actually get
accountability with strong
confidentiality when it's a symmetric
with sufficiently strong privacy
between contexts. That's how we do it.
We say okay I want context with high
accountability. I want to sacrifice that
because that's where most of the value
is. But I want to have a partition. So
what can I do to make the partitions as
strong as possible? I can't make them
impervious, but I make them strong
enough
that the that the tradeoff between
account value from accountability and
the loss of value from surveillability
or trackability or something else is on
the SAID of what I do. And we can do
really good stuff here. And often I get
in conversations where I criticize the
privacy community and people get
defensive and they think that I'm just
throwing the baby out with the bath
water. No, I'm going to great lengths to
do everything I can to make those
partitions as strong as possible, right?
I'm doing everything I can, but I'm
never going to sacrifice these two just
to make it easy on me to make those
partitions strong. I'll have to do more
work to make the partition strong. Yes.
You mean you mean privacy or
confidentiality in the last statement?
No. Privacy.
Confidentiality is easy. Privacy is
what's hard. Privacy is knowing who's
who's the party.
Explain what it means to have privacy
between contexts.
The parties in each context you
can correlate. So if I go to a bank and
I'm interacting in my bank context and
then I go to Walmart and I interact my
Walmart context, Walmart and the bank
can say, "Oh, you're the same person
that they broke the partition.
There wasn't a partition there." And so
tracking and surveillance is about
aggregating context because that's how
you that's how you gain value, right? I
need to know how you use,
you know, like what your behavior is. If
I want to advertise to you, I want to
profile your behavior. That means
tracking you across contacts.
So, you're saying I if you think about
all of those interactions as building a
a connection graph,
interaction connection graph
the ability to define those connections.
I want to be in control of the
connection graph.
Yes.
that I want to make it so that there
that they there is no correlated build
metadata whenever I interact, right? So
that they can't build the interaction
graph. I'm I'm basically looking at what
NSA funded in the post 911 world. They
spent
lots of money I developing software
that allowed
surveillers to build interaction graphs.
So they would know that if you're
talking to this person, they're talking
to that person that somewhere in that
network they're talking to somebody that
that is a bad person. And so when
you do a FISA warrant, one of the things
you do is you say, "How many hops is it?
a one hop fight a warrant, a two hop or
a three hop, right? Well, one hop is
your immediate connections in that
interaction gas. Two hops is two hops
out. Well, well, seven hops is the whole
world, right? So, a three hop FISA
warrant is a pretty broad warrant,
right? And people go, "Oh, well, you
know, right?" So it doesn't take
much, but it takes a lot of work to
to fight that. So, so let's see how
we do that. All right. So here another
acronym park portable authentatable
reputable contextual cryp cryptonimity
that's doesn't roll off the tongue very
well.
All right. So first we have to
start with how we make the strongest
possible authenticity and
confidentiality. We're not going to
sacrifice that. And this is called ESSR
encrypt sender sign receiver.
What it looks like is I create a
message. I have cipher data. Inside the
cipher data, I have source identifier.
So that's that's encrypt sender. Here's
the data. I then have a destination
identifier that's within the block
that's signed. That's the sign
receiver part. And then in order to
verify the signature, I need to send the
source identifier. So the source
identifier shows up twice because I need
it to verify the signature.
What that does
is it satisfies all of these and I'm
just going to go through these. You can
go read these papers, but basically
there's been this tension and this goes
all the way back to my rate days of
what should I do? Encrypt then sign,
sign then encrypt, sign and encrypt,
right? Well, these are the properties I
want. I want third party unforgeability
plain text. Third party unforgeability
cipher text receiver unforgeability
plain text receiver unfortibility cipher
text. The only one that gives me all
four is the SSR.
And signed and encrypt only gives me
one of these. So it's really bad.
So what I want to do is I want to do
ESSR. And this is so weird because this
is like a paper from 2001
that nobody paid attention to, but it
like is tells you exactly. And now, you
know, 18 years later, everybody's
worried about key compromised
impersonation attacks. And the IETF 9180
Hybrid public key encryption standard
basically says, "Oh yeah, you can't do
it with encryption. You can't do it with
chems you can't defy helman you
can't you can't solve this because it's
it's vulnerable to key compromise
impersonation attack but ESSR isn't and
so they say you got to sign so if you're
not signing you're vulnerable right so
every protocol on the planet that
doesn't sign is vulnerable to one of
these
so let's go back I already did this
yeah that's just a copy of that slide
okay so let's look at the this is a
little complicated. I'm going to skip
through this. I don't think you want all
this.
Yes.
How many P and Q's do I have to mind in
order to get privacy?
How many P's and Q's?
Minding my P's and Q's. How many of them
do I need to?
I don't know what you mean by is that a
joke?
It's a bit of a joke.
Okay.
How many? But you have you have one P
and one Q. Is that all I need? Because
that's not very many. I can surveil that
right
one. No, no, the triple tunnel. I'll
have to explain how the triple tunnel
works. So I
So Sam,
I think I need to Oh, there I Yeah, here
we go. Seeing a single tunnel. Yes.
So one of the things you said a bit ago
that I think everybody misses in this is
is your connections to me, at least
visually, are loosely analogous to
unidirectional onion routing.
Yes.
But the other part of that is there's
more than one AID.
Yes.
And that's a nuance I don't think I've
ever heard you say before, but it's an
important one because the correlation
that people complain about, including
myself, is reusing AIDs. And your
other diagram showed that you don't do
that.
No. No. Yeah,
that's important.
That's why I said it's covert. I have
two AIDs that are cover identities,
right?
That they're me. So, what is a what is a
covert op? A covert op says I have a
cover identity. So, let's say I'm
I'm I'm going to go to some foreign
country and I'm going to dress up and
act like a shopkeeper.
Actually, a good one for World War II is
I'm going to get a job at the train
station as the ticket taker at the
train station. So, I'm going to spend
years building that cover identity. And
during the time that I'm building the
cover identity, I'm clean. I'm doing I'm
I'm just I'm I'm spotless. I don't do
anything bad. Right now, I have this
cover identity and everybody trusts me.
I have this reputation that says I'm the
ticket taker at the train station. But
guess what I can do now? I can surveil
people that use the trains and if I have
a dead drop someplace, I can share that
surveillance information and nobody
goes, "Wait a minute. Who's that guy
standing at the train station just
watching everybody?" And they're going,
"What's he doing there? Why is he there?
He's surveilling." That's right. That's
the But if I'm a ticket taker, I'm there
every day. It's my job to be there. So,
yeah, give me your ticket. Oh, okay. Who
are you? Oh, yeah. Who are you? Okay.
Yeah, I know who everybody is getting
the in off the train, right? So, so
nobody suspects me as surveilling
because I'm supposed to surveil as part
of my cover identity. So, this is great.
So, what we want is a cover identity
that says we're doing something that is
innocuous, that doesn't reveal any
information, but we're going to use it
to cover something else we're doing that
the surveillor can't see through. Right?
So, the first cover identity is that I
have an endpoint and I have an
intermediary and I have a pair of AIDs
that allow me to communicate to the
intermediary.
It's perfectly surveillable.
It's from the privacy point of view.
These two are used to route information
between them. Right? I can I can encrypt
the content. So I have confidentiality
but I have no privacy. That's okay. This
intermediary has a cover identity P and
Q that allows these two to talk
together. Right? And then I've got a Q
to B1. So here's the path. So my
packet's going to follow this path. Now
what's not shown on this graph which
makes it really complicated but is vital
is that an intermediary what does an
intermediary do? It routes. So if it's
if it's an intermediary of any value
there are 100 or a thousand or 10,000
Q's that P talks to.
So when Q when P sends out a packet,
it's got to hurt privacy of a
thousand because any packet it sends out
addressed to any of those Q's is
uncorrelated with a packet I send to P.
Somebody can observe this pack and they
go, "Yeah, well it went here and then a
thousand packets came out here. Which
one is it?" I don't know. Right? That's
that's essentially how onion routing
works.
The problem is that intermediar P has
to know which Q A wants to send to. So
he's now a problem.
And intermediary Q needs to know how to
send to B, right? So he's a problem. So
so I can't just tunnel once because
the intermediaries can disclose the
tunnel. So what do I do? I add a second
tunnel. I've got A2. Now A2 is
encrypted.
So intermediary P doesn't see A2
because it's content data relative to
the pink. So now interp doesn't know
where the packet's actually going. It
just knows that I need to forward it the
next hop. And that's all it knows,
right? And Q, right, needs to he is
the one that has to unwrap this one to
know to get it to B2. So he's still a
problem. So now I do the triple tunnel
and A3 and B3 are not known by any of
the intermediaries. They can't see it.
So what I So the reason I need three
tunnels and only three is because I
want the intermediaries to not surveil
it either and they're second parties,
right? So I have third parties that
that can surveil this. I have second
parties that can surveil this, but
nobody can surveil this. So, I don't
need onion routing. I don't need 20
onion routers. I need two intermediaries
with high fan out and high fan in.
That's it. So, it's inherently easier to
build. Any internet service provider can
build this. And they and they're not
a target for law enforcement because
they're doing onion routing. They're
just doing what they're supposed to do
efficiently route lots of packets. Yeah.
It seems like the subtlety is that we're
talking about routing at an application
layer versus routing at an IP layer.
Well, no, no, it's it is it's both,
right? Because I have to route at the IP
layer.
But that's the IP layer routing is
right inconsequential. Well, well, no,
it's not because this one here, the IP
layer routing correlates to this and so
it defeats me. But at this
layer, then yes, IP's gone at that
layer. No more IP. So, so I've done two
things. I've gotten rid of IP because
it's in this layer and now I'm in a an
application layer and now I'm in an
application layer inside the application
layer. And that and so it took three. I
took me a while to figure it out. I had
to li, you know, that's why I have these
diagrams with all these, you know, 50,
100 symbols on it because I'm keeping
track of every piece of metadata and I'm
going, who knows what metadata? What can
they surveil? And after I got to three
tunnels, I said, "Oh, wow. I don't need
any more. I didn't know. I thought I
might need four or five."
If the routes were isomeorphic, then it
all collapses. Right.
What do you mean by that?
If the if the route for if the pink
route is the same route
Oh, yeah. That's why I said you have to
have a fan out. You have to have high
fan out.
It's not just fan out. It's it's that
there's there's randomization of the fan
out.
No, you just have to have white noise of
the fan out. So there's two ways to
do that. One is you can try to randomize
or two is you make sure that the
probability is uniform. So you have a
uniform distribution. And the way we do
that because we can't manage the
randomness, what we do is we make sure
that there's no correlatable metadata in
the packet itself. That means the
intermediary, if they're a good
intermediary,
will send data on all of their fan out
to maintain a uniform traffic level so
that you can look at and see a burst of
traffic from here and then see it
populated.
That's practical.
Yes, it's absolutely totally practical.
Every TCP connection does that anyway.
It does that anyway.
So, so, so we're not we're not adding
any net traffic.
Huh?
Can be bursting.
Yeah, it can. But, but then you do you
do scaling. You do elastic scaling to
handle the burst. So what we're saying
is that you design for a certain
level and then you can either decide
here to look at your own statistics and
decide to delay or not send based on
your statistics,
right? And every packet is the same
length. So yes, if you're trying to
build optimized routers, you don't like
this. But if you're trying to build for
privacy, you want you want uniform. You
want white noise and so what is
more efficient? two intermediaries with
high fan out and uniform distribution or
20 nested the tour routers
three minute warning.
Okay,
just real quick. So on that diagram, P
is aware of A and Q.
Oh, sorry.
And Q is aware of P and Q. Well, in
order to route the packet from endpoint
A to endpoint B, you have you have to
you have to send the route with the
packet,
right? No, I get I get that. I get
that. My question is what if P and Q
collude?
So, so if P and Q collude, the only
thing that they can do is DDoS this
route. That's all you can do. They can't
expose it. They can just break it. So
that's you're always vulnerable to that.
So if you're worried about that, then
you send the same packet by a different
route. You do you do
multi-perspective routing so that you
have multiple intermediaries. So if two
of them collude, it still gets through.
And that's why having it not be
channelbased but be totally asynchronous
and unary instead of by you know
birectional unidirectional allows you to
do that. And since all the messages have
cryptographically secure unique sets you
can you can figure it out at the other
end that they're that they're you can do
duplicate detection triply with
with duplicate detection replay attack
cra. Where's the cra guys?
There you go. Sorry. I was looking for
the first I was looking for the first
shirt like this. Yes. So, so, so, so
you do things like that to protect it.
But those are good, those are all
good questions. So, we added to the
protocol. So, so we just need that
that would be all that's required. But
we added another protocol because we
found that it would be useful and that's
a relation formation subprotocol. What
that allows us to do is that once we
establish a route and I won't go through
all this. Okay, I'll go back. Once we
establish A3 and B3,
we have a secure private channel.
We can use that channel to create other
secure private channels. And all we're
doing is saying, I've got an A4 and I've
got a B4.
And we'll we'll form a relationship with
those two. So now within this context I
can create other secure contexts
and when I create those I can exchange
routing data that says move A4 and B4 to
a different set of intermediaries.
So now I can use one of these. I can
stand this one up and then I can do
Do this on steroids because I say
okay the first five packets we're going
to use this one we're just going to
we're going to create A4 and B4 and part
of the information we exchange is a new
set of new pair of intermediaries that
we're going to use and every time we
send a message every day we just create
a new one. So every day we have so we're
having one-time use contacts and onetime
use contacts are highly un
uncorrelatable
because you're you're minimizing the
amount of correlatable data because
you're creating a new a new pair of
non-correlatable identifiers within a
secure context that does that is that's
a partition. So you can create
partitions on the fly as many as you
want
which satisfies all the usable
properties that people have for privacy
without sacrifice a wit of security or
confidentiality or authenticity.
We're done. All right.