Yeah, Mark, do you want to start with
your intro and then Scott and then I'll
Yeah, we can do that. So, we're
going to be talking about KERI vLEI's
and so forth. So, let's see if we can
bring that up. So, I'll kick off. I
apparently you guys were talking
yesterday, so people may know you. Yes.
I'm I'm new. First time here. It's
been a while since I've been in Utah. My
name is Mark Scrimshire. I'm chief
interoperability officer at ONYX.
And we focus really on
interoperability largely in the payer
market for
I suppose a bit of background about me.
I was actually
invited to go into CMS back in
To build Blue Button 2.0, which is an
API for 53 now 60 million Medicare
beneficiaries to be able to share their
data
with the apps of their choice.
That led to me now being retained by HL7
where I've written some of the other
implementation guides that CMS points to
in their regulations. So, I'm very much
focused around how do we take secure
APIs and operationalize them.
So, that's the really the focus and that
is how it's drawn me to
KERI and the way that we can
potentially solve that. So, gentlemen.
Yeah, so let me go next. So, my name is
Scott Stuewe. We did talk a little bit
yesterday. I'm the president and CEO of
DirectTrust and we're a nonprofit trade
association that supports trust in the
healthcare ecosystem broadly and
actually increasingly we're we're
describing ourselves as somebody who
cares about trust
focusing first on healthcare. But so,
we're with the with the understanding
that healthcare is adjacent to virtually
every other sector in the on the planet.
And in particular in this country
healthcare and financial services are,
you know, deeply related. My
background is mostly in the healthcare
IT space. I grew up working in the
healthcare IT, the e- the electronic
health record business. Watched that
business kind of grow and but
I've also been involved in
interoperability and identity kind of
from the very beginning of my career.
Worked as a what they used to call an
interface guy. You remember what that's
like. So, doing
business-to-business interfaces before
that there really was a
thing called interoperability. So,
I've been doing this that was that
started that life in '93. And then in
the late part of my life in the EHR
business, I actually worked on trying to
get healthcare information exchange to
work as well. So, we have that
commonality. My I'm more of the
marketect. I think arguably he's more
of the architect. So, Yep. And I'm just
the marketer, right? That's the So, my
name is Jared Jeffries. I'm CEO and
founder of healthKERI. As the name
suggests, yes, we are all in on mDL.
That's what we do pretty much every day.
that's what we do pretty much every day.
No, we
[laughter]
We have
seen the light and have decided to
roll this innovation that Sam
kicked off into healthcare. This
really started for me about 15 years
ago. I had a job at a law office. My
role was to try and get paper
records, medical records from point A to
point B. And felt like I was going
insane because I had a supercomputer in
my pocket, but we couldn't get data
moving around inside of healthcare. So,
You know, 15 years ago I really
started to say, "Okay, somebody's got to
be able to solve this problem."
And that's that's led me up to here
and that's that's led me up to here
and to starting this company. So,
Excellent.
So, we're going to cover a couple of
things
as we go through in really talking about
how we're we're really taking things
like vLEI and really applying them into
really
increasingly established
protocols and technologies that are
being used in healthcare because I think
if we go back to some of the things that
that Sam was mentioning, we've really
got to try and make it easy for
For organizations to take that first
for organizations to take that first
step and start to get comfortable with
the technology.
And so we're doing a we'll talk about
it later of a particular we're trying to
get a pilot off the ground that is very
very focused.
But once you see that, you can then see
how it could be applied in many
different
Situations across healthcare. So
we'll go through all of that. We'll talk
about that for fast security
explain a little bit about that because
that's driving how the healthcare
industry in the US is going to be
basically connecting to each other.
So
let's go and let's talk a little bit
about some of the problems you
Yeah, sure. So the challenge we have
is that the healthcare ecosystem is
immense and diffuse and also has a
need for connectivity which is extreme.
So
a lot of this is already connected in a
way. A lot of this through
intermediaries.
So when you look at the numbers though
it's just this kind of staggering story
about the different kinds of
organizations we're talking about. They
all have
protected health information that is
fundamentally what is the sensitive
information that needs to be moved back
and forth. It needs to be encrypted all
the time. Needs to be protected. So
getting this stuff to actually work
is first of all a problem of scale.
It's a huge a huge problem.
Now interestingly when you look at the
providers
providers don't really have very good
identifiers. Payers don't have
identifiers at all. Like so
literally are unenumerated. When you
hear about when you hear about
there's a there's a
public database you know, federal
database called NPPES, which was
originally in its conception designed to
enumerate both payers and providers, but
in the end only ended up successfully
enumerating individual providers.
They don't do organizations very well,
they don't do organizations very well,
and they don't do payers at all. So,
next slide. Yeah, well, can I
just put a little bit of
note on that as well, which is that the
the onboarding process for the NPPES
system is really light.
You know, Ryan House, who was here
you know, Ryan House, who was here
yesterday, didn't mention this in the
conference there. He has an NPI
number. He is not a clinician. He does
not provide care for anybody. But on
a lark he decided to go see if he could
get himself an NPI. So I asked him
what code he used. I think it was
probably therapy. So, if you if you need
a shoulder to cry on,
Ryan House [laughter] is your Ryan's
your man. Yeah.
Yeah, so I think the next slide we
actually kind of get into the NPI
question, I think on the next So, the,
This is sort of the we can't ask
this answer this basic question. So, the
onboarding process for all these
organizations and the onboarding process
for our CMS is weak at this point.
They're looking to strengthen it. I
think they're talking about
strengthening it and including
you know, I O 2 identity assurance as a
part of the process. That's something
that they've said they're going to do.
Unfortunately, that's only the very
smallest part of the problem. So
the manual onboarding that these
organizations do with networks, for
example, is a tremendously onerous
process on the one hand, but also not
standardized. It's standardized in
policy in theory. So, in other words,
there are a couple of big national
networks one called Care Quality,
one called TEFCA. They're are very
similar. They are almost have the same
participants. One, you know, came
first and the other one kind of came
second as an effort of the government.
And so the 11 different organizations
that operate the TEFCA ecosystem, those
11 different they call them QHINs, each
have to onboard the organizations to
those various places. And the way the
topology of this stuff works is that the
people who are connected by one QHIN
then are passed from the QHIN to another
QHIN and to their
participants and sub-participants. And
this weakness, this these extra
hops, basically means that the people
who are receiving messages have no idea
who sent them the message cuz there's no
actual understanding of the of the
organization across that boundary. So,
there's also no universal organization
ID. So, particularly, the only thing we
really have that does
organizational vetting is the issuance
of a digital certificate, which is
something Direct Trust does at scale
today for a whole bunch of
organizations, but it's not really all
that useful to tell you about the
organization. It just tells you that
this person has control of this domain,
which is not all that useful,
particularly if patients are trying to
find where their doctor is, which is one
of the problems we're trying to solve.
Is if I've got a directory that has a,
you know, listing of all the places my I
might look, how can I tell which one is
where my doctor's stuff is? So, it's a
big problem.
There's also a big deadline. I can maybe
talk a couple of things here. So,
you see digital identity, individual
identity there.
That doesn't solve the problem. My
sister's a doctor in the UK,
and you know, on Monday she would be
working for one organization, on Tuesday
for another. So, it's all about context.
So, you really need to be able to tie
that organizational identity and the
individual so that you understand what
context they're actually acting in.
Now, the other thing that we were
about to get to is CMS 0057. It Sorry,
it rolls off the tongue. We add the two
zeros, so it sounds a bit like James
Bond. But it isn't. But this is
really mobilizing the industry because
CMS a couple of years ago put out
regulation. And remember, CMS spends
what, about 1 and 1/2 trillion dollars a
year, which they give to
basically payers around the industry. So
they hold the purse strings. So they put
out regulations that basically say,
"You need to do this."
Right? And 0057
really does a couple of things. One,
it's expanding patient access. So if you
if you have a
A plan with a Medicare Advantage
organization, a payer you're allowed
to go and get your health data that they
hold. Now, what they're doing is they're
adding in prior authorizations to that.
The other big thing that everybody's
focusing on this rule is
providers are going to be able to submit
in a standard way a prior authorization
request and get an answer from the
payer.
That means you've got a secure API, and
you literally going to have tens of
thousands of provider organizations
having to talk to a thousand different
payers to get an answer.
Today it happens through provider
portals at the payer, through faxes,
through phone calls, all of these
things, no standard way of doing it.
What CMS has done is saying,
"This is an API standard to do
this." And so everybody's busy
automating that, and the deadline is the
1st of January, 2027. So we are about
7 months away. I
And I'll say one other thing here. If
if you're interested in fire, my session
later today talks through I think in
depth what fire is, how it works
at a at a very atypical or a technical
level just to kind of put some
definitions in there.
Yes, so a lot of the CMS series of 570
is really driving the adoption of fire
fast healthcare interoperability
resource specifications.
That drives a standard way of
that drives a standard way of
expressing exactly what you want to do.
So here's a patient record, here's a
coverage record, here's an encounter
record, etc.
So the industry, particularly the
payers, are busy implementing this and
hopefully also the EMRs will as well.
So I think we can
go on.
So Yeah, let me So this is sort of the
nature So interestingly you know
United Health Group and actually most
payers are publicly traded companies. As
a consequence, they actually mostly have
LEIs, which is actually a useful thing.
But also just to understand the
challenge of the complexities here,
Disambiguating an organizational
unit over here, the names of these
these health insurance
organizations. So if there are 1,100
or so, some of some, you know, I don't
know, 10 or 12 of them are actually
under United Health Group. And so for
you to find
for you to find a health plan that's
associated with United Health Group, you
need to understand what the LEI can
provide for you, which is the who's your
daddy problem, right? So all of these
all of these children health
insurance companies roll up through
United Health Group. Now not shown
on this slide is the complexity
underneath United Healthcare Services.
UHC UHS actually operates
an incredibly complex network of
variable kinds of organizations, some of
which are actually provider
organizations. One
One of their subunits is called Optum.
They're actually the largest owner of
providers in the country.
The largest
employer of providers in the country.
And they roll up through a company
that also has a bunch of health
insurance companies. So it becomes very
important for us to figure out
you know, I'm not just talking to UHG.
That would help me in no way at all if I
want to figure out what the bonafides of
this organization are and what frankly
they ought to be able to do on the
network. I need to know exactly what
organization I'm working with, but also
I probably need to know more about that.
I actually need to know
if they are bonafide for a given purpose
of use. You know, who says that they can
And there's actually a huge
controversy right now on the care side
relative to whether or not you are
bonafide for treatment. The question of
whether or not a provider, just a
provider who's making a KERI
can do so on the basis of treatment. In
other words, that they're actually
treating a patient at this point.
They might work for a
law firm at this particular moment. They
actually are practicing provider and
they might work for all sorts of
other companies potentially. But they
that they shouldn't be able to
operate in that context if they are
working in that particular setting. So
understanding where they are really
literally, but also
what is the purpose of use that they are
That they are bonafide for.
Great.
And Scott, I think
Yeah, I'll just really quickly sort of
what our role is and I think
we're going to move into a very much
more technical mode here after this, but
one other little thing I
can say is that
we play this role today. Our when I talk
about our community, we are we do not
ourselves issue anything. We are a
we're a non-profit trade association.
Our members are the operators of a very
large healthcare network that actually
operates a PKI framework for that
purpose. So, and if you actually pull
back the covers on what Direct Trust
does, it looks oh so very much like what
the VELI ecosystem looks like. So, it's
it's actually a very good map in terms
of how it would look cuz we're
fundamentally a governance
a governance engine. We're not a
we're not you know, we some people argue
we're not even a network, but we do
operate a network. This idea of our
accreditation process is what gives us
the ability to make sure everybody's
doing what's right associated with the
governance not just of our governance
expectations, but also for expectations
of external sources of truth like
853 or 863 as we were talking about
yesterday. If it's
identity assurance or if it's
taking care of your cybersecurity
bonafides, all of that stuff is what we
do today.
And I think it's important to note Sam
said this morning that
the technology doesn't solve the problem
alone. And I think increasingly with
with Daniel's presentation earlier
with what we're talking about here, you
do have to go get the stakeholders from
the governance side involved because
because you can have the best technology
in the world, but if you're not solving
the policy concerns you're not
going to get to actual results. Yeah.
So, just touching on the scale of the
problem
what we've seen if I go back to the
work I did with Blue Button, you would
have individual consumer apps coming and
trying to connect so that they could
then have a member use that and give
them permission to go and get the
data. Well, we built at Donex we built
an app
you know, get my
get my data, and we wanted to connect to
health plans across the country so that
you could go to this one place, you
could
find the health plan,
authorize sharing, pull the data.
We actually got 350 health plans
connected,
but it took us about 6 months.
Because everyone you had to go
individually to the to the health plan.
And this is where you've got like an
Aetna and they've got 47 plans.
But you rapidly get down that
curve where you're talking you run a
plan, you've got an API, I need to
connect to it.
And the process is a manual back and
forth. You answer the same
50 questions 150 different ways at every
different
Plan.
And they'll finally decide that they're
going to give you access. Under the
regs, there's very little they can do to
refuse.
So it's a heavily manual process. So as
we were looking at this requirement to
do things like providers have access to
payers to pull data about the members
they're treating
or to be able to submit a prior
authorization
or for one payer to connect to another
payer because a member's moved and they
want their data,
you get this
Math problem of the number of
math problem of the number of
connections you need to make. And we
need to
we are not going to be able to
operationalize the APIs if we cannot
find a way of basically automating this.
And so this again comes back to this
core issue that particularly in health
care space,
we don't have a standard identifier. We
haven't got an easy way to identify. And
in fact, the plans tend to push away
from that. You know, talking about
having a national plan ID you know,
it's taken years and it's gotten
nowhere.
But we do know as you said Scott,
there's about 90% of the health plans
already have an LEI.
Right? So that they're they're already
on the slope. We've got to just prod
them down there. Yeah, and I imagine
Carla can tell you it is a very
laborious process to get your LEI. I
think it's about $50 and what a day, 2
days if you've got all the
documentation.
15 minutes of actual real work. Yeah,
yeah. Complete completely untenable for
the industry to adopt, right? Yeah.
Can't be done.
Yeah.
So let's go into what we're we're
really trying to
propose here. So the first thing is that
let's get people from an LEI to actually
having a digital credential for the
organization. Okay?
That brings a whole bunch of benefits
and Jared, feel free to chime in on
this.
But really what we're trying to do
but really what we're trying to do
I suppose I should take a little bit of
a diversion here and talk a little bit
about TEFCA from the payers'
perspective. Scott, you mentioned, you
know, there's a lot of the providers
have gone into TEFCA. They were in
CommonWell. They're probably still in
both.
The challenge is that you to get into
TEFCA, you're then agreeing to do
Basically return information about
treatment in multiple different
formats. And so the payers are looking
at this and saying
I'm going to have to respond to a whole
boatload of queries. I can't really do
the same in the opposite direction. So
it's very imbalanced and a lot of this
stuff I don't want to be dealing with.
I'm I'm worried about January 1st,
2027 and getting my fire APIs
operational.
I don't need to worry about having to do
IHE
Formats and so forth. So
formats and so forth. So
they've been resistant. So how do we get
them moving forward? And this is really
the first step. Yeah, one other
reason why they're resistant is they
already have the data that they are
required they're required to ask for in
this new model. They're like, they
already have this data. They've done
individual data sharing relationships
with all the electronic health record
companies. So, they don't see the value
proposition. So, it's like you can't
really get them interested in TEFCA. And
so, they want to try and do something
that is extra TEFCA. I like to call it
extraterritorial.
Yeah. Yeah, and really the
purpose there is that then they can
start to set the boundaries for the
connections. Right. So, CMS has said
this is what you got to get stood up.
It's got to be fire APIs. But, in terms
of the value for the payers, it really
comes down to and you know, Phil did
this demo yesterday and I'm sure he'll
talk a little bit more about it today.
It's that idea of can I take a
member's request and bring it through
from one payer to another payer to pull
the data back out through. And that's
what they're trying to get solved here
that doesn't get discussed as
deeply in TEFCA, but will be incredibly
relevant for the CMS 0057 connections
that are required by January.
Yeah, so the key thing as we as
we're looking at using vLEI is really
being able to identify who is the
organization,
what's the purpose of use, and who's
actually been delegated the authority to
actually engage into those transactions,
right? And I'm basically coming this
at this from a very simple perspective.
And I've been in calls where
we start going down the digital
identity, the individual identity route.
And I'm saying, "No, no, no, no.
What we're actually trying to do here is
you've got this first step of actually
getting secure APIs connected. And how
do you have confidence that the
organization that is representing
is actually who they say they are and
the person that's trying to
Do that setup is permitted to do it.
And there's multiple types of
transactions we're talking here, prior
auth, payer to payer, provider access.
So, how can we
really start to bundle that together so
that you can answer that question and
ultimately be able to automate it?
So, this is where Jared and I are going
to try and make Phil at the back there
cringe as we try and do more of a
technical
explanations.
Yeah, so let me let me just run through
this at a very high level and again
point you to some of the stuff that
Phil's going to be presenting later
today.
The way that VC this is that there's
with some minor augmentation at the
ECR level,
what GLEIF has done with the vLEI is
actually pretty much perfect for
this use case. It's it's purpose built
for what we're trying to do here, which
is if I don't understand the other
organization on the other side, then the
GLEIF ecosystem solves this problem. And
I would So, just raise of hands, is
anybody in here not familiar with the
vLEI's architecture, how they lay these
things out?
Okay, then I think we can go very
quickly through this just to say that
all the way down at the bottom, the ECR
credential piece, that's where there's
going to be a lot of work done I think
with direct trust and others in the
industry to determine what is purpose of
use. And we're starting with payer to
payer, but the amount of ECRs that
you can issue within this ecosystem that
is specific to healthKERI is
incredibly valuable. So, everything that
we're doing, we really want to keep it
as stock standard vLEI as we can to
the point that if there are vLEI issuers
that are working on, you know,
issuance outside of the healthKERI
industry, we've really pushed to say the
VLEIs that operate there should be able
to operate here. Now, one of the
questions that we had was, okay, well
let's say you've got Bank of America and
they've got a valid vLEI. Just because
they have a valid vLEI, can they come
into the healthKERI ecosystem to one of
these payers? Can they go to CVS Aetna
and ask for your data because they're a
validated organization? The answer is no
because in that ECR credential space,
we'll have specific purposes of use that
we talked about already. Yeah.
And I think that's key and
obviously by being more precise about
the purpose of use. So, whereas TEFCA is
basically you join the network and
anybody within the network we're seeing
now some of the legal challenges
saying are you really who you say you
are? And you are you able to really
ask for that data?
By being very precise about the purpose
by being very precise about the purpose
of use, it actually potentially
simplifies the policy framework that's
got to be around that.
You know, to the point of one of the
things I'm proposing is
in fire, we actually create
implementation guides that define
effectively a use case for the standard,
right? And so, each of those I Gs has a
canonical
you know, basically URL that you can
reference. And that could be a mechanism
for actually defining the purpose of use
because what you're saying is
within an implementation guide, there is
a
API for doing, for example, provider
access.
And so, there's actually a canonical I
know I wrote it.
You know, so
you could define that as something
unique that everybody then understands
this is the transaction type that I'm
engaging in.
So, we're really then leveraging
particularly down the ECR credentials to
define those purposes of use.
So, it really goes this way. We
get an organization gets their
organization credential.
We're looking at the fact that
there are going to be people within the
organization that will actually
do the transaction. So, in somebody,
for example, in an IT department or in a
compliance department is going to be
responsible for
making sure that these connections get
created. So, should they have been
delegated the authority to do that?
Another thing, with just the complexity
of healthcare, I mean, we
by the end of this year, we will
actually represent the interoperability
capability for more than half of the
Medicaid agencies in the country. Right?
So, we are operating on their behalf.
So, they would effectively, if they
brought into this, would have a VLII for
the Medicaid agency,
and they would have a delegation of
authority to ONYX to be able to go and
set up these connections with whoever
they wanted to
set up.
And similar to the provenance use
case here, that is incredibly
essential, right? Because
while we will want ONYX and others to be
able to act on behalf of those Medicaid
organizations, we don't want them to be
confused in the pathway, right? You
still need to know whose throat you can
you can choke, essentially. Who's it
going up to? Yeah, exactly.
So, we're building this effectively
this chain.
One of the things we're suggesting is
also
putting when you make a connection, what
typically happens today, we can get into
the technology of smart on fire, so it's
the issuing of a credential to allow
you to now effectively open up the API.
You normally that's just a transaction
you normally that's just a transaction
between the two parties. What we're
saying is, well, what happens
if the party that issues you that those
credentials, so payer A goes and says,
"I want to connect to payer B for
payer-to-payer."
When they issue the relevant smart
on fire credentials so that the APIs
work, what if they give back a
credential that says, "Payer B has
approved payer A." And now you put that
into the package.
And now you go to the next payer, payer
C.
And you can already you can actually
present to say, "I'm already connected
somewhere else." You get to a point
where a payer is going to go,
"What the hell am I doing by trying to
do a manual verification of you when
you're already connected to another
bunch of folks in the
in the network?"
So that then starts to lead to
you can automate the process of
actually registering. So it goes from
being, you know, as
being conserved at $2,000 at a time to
hundreds of dollars a time.
Right? Just because you can now
automate. And as long as it we can use
the capability in the in the VELI to
say, "Well, if there's a bad actor,
they can be revoked."
You can check that.
And therefore there's confidence in the
network. Yeah, I really want to hit this
this concept here really hard, which is
that
Mark has coined it as
connectedness is trust. And the way that
I put it is trust equity. The reality
is that for every organization, every
single connectivity point that they have
to operate today is a is both a
bottleneck and a cost center. It you get
nothing from it other than the
connectivity. It is a bother, and once
you're done with it, you go to the next,
and you repeat that entire process. And
the VELI allows you to start to do this
connectedness is trust. You start to
build a trust equity within your
ecosystem with those back filed
credentials that say, "Hey, we're
connected. We've done the check. We
trust who you are." And at a certain
point you get to a
the opportunity to actually look at one
of the
biggest monoliths in healthcare, which
is the clearinghouses, and say, "We
don't actually need to rely on you to do
our network of connectivity anymore.
Because one of the problems that
healthcare has right now is you've got a
monopoly of a few very small parties
that are making
rent-seeking to the tune of billions of
dollars on facilitating all of this
exchange. And that sounds fine, I guess,
if it was just that problem. But one of
those clearing houses was Change
Healthcare that got blown up and it's
been 18 months now. And you go ask
some of the mom-and-pop clinics that had
to fold up shop because Change got
got completely destroyed in an attack.
What we're talking about here is an
alternative. So if you go talk to an
Availity, if you go talk to one of these
large clearing houses, their answer is,
"This is a solved problem. Just be our
customer." And the contention that we
have for the entire industry is that
that's a really, really bad idea because
we don't want to centralize power into a
few different, you know,
Private organizations as they move
forward. Now, I don't think the
clearing houses are going anywhere.
But what we do want to present is an
but what we do want to present is an
alternative where you can build your own
trust equity, you can build a network of
connections, and you can do it
automatically and at scale.
And I wasn't here yesterday, but Ryan
was.
When we first presented this concept to
to Ryan, and he's been very much
promoting this,
the first words out of his mouth were,
"Is this open source?
Because if you're going to get this
adopted across the industry, you don't
want those barriers to implementation.
That's been one of the real benefits of
HL7 and the fire protocol because that
was made open source. Anybody can go and
look at the specs, they can they can
take them, use them. There's no barrier,
whereas, you know, we're we're looking
at X12, and I have to go and buy a
license every year just to look at what
the spec says, right? So we don't want
that barrier. And so that's really
important. One of the features that
KERI brings is this open source
Basis.
So, anyway, let's So, let's talk about
this
What we're actually trying to do
here. There's a couple of initiatives
going on.
TEFCA, as Scott mentioned
is really this national network. It's
largely providers. Payers haven't leapt
into it yet.
There is an organization an accelerator
there is an organization an accelerator
fast fire at scale task force.
It started as part of the ONYX
initiative, but now is an official
accelerator within HL7. And they're
really looking at how do we build the
infrastructure to enable all of this
interoperability.
So, it really is an underpinning of
of fire. Now,
they have an implementation guide. They
have multiple. Fast security or fast
security for scalable registration,
authentication, and authorization.
Terrible.
But it's one of the longest.
but it's one of the longest.
That is actually in regulation saying
that is actually in regulation saying
TEFCA is going to use that. And that
defines the mechanism
for basically acquiring those smart on
fire credentials to do a connection
between
two organizations.
So,
that is in there. Now, the fast that
fast security
protocol implementation guide is
extensible.
And that's what we've really tried to
leverage here in saying, "Let's use the
vLEI
and all of the associated credentials
to make it easy for an organization to
move into this and have more confidence
in who they're connecting with."
Ben just says, "One thing about this
that in its first iteration, this was
expected to be an X.509 certificate that
That anchored these connections
for organizational security. So,
this idea of being able to have clients
dynamically register with servers and
get, you know, so that they can
eliminate that
excess topic was initially imagined to
be a strictly a an X.509 exercise.
Yes, so
I suppose as an a SAID, I actually trace
the dynamic client registration protocol
in a OAuth 2
is really there in what we call SMART on
FHIR. Okay? So, it's the mechanism of
getting connected. So, you've got this
ability to get credentials. Dynamic
client registration has been there in
the OAuth spec for years.
And I can trace it back to in 2015, I
wrote a blog for the for
the Department of Health and Human
Services about
how could we actually
really leverage dynamic client
registration? Nobody used it because
they didn't trust who was coming in and
saying, "Just register my app."
And so,
I went to I think organizations like
DirectTrust and a couple of others and
says, "Is there a way that you could
tell me whether the person that's
actually submitting
can be trusted?" And so, that really
emerged into what is often referred to
as UDAP, but if you're talking to the
FAST folks, if I say UDAP, someone's
going to come out and punch me. It's
FAST security.
So,
what that's done is basically put an
X.509 certificate on top of dynamic
client registration so that you can say,
"I know who the organization is.
Here's all the information you would
here's all the information you would
normally have plugged into a developer
portal. Go register." Okay?
What we're proposing is using the
extensibility in fast security to
say, let's add some additional an
additional
cryptography check, which is for the
vLEI. So, that you can put the vLEI in
there and I know Phil's going to be
cringing at this because I'm not as
expert as he is.
You can
you can
basically reference the vLEI I'll
call it the vLEI package. So, all
of those bundles of credentials
and validate that they are legitimate.
Right?
And so,
what we're also in there is
effectively setting a confidence factor.
Because if you are able What's going to
happen is
it's we have this crazy scenario. You go
and talk to health plans and they
basically say,
we're trustworthy. It's all those others
out there that you cannot trust them,
you know, at all.
So, there's a problem with looking in
the mirror and really saying, you know,
am I trustworthy?
And so, we've got to we've got to try
and break that. So, what happens is they
are going to want to manually valid-
validate anyone that even submits
this.
Right? So, what we're saying is let's
allow them to configure a confidence
factor. So, if you pass that threshold,
you could be automatically registered,
go into get DCR runs, you get your
credentials, and away you go. Yeah. And
I So, I want to call out a couple of
things on this slide in particular
that I think
a staunch KERI advocate would
bristle at. One is the word OAuth
2.0 and the other's token grants. And
I know that there are people in the room
that look at that and go, well, why?
Why do that at all? Like if KERI is
what KERI claims to be and I think we
all believe that it can live up to its
promise,
why go backwards? And the reality here
is similar to I think what
Provenance is doing with Telco, you've
got to meet the market where they are.
You have to come to people and say,
You have to come to people and say
You know, we're we're just adding a line
you know, we're we're just adding a line
for that kind of cryptographic proof on
the ecosystem. And that's one of
the most common questions we get as we
start to go into the pilot on this
is payers saying, "Well, are you trying
to rip everything out and replace it?"
And the answer has to be right now,
today, no. No, we're making an
augmentation that is that is incredibly
minor to gain a ton of value. Now, if
you ask me, maybe not on stage, my
answer might change and I say, "Yes, we
want to rip all this out. We think we
can do it better." But we're going to
walk people into that path, right?
Yeah. I mean, put this in context.
Back in July 2021,
All of these health plans that are
funded by CMS so the Medicare
Advantage, Medicaid chip plans, so
children's health insurance, and
Medicare
Care organizer MCOs, all of these
have to follow these CMS regulations. So
there's about a thousand plans out
there.
They have invested in fire
interoperability with smart on fire, so
with OAuth 2. It's gotten through their
security
teams, which is
a major thing. I you know, I took I
took this concept through CMS. I had to
actually explain what OAuth 2 was.
Now that's accepted. So really what
now that's accepted. So really what
we're doing is we're just adding an
additional check on top of that. So
you're building on top of something
they've already implemented, and we're
trying to make it really easy for them
to take this extra step and gain a lot
in return.
And the ecosystem also includes all the
provider organizations,
and they're all served by electronic
health record companies and each of
those electronic health record companies
have also made that same investment. And
so, as a consequence, what you've got
is, you know, tens of thousands of
organizations that need to make changes
to their road map to include new
capabilities. This is a whole lot harder
than getting you know, Google and
Apple to do something, by the way.
So,
so this is really where we're at. It's
not a replacement, it's one additional
check
is really what we're trying to drive
home here.
So that
so that
we take the extensibility of fast, we
leverage VLAIs in that with all of the
subsidiary credentials and you've now
got the ability to have more confidence
in
the organization that's connecting
to you. You can also define specific
purposes of use.
So, we're talking about payer-to-payer.
It is required for 1127.
So 1,000 health plans out there in
the in the US are going to have to
support payer-to-payer. So, when you
decide to up and move to the next plan,
as many of us do,
you can say, "Go get my data."
So, they're going to have to have these
connections. So,
rather than confuse things around the
fact that I've got tens of thousands of
providers
and that's complication,
say, "Let's get you comfortable with the
technology between people that you sort
of trust. They don't trust each other,
but they sort of do, right? Just a
little."
So,
we're trying to drive this as a specific
pilot, but if you talk to folks, I've
talked to folks in the Medicaid
agencies, I've talked to folks at the
various plans,
and their mind is immediately going,
"I may have to deal with a hundred
or a even up to a thousand health plans,
but I've got tens of thousands of
provider organization
And that's where their mind is already
going there. We just don't want to push
them there right now.
We'd rather them get comfortable and
then say, "But we can extend that."
Again, it's a it's a small step further.
But we bring them
Yeah, we're we're boiling the frog for
sure on this one.
Yeah, yeah. Totally. Totally.
So,
the other thing that is happening is
there's actually we get we get into
time, aren't we?
Yeah, you got about 2 minutes. We may we
may jump through them.
what we're actually getting to is we're
going we're proposing this CMS align
network. So, that's a sort of mini
version of TEFCA
focused on doing specifically payer to
payer, so we can actually prove this
technology in the wild between a handful
of payers and then scale it
potentially really quickly.
So, that's that's really where we're
going with this. And so, if we had we
were more or less at questions. So, I
don't know if you've got time for
questions. Yes.
I
love what you're doing. It's
really ambitious and it's obvious you
have deep industry knowledge. What I was
curious about was in particular the
notion of the canonical URL.
To me it seems like if
to me it seems like if
you cannot this city is associated with
the URL wouldn't that be an
anti-pattern? Would you rather have some
sort of canonicality that was tied to
the content itself rather than a path to
the content?
what we're really talking about is
what's the what's a shorthand for
example payer to payer? Right.
Right. And so, just trying to take the
easy path is there's hundreds of
organizations out there that are looking
at implementing payer to payer. And
they're going to have to connect.
They're all looking basically at the
same implementation guide.
And that we have scopes in those
implementation guides and one of them is
you're going to give a permission to
do, for example, a member match. And
that we basically
is embedded in the URL? Well, that's
you can effectively look up the
implementation guide by that URL, which
says here's the use case that we're
looking at. What we're saying is that
could be a short hand to include in
the
to put into the purpose of use because
it's very specific. It's about this
particular use case that's been defined
as a standard. It's interaction. Yeah.
Anybody else?
Okay. All right.
And after that question, we got a
great announcement of Jared.
Back in the
mid to late '70s, I was responsible for
a database called Sparks,
which has all of the admissions and
discharges from every hospital
experience in the state of New York.
And we traced the doctors and we traced
the organizations
without this then by their license
number.
And every state
in the United States,
there is a license number for doctors
and
Clinics and hospitals issued by their
clinics and hospitals issued by their
local
their state health department.
Why aren't you using that?
So let me describe
the challenge I think that
represents. I think So, the payers,
for example, free frequently use EINs
as a part of what it is they use to
identify organizations across
The ecosystem. The challenge here is
that these organizations, first of all,
operate across state boundaries. So
they're the meanings of those things are
going to change as you move from state
to state. The other thing that is
challenging about any of the enumeration
models you have today is that they are
they don't actually represent hierarchy.
And this is actually a real problem for
any of them. The biggest issue I see
is with type 2 NPI, which is what they
do for the healthcare
organizations. That is what CMS uses to
identify those organizations, but it's
not really the organization they're
identifying. It's a billing group, which
is not really helpful. So not to the
outside world. They don't understand
that construct. So getting something
that is universally understood as well
as disambiguating is the challenge. And
so it's it doesn't work if it's a
state-issued item because these
organizations are multi-state entities
with you know, children who are in other
states. So it's it's a complexity that
is difficult to manage.
All right. Thank you. YEAH.
[laughter]
[applause]
SO THEN BEFORE WE GO TO THE LAST plenary
speaker of today, I would want Yeah, so
so we've talked about this I think a
few different times today. I guess the
the announcement that I'd make for you
is and this is probably
deleterious to my own session. But I
would encourage you as you look at the
agenda for the rest of today and
tomorrow to bias your sessions towards
the Carrey Foundation sessions and the
sessions that are being hosted by Ari
and Phil. The reason that I say that
is because we have pushed a massive
amount of code into the open source
as a result of wanting to kickstart
this ecosystem. So we're talking about
things like witnesses, watchers and
the
wallet as well. So if you are looking at
the things that we're trying to do, if
you think you've got an ecosystem that
is
Very relevant here, I think we've
seen really common threads through Telco
and healthcare. If you have lines on
other industries, you want to start
doing these things we're we're
equipping you with all of the tools you
need to get started in that process. So,
again as much as I'd love to have a
full session later today, if there's a
competing session that's a KERI
Foundation or Ari or Phil I would
bias you towards those to go learn more
in depth about what exactly has been put
into the open source and what the value
is for you as an individual in the
KERI community. Well, first, a very big
thank you for donating all that code
into open source. Yeah, I it
represents literal man years of time,
so.
[applause]
Fantastic.