All right,
good afternoon almost. My name is
Thomas Mayfield. I'm here from the
Cardano Foundation. And I'm going to
be speaking today about Veridian. And
usually when I'm in front of this
majority of this group of people, I am
demonstrating what we've been building.
But today I have the honor of actually
providing a bit more of a ational or
academic. Is it not loud enough Jared?
Testing better. Excellent. Okay.
So my name is Thomas Mayfield. I'm
from the Cardano Foundation. And I'm
here going to be speaking a bit about
Veridian. And usually when I'm in
front of this group of people, I'm I'm
demonstrating the tech that we've been
building at the Cardano Foundation.
But today I have the honor of actually
but today I have the honor of actually
providing a bit more of an educational
overview of KERI and more
specifically speaking about the
concept of the five Ws. I will
intertwine elements of Veridian throughout
the talk. But I think the majority of
this audience, it's probably going to be
Already content you're very familiar
with, but hopefully for the viewers that
are going to be watching this online and
at home it's a bit more of an
informative content for them.
I'm going to put my timer on so that way
Henk doesn't have to give me a reminder.
All right. So, today I'm going to walk
you through the KERI infrastructure
using a framework known as the five W's.
Wallet, witness, watcher, web, and
wizard. And by the end of this talk,
you'll understand not just what each of
these roles are, but how they work
together as a system and also how Veridian
is building all of this in the open. So,
let's start with the problem. Digital
identity today is borrowed. When you
create an account, get a credential or
receive a certificate. You don't
actually own it. The issuer does, the
registry does, or the platform does. And
if that platform shuts down, that
registry gets compromised or that issuer
revokes access, your identity
effectively disappears with it.
You are effectively a tenant, not an
owner of your digital identity. But
KERI changes this. With KERI, your
identity is rooted in cryptographic keys
that you control. No registry needed, no
platform dependency.
It's portable, verifiable,
and it is yours.
So what is KERI exactly?
And I don't think anyone's actually said
the acronym and in the last few days.
So KERI stands for key event receipt
infrastructure and there are three core
concepts that make this work. The first
is self-certifying identifiers
and what this means is that your
identifier is derived directly from your
cryptographic keys. There is no registry
or registar that grants you your
identity.
The second concept is that every
critical action you take with that
identifier, such as creating it or
rotation those controlling cryptographic
keys, all of these critical events are
signed and chained into a tamperevident
log.
And the third concept is everyone can
verify your identity by replaying the
same tamper evident log. There is no
need for phone home to a central
repository or authority. And if you'd
like to understand a bit more about no
phone home, I encourage you to visi to
visit nophonehome.com
and you can read a bit more about this.
So this combination of concepts, this is
what gives us something that no other
identity system achieves and that is
truly portable trust.
So let's make this concrete. In KERI,
your identifier is called an autonomic
identifier or an AID. And this is a
cryptographic identifier that you
generate. Its authority comes from the
keys that you made. And no one else or
entity issues that to you. Every
significant action that the AID conducts
gets recorded in a Key Event Log and
that is called a KEL.
Your inception event, this is when you
create your AID. the rotation events
that change the AID's controlling
cryptographic keys or interaction events
that anchor data that is critical to
your AID. Each and every event is
cryptographically signed.
Each and every event is
cryptographically signed with the
previous one. And this is what creates a
tamper evident chain. If anyone alters a
single event in this chain, the
signatures break and the tampering is
immediately detectable.
If you're familiar with blockchain
technology, this is the same hashchain
data structure that makes blockchain
secure or immutable.
Now that you understand the foundations,
AIDs and kels, let's talk about the
infrastructure that makes it all work at
scale. And we've organized these into
five roles. And conveniently, Sam has
started them all with a letter W. So,
let's move on to the wallet. And this is
where your identity lives. It's the
holder's home. The wallet generates and
rotates the cryptographic keys. It
stores the verifiable credentials in
KERI. These are known as ACDC's. We'll
talk a bit about this later. The wallet
signs, presentations, and interaction
events. And it collects all of this and
it combines all of this with device
grade security. This includes
biometrics, your enclaves, and anything
else that occurs on the hardware device
itself. The key insights here are the
wallet is the only component that the
holder directly controls. The vital
functions of the wallet in KERI are key
management and signing.
At Veridian, we've built an open source
mobile first KERI wallet that is
production ready and available today.
You can download that from the Apple iOS
stores as well as Android Play Store.
and it is also available on the privacy
preserving operating system graphine OS.
Witnesses are the second W in the 5W
framework.
They are designated services that
receive, sign, and republish your key
events. You can think of these as
notaries for your KEL.
They give your event log a highly
available home so verifiers can access
it when your wallet is offline. They
produce receipts that prove the specific
event has been seen at a specific time.
And through redundancy of these
witnesses, we can resist censorship.
Critically, you choose your witnesses.
They are not selected or imposed by the
system on you. And at Veridian, we operate
witness pools that you can use directly
or you can host yourself in your own
infrastructure.
The third W is the watcher.
Watchers are independent observers. They
are critical to KERI.
Their job is to detect duplicity,
meaning they catch anyone who is trying
to present two conflicting versions of
the same Key Event Log.
This is KERI's answer to the double spend
problem that you have in blockchain.
But they do it for identity.
Watchers give verifiers confidence that
the state they are seeing is the latest
legitimate state of an identifier.
They run separately from issuers and
holders which means they are truly
independent.
This is what turns trust me into check
for yourself or verify for yourself. And
at Veridian, we are deploying highly
available watcher infrastructure
services in the second half of this
year. And I would be remiss if I did not
pay attention and show gratitude to the
healthKERI for releasing the watcher and
wallets to open source.
The fourth W is web.
This is the discovery and transport
layer of KERI. This is how parties find
one another and how they exchange events
and credentials and they do so through
something known as an OOBI. This is an
outofband introduction. You can think of
these as sharable links that bootstrap
trust between parties.
Effectively, these can also be assumed
to be QR codes that establish an initial
connection and from there mailboxes and
endpoints handle the messaging moving
forward. The design of KERI is
transport agnostic.
So today it runs over HTTP, but the
protocol doesn't really care about the
transport. It can run over Bluetooth,
over NFC. In fact, it can run across
anything.
And it's interoperable across different
wallets and agents.
Veridian provides hosted endpoints and
sandboxes from our data center in
Switzerland, including infrastructure
deployment guides for those that are
interested in deploying.
The fifth and final W, the wizard.
This is how we achieve one-click KERI.
For example, the majority of users are
not going to understand how to set their
witness threshold. Wizards abstract
low-level details of KERI and they
provide suitable defaults that ensure we
make KERI accessible but safe for
users.
For developers, we expose highlevel easy
to understand APIs to build on. And in
short, the wizard bridges the protocol
to the product. Without KERI, sorry,
without wizards.
Yes, without Wizards, KERI is a
powerful protocol.
With Wizards, KERI is a product that
you can ship to market. And at Veridian,
we offer one-click onboarding, witness
selection, and automated schema
discovery.
Now, this is the whole picture.
This is how they all fit together.
Wallets hold the keys and credentials.
Witnesses attest to events. Watchers
verify integrity. Wizards orchestrate
operations and the web connects them all
and provides scalability. Each of these
five roles are independently operated,
independently verified and uniquely can
be independently replaced.
So that's the friendly overview. We're
going to delve a little bit deeper and I
want to cover four concepts that take
KERI from an interesting protocol to a
production grade infrastructure. And
those four concepts are pre-rotation,
delegation, multi- signature control,
and ACDC's.
So we'll start with pre-rotation. And
this is one of K's most elegant
concepts. In fact, it was probably the
main concept that enabled me to
influence the board of the Cardano
Foundation to allow me to build on
KERI.
Pre-rotation,
as I mentioned, is one of the most
elegant concepts of KERI. At in at
inception of an AID, the moment you
create it, you don't just commit to your
current keys. You also include a hash of
your next key set. Those next keys stay
offline.
They remain unused
only until you need to rotate your
controlling key. If an attacker steals
your current signing keys, they cannot
forge a valid rotation event. And
because they cannot do that and because
they don't have your next keys, but
because you have committed a hash of
your next keys, that rotation is already
locked in and you can verify someone is
legitimate controller of an identifier
without publishing the public key. This
is extremely important.
This gives KERI something called post
compromise recovery. Even after a key
compromise, you can regain control. And
because of this commitment, using this
hash, we have resistance to future
quantum computing attacks. There is no
other digital identity system that
offers this level of key management
today.
Multi- signature control. This ensures
no single point of compromise for high
value identifiers.
An AID can require M of N signers. For
example, two or three board members must
sign to rotate the organization's root
key. The threshold can be weighted for
governance scenarios. Rotation events
are also respective of the threshold
rules. This means you cannot bypass
multi- signature control even during a
rotation event.
This is critical for enterprise AIDs
where a single compromise no longer
means the entire organization is now
compromised and game over. And Veridian
supports multi- signature control
coordination out of the box with our
Veridian wallet and our cloud agents. And
we handle the ceremony of gathering the
signatures across multiple parties
seamlessly for you.
ACDC's authentic chained data
containers. This is K's answer to
verifiable credentials, but they go much
further than the typical verifiable
credential or VC that exists in the
decentralized identity space. Each ACDC
is signed and anchored into an issuers's
KEL. So, its provenance is always
verifiable.
Schemas are composable and versionable,
so you can build complex credential
types from simpler ones. An ACDC
supports graduated disclosure where you
can share only the minimum information
needed for a given interaction. And
you'll notice on the slide that the
credentials chain back through the
schemas and issuers to a root of trust.
This is what authentic chained really
means. Every link in the chain is
verifiable.
And Veridian wallet allows you to store
and present ACDC's natively. It's also
important to mention that although the
wallet is storing a copy of your ACDC,
the way that ACDC's work, the way that
they are presented, if you lose your
wallet, you are still able to recover
those ACDCs because it is effectively
the keys that allow you to prove
ownership of those credentials. So, as
long as you have a backup of that data
somewhere, you can regain those
credentials or you can request that they
are reissued to you. This is extremely
powerful.
Delegation of authority.
This would probably be the second reason
I was able to influence the Cardano
Foundation to pursue this technology.
Delegation is how KERI handles
organizational identity. An AID can
delegate authority through ACDC's down
from a route of trust. GLEIF's VI system
uses exactly this pattern for
organizational identity within the
financial sector. A qualified vLEI issuer,
a QVI, receives a delegation from the
GLEIF's root AID, and then has the
authority to issue legal entity
credentials to other organizations.
That same authority can also be revoked
at any time. Delegated AIDs also enable
top-down hierarchical recovery. For
example, this is how GLEIF can recover a
compromised QVI's AID.
With KERI delegation, the trust chain
is always auditable. You can always
trace any delegated AID back to its
root.
So, at Veridian, we are building all five
of the W's. The open- source mobile
wallet. We are hosting witness pools and
self-hosting options for those who are
interested. We are committed to
releasing public and private watcher
services. This year we have hosted
endpoints, UB resolution, credential
management services, secure KERI
tunnels and identity access management
integration modules.
We have enterprise onboarding,
provisioning services, deployment and
infrastructure automation as well as
disaster recovery. All of this is open
source. All of this is production grade
and it is built in the open by the
Cardano Foundation. I'd now like to share
with you an overview of what it is
Veridian is aiming to achieve for the
second half of this year and into the
years to come.
Institutions cannot verify who they're
children with strangers. AI agents
execute
Today we cannot answer the most
questions on the other
age without
address
industry needs.
So I leave you with these takeaways.
If there are four things that I would
like you to take from this talk, it is
one, KERI moves identity from platforms
and registries to cryptography.
Self-certifying identifiers combined
with signed event logs mean no authority
is needed.
Two, the five W's make KERI concrete.
Wallet, witness, watcher, web, and
wizard. these five roles in one coherent
system.
Three,
pre-rotation,
delegation,
multi- signature control make it
enterprise ready.
Post compromise recovery, hierarchical
trust, and threshold control address
real world needs for the digital age.
And four, Veridian ships all of this open
source. You can start building today. If
you just need to verify, you can just
verify.
But it is all here available open
source. And finally, I'd like us all
please a round of applause and thanks to
Samuel Smith for his life dedication to
KERI.
I can provide the slides if you'd like.
If you go to the website, reach out or
just come speak with me directly. I can
share them with you. Thomas, thank you
for this great u presentation very just
actually your voice just brings peace.
But anyway, go going back to my
question is given that Cardano is it's a
proper blockchain I'd like to know
more how you leverage it. How I
assume witnesses or watchers are part of
the infrastructure that the ledger
itself provides.
So the Cardano Foundation
is a very different blockchain
foundation than the others.
We don't have castles and yachts.
But we do have a vision for what is
but we do have a vision for what is
the right thing to do for technology and
for people. And what we've been able to
do is actually build Veridian
completely offchain. And the way that we
actually leverage the chain is in a
number of ways. One we are also going
through the process of becoming the
first Swissbased QVI. So we Cardano is
the only blockchain that is vLEI
compatible at the moment as far as I'm
aware. We also have the only vLEI
compatible mobile wallet. We are working
towards a verifiable smart contract
format as well as a programmable token
that leverages KERI as the identity
layer for the token itself.
You can actually visit
verifiablesmartcontract.com
and see a report that was put together
between GLEIF Key State Capital and the
Cardano Foundation if you'd like to
understand more about that.
We're also looking at how digital
identity or decentralized identity and
Sam touched on this a bit in day one.
Every blockchain uses decentralized
identity as a mechanism to try and lock
you into their chain and to sell their
token.
And although this initially seems to be
a good approach they all fail.
they never have interoperability
and ultimately we are creating more and
more fragmented identity with varying
levels of security and recoverability.
What we've been able to do with KERI
Is we've created
verification across chains just using
KERI as that identity layer. So we have
worked with partners in Canada that are
using corder and we've created
verifiability of data between public and
permissioned ecosystems.
We've integrated it with IoT modules for
signing data that passes through sensors
to have an irrefutable audit trail
for emissions data on which actual
Canadian dollars were then paid out to
these participants.
But VC this as being an identity
that can work across any network, any
chain. That ne agnostic element of KERI
is extremely powerful in a blockchain
space.
So a very long-winded way is we are
we are integrating it into the Cardano
blockchain in ways that make sense but
recognizing that the identity must live
offchain.
We have one product as well called reeve
where we sign our financial records and
upload them to the blockchain and we
actually have had the auditor get
their vLEI and they are also signing our
testations and anchoring them on chain.
So this is the sort of direction we are
moving in as it pertains to the Cardano
blockchain itself.
When Midnight came out I thought
there was a you know a lot of overlap
with this. I don't know if you guys are
involved with Midnight at all or if
that's a sep separate thing. Can you
talk to that?
I can. I have a meeting next month.
We've had an initial conversation
with them. Midnight was looking at
DID methods in general. U for those that
don't know Cardano is broken down into
a number of entities founding entities.
One of them is input output.
This is a US-based entity out of
this is a US-based entity out of
Wyoming. Initially was founded in
Asia. The Cardano Foundation is
purposely put in place to ensure that
regardless of what happens with the
Cardano blockchain that web 3 and
blockchain technology drives forward. So
the mandate of the Cardano Foundation
doesn't say that if the Cardano
blockchain was to fail that the
foundation closes. Our remit is to just
drive decentralized technology in web 3.
Obviously we are focused in on the
Kanana blockchain. I know that they
are very interested in the power of
KERI and the value that vLEI brings to a
financial privacy infrastructure that
they are building on midnight. Midnight
is a privacy focused blockchain that is
being deployed by our partners in the
states. And we are having those
conversations now.
What's your what has been the
feedback when you talk to enterprises
and companies, corporations about what
you're doing, adoption. I'm just curious
to see what you guys see out in the in
the wild.
Sure. Absolutely. Well, nothing is
exciting us more than SEDI. But we are
focusing what we are building is we're
building tech that we can deploy across
five verticals. So we initially have
started focusing in on Switzerland
within the financial sector. We're
having conversations with financial
market infrastructure players in
Switzerland who understand the power of
KERI or more specifically the vLEI.
they understand there is an efficiency
of reusable compliance that is initially
attested by their internal compliance
team. One of the challenges here is
regulation. So specifically in
Switzerland, there is a stable coin
regulation that will come out in 2028.
There is also work that's happening
with the secure asset transfer protocol
that you'll hear a bit about later today
as well. One of the challenges here
is you need participants that are
willing to take a risk on a technology
Until they're mandated to do so by
regulation. So many people are open.
We are uniquely positioned to lower
we are uniquely positioned to lower
the curve of adoption. So we are going
in and speaking with these partners and
being able to deploy pilots and
demonstrate how the tech can be
integrated into their systems. When
we speak with other enterprises
What we actually do is we position
the value proposition without delving
too deep into KERI and ACDC initially
because you can kind of lose them.
But effectively and I think it was
but effectively and I think it was
mentioned previously we need to angle
this as a cost reduction or a security
uplift. And then the final kind of
caveat or carrot is you know increase
market share. So the real the real
value or uptick and adoption that we
see is when we can actually not only
deal with the bank-to bankank
compliance and verification but bring
the power of KERI and vLEI into the end
clients wallet where you now have this
endto-end route of trust. So when you
start handling digital products
financial products you have this very
robust compliance root of trust.
It is it has never been more
it has never been more act I have people
reaching out now for vLEI and KERI before
we were constantly pushing so it's never
been more clear that there is a snowball
that is building and building I think
the successes around SEDI are only going
to add to that momentum within
Switzerland alone we are using a KERI
like method for the digital identity
program verifiable history and my
intentions are to start really driving
that conversation to full KERI and
using SEDI as the example of what's
happening on this side of the of the
world.
Did I hear KERI light correctly?
Yes, that's right.
Okay. Could you explain what KERI light
is?
So I mean effectively what you have with
a KERI-l like method is some of the
elements of KERI which are easier to
implement but not the full five W's
effectively they are using what's
known as did verifiable history did VH
which is considered a KERI light method
that's sort of the best there's another
way to explain that
maybe that's a discussion that we could
have offline
because we don't believe that KERI
light exists in general because you will
have to trade off security.
Neither do I.
I got a got another question about this.
You said that Veridian is the
implementation of 5WS
and as you know we have collected
quite a few sponsors to finance
the development of 5WS in the foundation
as well. So I wonder how is that
synchronized
In what regard? Well, we are building
code and you have been building code for
the five W's and I wonder how that
is synchronized.
We contribute to Web of Trust. Fergal
is a maintainer of KERIA.
All right.
We're also a sponsor of the KERI
conference.
Yeah. Yeah. Of course. That's the
conference
and we definitely we believe in
contributing as much as possible to web
of trust KERI Foundation.
So, so there's a way that we could
maybe formal do some more stuff like one
of the things that benefits wallets is
to have multi- vendor suppliers of
witnesses and watcher services. So
standardizing on plugins that various
vendors can contribute to wallets. So
all wallets support multiple vendors of
the infrastructure and then they can
differentiate on other things as well.
that I think that's attractive
to enterprises that want to adopt to see
that a given vendor isn't just supplying
one set of stuff.
Absolutely.
Go ahead, Phil.
go ahead, Phil.
Can I can I add to that? I think
we've heard several times over this
course this week from the state of Utah
signaling that they can't do this with
just one vendor. They need multiple
vendors and the way we synchronize with
each other is the KERI protocol. And so
I think it's awesome that these guys are
building this great platform that's
going to help move KERI forward. That's
what we all need. We need more of it.
Yeah. The question is more that we that
we don't do double work so we create the
same code at several.
You almost have to because you need
multiple vendors running the code so
that people can. So, for example, we
tell our customers, you can't just get
your witnesses from us. We need other
people with witnesses so that they can
they have the security needed from the
protocol. So, I yeah, there's some
double work, but these guys have
contributed a ton to open source. So
I think it's I think it's working well
actually.
Thank you.
Also, I'd like to give a shout out to
Fergal.
I have time, don't I?
Yep.
Excellent.
Fergal has been instrumental in the
success of Veridian and he's someone who
maybe isn't at the front of the room all
of the time, but because of what Fergal
does dayto-day, I'm able to stand here
and talk about the things that are being
built and shipped and delivered. But
Fergal is
Fergal and I went to IIW about four years
ago now and we attended a few
sessions of Samuel Smith, we attended a
bunch of sessions as well. And
internally within the Cardano Foundation,
you might find this funny, Sam. We
refer to Fergal as our Samuel Smith within
the foundation. But without his
dedication and his willingness to
always speak up and ensure that what we
are doing from a dele development
perspective is aligned with open source
and with the ESOS of caring ACDC,
We wouldn't be here today. So, I
just also want to say thank you Fergal
for all of your hard work. Truly,
if I could just pile on to make him even
more embarrassed. Also, his
contributions to the KERI ecosystem in
general as well as the open source
community. He's one of the top guys that
we have doing this stuff, moving us
forward.
Thank you.
Speech, speech, speech.
All right, if no other questions,
I will end it here. Thank you.
Thank you very much.